[{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_lindsey_mowen","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["Our students need to come first, regardless of what situations may arise or issue we face, I will always put our students first. We must continue to do our best for the greater good of our district. "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_lindsey_mowen","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are you plans to address it? ","response":["We have a few top issues our school, and other schools are currently facing. Budget has always been a main concern, CRT is a pressing issue, and we have COVID still on the rise. We have many issues at hand, but need to work together for the greater good of our students. "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_lindsey_mowen","question":"Should teachers and students ages 12 and older be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19? Why or why not?      ","response":["No, vaccinating is a parent/personal choice, I feel that parents need to be making the decisions of vaccines for their children, if they so decide. "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_lindsey_mowen","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to your district's curriculum regarding race and racism? Please explain. ","response":[" None at this time. "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_cameron_schroy","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["Public education has always been a passion of mine.","","In 2014 I graduated from Greencastle-Antrim High School.  I am the only candidate who has been a student in our school system within the past decade.  As a product of all four GA schools, I’ve seen the successes and failures of our district.  As a school board director, I want to build upon what makes us great and fix what holds us back.","","As an educator, I work with students, administrators, faculty and support staff every day.  I understand the day-to-day operations that go into running our schools because education is my professional career.","","My wife and I purchased our home in Greencastle because we want our children to receive the excellent public education that we both received through GASD - as homeowners we have a stake in keeping property taxes reasonable.","","I am the most qualified candidate because my experiences come directly out of the same public schools we are talking about. "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_cameron_schroy","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are you plans to address it? ","response":["Without a doubt the top issue facing our district is the persistent budget deficit.  Just about every year we receive more mandates from Harrisburg and Washington, and every year we never receive enough money to implement them.  Our district spends over $45 million to educate our students with nearly two out of every three dollars coming from property taxes.  ","","Our past school boards have not been spending money left and right either.  Anyone who looks into the budget documents available online can see that our district has upheld the principles of fiscal responsibility to the highest degree.","","I propose that the district abandon the LERTA in 2022 and require the warehouses off of exit 3 pay their fair share in property taxes.  The fiscal imprudence of letting hundreds of thousands of dollars go uncollected is baffling .  The warehouses will certainly continue to  provide jobs to our community as our labor force and prime location on the I-81 corridor will compel them to stay."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_cameron_schroy","question":"Should teachers and students ages 12 and older be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19? Why or why not?      ","response":["Teachers and students shouldn't be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19.  While I personally believe that getting vaccinated is the reasonable thing to do, the school board has no legal standing or authority to require vaccinations.  The potential legal challenges of compulsory vaccination would cost the district money that we do not have to spend and push parents to seek other schooling options (making the district miss out on funding that we cannot afford to lose).  Our district is already shelving out some $700,000 to charter schools; it would be deleterious to see another dime leave our district.","","At this point in the pandemic, getting vaccinated costs you nothing more than 30 minutes of your time.  Compulsion through the school board will not make people get vaccinated, and I do not endorse, promote or support this tactic."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_cameron_schroy","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to your district's curriculum regarding race and racism? Please explain. ","response":["Having read all of the curriculum documents available online, I believe that Greencastle-Antrim presently has a good set of instruction for our students.  Racism and prejudice are always wrong, and I trust our administrators to handle disciplinary issues surrounding them effectively and thoroughly.","","Our teachers are dedicated professionals who work directly with our students.  We should listen to their concerns stemming from student attitudes and make adjustments to curriculum together as a team.  ","","As a fairly recent GAHS graduate, I know for a fact that racism and racist attitudes are not tolerated by our administration or even by the student body.  If there is to be any change in curriculum it will be discussed openly and meant to target specific issues directly involving our schools - not directed at divisive national issues that are not relevant to our district.","","I am opposed to the implementation of critical race theory (CRT) and any adoption of the 1619 project."]},{"candidateCode":"waynesboro_area_board_of_directors_north_end_2_year_rachel_fortney","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I am excited to be running for the office of Waynesboro School Board.  I am hardworking and motivated.  I am loyal to the district and love living here.  I have been heavily involved in the Quincy community for many years and in the Mowrey School PTO for several years.  In my personal life my job consists of many of the facets that I think would make an excellent candidate for a school board member.  I work with the public daily.  I am the liaison between management and staff.  I also head up and create multiple volunteer opportunities which take planning and organization skills.  In the past within the Quincy Community I have served for 10 years on the board of supervisors for the Ox Roast, where I held the position of secretary for 3 years.  In the Mowrey School Community I have been involved with PTO for 4 years where I currently hold the position of treasurer.  I am excited for this opportunity to bring my talents and qualities as a part of the Waynesboro School Board."]},{"candidateCode":"waynesboro_area_board_of_directors_north_end_2_year_rachel_fortney","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are you plans to address it? ","response":["I think the top issue facing our school district is the discord we have between our schools and our communities.  We are all working for the same goal, the students.  I think we need to support each other in our roles.  In our current environment, we are trying to make the best out of a less than ideal situation.  I hope to bring a level headed approach to the problems facing our school community.  I hope to be able to be the bridge between the community and the school to see the facets of everyone’s opinions.  I want to look at both sides of the argument and make a decision that is best for our students."]},{"candidateCode":"waynesboro_area_board_of_directors_north_end_2_year_rachel_fortney","question":"Should teachers and students ages 12 and older be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19? Why or why not?      ","response":["I believe that vaccines are a personal choice. "]},{"candidateCode":"waynesboro_area_board_of_directors_north_end_2_year_rachel_fortney","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to your district's curriculum regarding race and racism? Please explain. ","response":["I believe that we should put curriculum matters into the hands of the teachers.  The teachers in our district are the experts in their fields.  They went to school many years to be teachers and are constantly updating their knowledge of their curriculum.  Many of them have children in our district.  I believe that these teachers and administrators are teaching our students to be good people.  If there is a particular instance or complaint, I believe that could be addressed at the board level.  However, I wholeheartedly believe in the qualified staff that our board has put in place. "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_eileen_dickinson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I have a strong commitment to public education and this is an important way of serving my community. I have excellent communication and collaboration skills and years of experience working with staff, the public and management. I have a high emotional IQ which is a characteristic that has helped me be successful in my career and is essential when working with others who have differing viewpoint. The challenges of today need critical thinking skills, which I believe I excel in."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_eileen_dickinson","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are you plans to address it? ","response":["I have heard from numerous parents, students, teachers and community residents that the pandemic and the mask mandate are the biggest concerns facing our school district. COVID-19 has brought to light many issues, one of which has been balancing the decisions about the health and safety of our students and staff. ","Examining all resources including, research studies, laws and policies, along with input from parents, staff, students, administration and the community, will be utilized in making a fair and informed decision."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_eileen_dickinson","question":"Should teachers and students ages 12 and older be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19? Why or why not?      ","response":["It would be a mistake to make COVID-19 vaccine mandatory without sufficient safety data. Vaccine trials, especially for children, are in their infancy. Time is needed to accumulate the safety and efficacy data before requiring children to be vaccinated.","The studies we do have confirm a low rate of Covid transmission in schools and that the overall risk of death or severe disease from COVID-19 is very low in children.","Everyone has a different medical history and unique medical conditions. Parents need to do their research and consult with their doctors and medical professionals to make the right decision for families."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_eileen_dickinson","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to your district's curriculum regarding race and racism? Please explain. ","response":["The core competencies: critical thinking and social responsibility; creativity and innovation; literacy and communication; physical and emotional health; and general knowledge and academic preparation, will develop our students to be successful in life.","However, I have concerns regarding the curriculum and how it is being taught.","Jay McTighe, the consultant with the development and implementation of these competencies, tends to defend Critical Race Theory (CRT). He states his made- up word, “Attacktics,” describe anti-CRT citizens that are politically driven to fabricate threats of CRT for the purpose of alarming parents and sowing distrust.","I have not seen or heard of any evidence that CRT is being taught in our district. I will remain vigilant and demand transparency in our curriculum."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_charles_c._ford","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["As a School Bus driver and a school volunteer,  I am personally involved with hundreds of our students each and every school day.  My unique perspective can only be achieved by someone who is directly involved with our students.  Any candidates who have direct ties to school children would make ideal School Border members."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_charles_c._ford","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are you plans to address it? ","response":["Keeping our doors open for in person education during the Covid-19 pandemic is our number one concern.  Since there is nothing we can do to eradicate the virus, our primary goal should be to focus on how to keep education in person and not virtual. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_charles_c._ford","question":"Should teachers and students ages 12 and older be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19? Why or why not?      ","response":["I believe in Doctors and Science, I also believe that the only way to get a handle on this virus is through vaccinations.  However, it IS a matter of personal choice."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_charles_c._ford","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to your district's curriculum regarding race and racism? Please explain. ","response":["I believe the curriculum regarding race and racism is fine as it stands in our district. If there are any changes that should be made in the future I believe that they should made district specific.  I do not agree with CRT and believe that kind of indoctrination has NO PLACE within our schools."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_2_year_pat_parson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I’m running for school board because I feel I can contribute good analytical, leadership, and collaborative skills to continue to move the district forward in a positive direction. I do not have a single-issue focus, but rather an interest in the success of all students in our district. Being in the classroom, currently at year 17 as a teacher at Career Tech, I have a daily birds eye view of today’s student and what drives them to succeed and love learning. My coaching experience adds the value of team collaboration, dedication, and desire to do what’s in the best interest of our community. ","Overall, I want the community that my family has lived in for over 10 years continue to thrive for many families to come.",""]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_2_year_pat_parson","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are you plans to address it? ","response":["Balancing the budget and making sure the teachers and staff have the funds to do their jobs to support our students. I will be looking for ways to bring monies into the district and find ways to undo the LERTA tax breaks, that are leaving our budget in the negative. LERTA is a wonderful program if your community/district is struggling!! We are not a struggling community/district if the businesses pay their fair share of the tax base in Greencastle."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_2_year_pat_parson","question":"Should teachers and students ages 12 and older be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19? Why or why not?      ","response":["No! I believe its the choice of the individual. I don't believe there has been enough research on this vaccination to be pushing it. too early and too soon. There has never been a push like this for the Flu vaccine. Just my personal opinion as we talked forever on this subject and never come to an agreement on way or the other."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_2_year_pat_parson","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to your district's curriculum regarding race and racism? Please explain. ","response":["None. I have a student in the district and there has never been any mention about racism in any of the schools in Greencastle. I've been a resident of Franklin county for 50 years and a Greencastle resident since 2012. There is racism everywhere you go, I don't believe there is predominant problem with racism in Greencastle. Our district is a mix of blue and white collar hard working folks "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_pat_parson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I’m running for school board because I feel I can contribute good analytical, leadership, and collaborative skills to continue to move the district forward in a positive direction. I do not have a single-issue focus, but rather an interest in the success of all students in our district. Being in the classroom, currently at year 17 as a teacher at Career Tech, I have a daily birds eye view of today’s student and what drives them to succeed and love learning. My coaching experience adds the value of team collaboration, dedication, and desire to do what’s in the best interest of our community. ","Overall, I want the community that my family has lived in for over 10 years continue to thrive for many families to come.",""]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_pat_parson","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are you plans to address it? ","response":["Balancing the budget and making sure the teachers and staff have the funds to do their jobs to support our students. I will be looking for ways to bring monies into the district and find ways to undo the LERTA tax breaks, that are leaving our budget in the negative. LERTA is a wonderful program if your community/district is struggling!! We are not a struggling community/district if the businesses pay their fair share of the tax base in Greencastle."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_pat_parson","question":"Should teachers and students ages 12 and older be required to be vaccinated against COVID-19? Why or why not?      ","response":["No! I believe its the choice of the individual. I don't believe there has been enough research on this vaccination to be pushing it. too early and too soon. There has never been a push like this for the Flu vaccine. Just my personal opinion as we talked forever on this subject and never come to an agreement on way or the other."]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle-antrim_board_of_directors_4_year_pat_parson","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to your district's curriculum regarding race and racism? Please explain. ","response":["None. I have a student in the district and there has never been any mention about racism in any of the schools in Greencastle. I've been a resident of Franklin county for 50 years and a Greencastle resident since 2012. There is racism everywhere you go, I don't believe there is predominant problem with racism in Greencastle. Our district is a mix of blue and white collar hard working folks "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have lived in the district for 16 years and have two children in two different schools. During that time I have volunteered in the schools and led after school programming. I also hold a teaching certification in special education and have been a professor in a School of Education for 16 years. I have worked with schools and trained teachers both locally and internationally. I have an ideal combination of local community knowledge and academic understanding of issues related to education that range from teaching practices, child development, and educational policy. I have also worked as a Youth Mental Health First Aid trainer and as an educator and counselor at a non-profit serving survivors of sexual assault. Finally, I have been both an athlete and a theatre kid and still see myself as both. I truly believe I have the most well rounded background and experience to serve our community well.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe our biggest issue is our ability to communicate with one another. Although this issue shows up in lots of specific ways (i.e. masks, curriculum decisions, contract negotiations), the core is our inability to work collaboratively with one another. I will commit to approaching all issues with an open mind. I realize that with many issues there will be disagreement. However, I believe it is important to start from the assumption that everyone wants what is best for their children. We may not agree on how to achieve that objective -- but we have a shared objective. I also believe it is important to trust the experts in the room. In our case, that is often the instructional leaders - including teachers. While we as parents and community members may have opinions, they are the people working with our children every day. When they make an informed recommendation, it is our responsibility to take those recommendations seriously and not undermine the good work they are doing."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["We must trust the medical and scientific consensus in order to protect both children and community members from illness. At this time, the BCDH, as well as the CDC and APA, are recommending masking and distancing indoors. In making decisions for both my own children and other people's children, I will trust the experts and follow their recommendations.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The medical consensus is that my mask protects you and your mask protects me. With that in mind, if masks are recommended by health officials, I support that recommendation. Masking is not only about my safety -- if I choose to mask, I am choosing to protect those around me. When one chooses to wear a mask, it says they are concerned with the safety of others and are willing to make that sacrifice for the well being of their fellow humans. In addition to teaching the basic subjects, our schools have long engaged in character building with things like the Doyle 5 and the Kutz Character Traits. Kindness, respect, citizenship, and empathy have always been among the cornerstones of that effort - the Golden Rule comes to mind. At this very moment, masking is recommended by local, state, and federal departments of health. Thus, I support that recommendation. However, if the numbers of cases dropped such that they were no longer needed -- again, I would trust the medical consensus.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The State of Pennsylvania has vaccination guidelines. They currently do not include COVID. I need to do more research about this particular issue. However, at this time I would not insist that those over 12 be mandated to vaccinate. That said, I would expect everyone to follow common sense guidelines to protect those with whom they come in contact.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity and inclusion are important areas to consider. Some forms of diversity, such as race, are very obvious. Others (i.e. socioeconomic status, religion, sexual orientation, ability status) may not be visible. It is important that all teachers and staff engage in self-reflection about their own identities and misconceptions or biases they may hold. Moreover, having open and honest conversations with students is important. So much of our history and literature is interwoven with these themes. Without careful consideration and attention, some students may feel alienated and others may inadvertently reinforce negative stereotypes. While our teachers are engaging in the teaching of content, they are also preparing our children for life beyond their classroom. The best preparation allows all students to not only be able to read the words on a page, but also the world around them.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["All students benefit from a diversity of thought. We might consider looking at the curriculum and asking questions like, \"Whose story is being told?\" and \"Whose story is being left out?\". If instructional leaders look at the curriculum and notice areas where the content can be more inclusive, that is an opportunity for improvement. It is important for all children to see themselves reflected in positive ways throughout the curriculum. I would also encourage all school faculty, staff and administrators to engage in self-reflection. It is natural to gravitate toward what is familiar. We need to push ourselves to look through multiple lenses so we can be sure that every child in our classrooms knows they are loved, valued, and supported. Lastly, we need to listen to one another. When people of color tell us we can do better, that must not be minimized. Instead, let's take that as an opportunity to create a positive learning community for everyone.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_tabitha_dell'angelo","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["According to the non partisan Gallup Polls, about 5.6% of U.S. respondents identify as part of the LGBT community. Given the enrollment at CBSD, that would be more than 1000 of our students. Assuming even distribution, that would be ~45 students per school. All CBSD employees from teachers to nurses to bus drivers, etc. need to know and understand that a child's sexual orientation is part of who they are and should be valued just like every other part of their identity. CBSD employees who feel challenged by this aspect of a person's identity may benefit from specific training or professional development. Part of this education might include statistics to \"normalize\" variations in sexual orientation. Not only are many of our children members of the LGBTQ+ community, so are our immediate and extended families. And, as in other aspects of curriculum review, we should be sure that the historical, scientific, and literary contributions of the LGBTQ+ community are visible.",""]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["For more than 20 years I have been building relationships and interacting with the families and students in CR. My three children all graduated from CR. I have given my time as a director for school musicals at the elementary and middle school level and as a volunteer and member of the 2014 capital planning committee. When I was on the committee, I fought to remind everyone that students are not just dots on a map; these are children and families that need care and attention when we think about redistricting, funding, and education. Now that my children are grown, I have gained an even greater perspective on the impact the school board has on every member of this community, not just those who have students in our schools. The infrastructure of our schools is a high priority for me. The condition of our buildings affects students' ability to learn and also our property values. The quality of our district directly impacts everyone in our community."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Aside from the multitude of issues associated with teaching and learning in a pandemic, the top issues facing our district right now are the mental and physical health of our students as we continue to navigate COVID-19 and the infrastructure of our buildings and properties. The top priority is to have a plan in place that allows students to stay in school. We must do everything we can to keep our schools open and keep our students and staff safe and have a normal, social year. I also plan to work to find funding and solutions so that Richboro Elementary gets the renovation it deserves, matching the high standard that families in Council Rock expect. Without that attention, Richboro Elementary would be the only school in the district without air conditioning, and that is unacceptable."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Federal, state and local health agencies are aligned. Therefore, we need to follow the recommendations of the PA Department of Health, CDC, the American Academy of Pediatrics and the Bucks County Board of Health. I firmly believe this is an ongoing conversation and should be re-addressed as circumstances and local conditions shift. There is one thing everyone can agree on: In-person instruction for all students. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["At this moment I believe masks are a temporary solution, in accordance with the PA Department of Health mandate, until we can lower the transmission rate in the community. We should respond to the high rates of infection across the region and the elevated risk that Delta poses to young people. The PADOH mandate aligns with the CDC , the American Academy of Pediatrics, and the Bucks County Department of Health recommendations. However, no plan should be etched in stone. The board currently has a standing agenda item to discuss the health and safety plan and I support that ongoing strategy to respond to any changes that present in our community in a timely way. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do not think that vaccines should be required. The district should strongly encourage vaccination and provide resources so the entire population of Council Rock can be vaccinated and avoid serious illness and the spread of COVID-19. I believe strongly in the efficacy of vaccines and I trust the science behind them. As of this moment, none of the COVID-19 vaccines have been FDA approved for children ages 12-16."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["One of the pillars of the 2019-2023 CR Strategic Plan focuses on diversity and inclusion. School is where children spend most of their time each week. It should be a place where they feel safe and can thrive in an environment where they are comfortable. School is a place where children learn about their own history and the history of others to prepare them to enter the world after graduation. Therefore, what is learned in the classroom should reflect the world, not just our own community, from different viewpoints. “Embrace and incorporate diversity” and “Build an inclusive and welcoming environment” are values noted in the plan that I fully support. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["On July 30, 2020, the school board unanimously approved an anti-racism resolution which included establishing a district-wide diversity and inclusion team and hiring an outside consultant to conduct a diversity-focused curricular audit. The district has made a good start but even more can be done.  As the resolution states; “We must better educate ourselves and seek to educate the community on the historical and current impact of racism and discrimination on our students, families and communities, as well as understanding our role in perpetuating such inequity.” This topic is a high priority and should be discussed at public meetings for transparency and  community feedback."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_paula_barson","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["There is a moral obligation to educate the whole child: socially, mentally, and emotionally. Not all students are the same and we need to provide the resources necessary so that every student can bring their authentic selves to school every day. All students need to know the support systems are in place and available, and that the district will not tolerate situations that make any student feel discriminated against, unsupported, or unsafe. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["","","I believe that I am the best candidate for Region 3 School Director because I am strictly here for the children and the community.  I do not have any political aspirations above this position nor am I using this position as a stepping stone. ","Children are our most precious gifts as they will be our future. We all need to care that they are getting the best education our schools can offer.","I am honest even when it’s not popular. I am not afraid to tackle the hard decisions and I always do it with the children and the community in mind.","I take my position seriously and appreciate that voters trust me to listen to this community and to vote with their best interests at the forefront.   ","I have been on the School Board almost 4 years and I truly feel that my experiences have only made me more compassionate for this amazing community.",""]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Covid is the top issue facing all school districts.  As School Directors we are entrusted to keep all the children, teachers and support staff safe while offering the best education we can offer to these precious children during this horrible time dealing with this horrific illness.","I plan to advocate for in person learning to continue.  I plan to listen to the folks that know these children best and that is their parents.  I plan to take the science of this raging illness into consideration when making decisions to do what is right for all in our community.","I would be a liar if I told you I know what comes next with Covid but I can promise you I will do all that I can to keep this district moving forward as safe as I know how.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I believe the district has safeguards in place to protect children and staff.  The excellent cleanliness of our facilities is to be applauded.  The care of the staff and teachers in caring about the students warms my heart.  I know in my heart that these folks do their job so well because they know they are one of the first lines of defense in keeping Covid cases to a minimum.  I would love to see the School Directors find a way to communicate in a better way with the parents and community members.  We may not always agree with what a parent would like to say but to make them feel like we have taken all the choices for their children’s health concerning Covid only causes more of divide.  "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["That decision has been taken out of the hands of the School Directors as of now.  It is mandated that all staff, students and all those entering school facilities wear a mask while indoors.","Our board had a vote on this subject several weeks ago and I voted to make masks optional.","Several of us voted for optional but we were outvoted.  ","I am a firm believer that parents know their children best and who am I to tell a parent what health decisions to make for THEIR child.  We are in to this nightmare Covid over 18 months and I am not certain anyone has the magic cure for surely they would have shared it by now. I respect what each parent feels is best for their child.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do not think I have the right to make that choice for others.  ","I am vaccinated. My family is vaccinated but not in my wildest dreams would I ever want to tell someone else what is right for them or their children."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["It is my belief that all children deserve the same quality education and the same opportunities.  Every single child is precious in my eyes."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Our community is an amazing melting pot of different ethnic backgrounds that has always worked respectfully together.  I love the diversity and I love that our children do not see color when looking at their friends.  They are just friends.  ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mary_alice_brancato","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our district is supportive of the LGBTQ students.  Who one chooses to love is their own business and love regardless of who it is between is a wonderful gift in my eyes.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I believe I am the best candidate for this office for a couple of reasons.   First, I am informed about what is going on in our district, our schools, and our community, such as by engaging community members, & attending school board meetings & committee meetings. Second, I follow what the community is sharing about key issues that affect them, try to collect all the key facts, & work to formulate a solution that takes into account what is best for our kids, our schools, & our community.  Third, I have invested my time, my energy, & commitment to participating & volunteering so as to make our schools as great as they can be &, most importantly, to give our kids a well-rounded & challenging education that allows them to succeed in school & beyond.  Fourth, leaning on my life & work experiences, not to mention my upbringing & the strong support of my family, I bring a positive & unique approach, which relies on knowledge, understanding, consensus-building, & positive collaboration. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing our school district is our curriculum.  Unfortunately, our curriculum has not been updated in over 2 decades and finally after 3 years of being worked on diligently by our teachers and staff, the school board decided to halt its approval.  Our students need a well-rounded, historically accurate and challenging education if we want them to be able to compete with other students when they graduate and succeed in college and beyond.  One of the things I would do is pass the student-centered curriculum that the professionals have worked on for over 3 years and follow their recommendations for regularly improving our curriculum to stay ahead of neighboring school districts.  The new proposed curriculum would be a living document which would continue to be updated and is exactly what our students need. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Things are very fluid when it comes to COVID, however, I believe our School District should be looking very closely at what the medical organizations and healthcare professionals, such as CDC, Pennsylvania Department of Health, American Academy of Pediatrics, and Bucks County Department of Health, are saying and follow their science-based recommendations and guidelines, particularly when their recommendations align. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["As mentioned above, I believe the District should be looking at what the medical organizations and healthcare professionals are recommending.  The School Board Directors are not medical professionals and should be doing their best to keep all our students safe, which in my opinion is by following the recommended guidelines of such organizations, particularly when their recommendations align.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do not believe teachers and/or students should be required to be vaccinated, however, if they choose not to be vaccinated then they must wear a mask while inside at school and in the case of teachers, they would need to be tested regularly. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The District should continue what it started over a year ago with implementing school Diversity Committees and continuing to implement and grow the District DEI Initiative.  Our world is a diverse place, and we have to move forward in allowing our students to learn about cultures and people aside from their own.  Our students deserve a well-rounded, factual and challenging education which has to include the topics of diversity and inclusion. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["One change that has to be done is to allow Diversity, Equity and Inclusion in our schools again.  With the current school board’s decision to halt anything that has to do with DEI, I believe is only highlighting how much we need it in our schools.  It appears that instead of embracing our differences and acknowledging them they are instead trying to act like there are no differences and surely do not want them to be acknowledged or celebrated in our schools.  In order for our students to be taught an accurate history and learn from it, race and racism has to be a part of the curriculum because race and racism is a part of our history.  We live in a great country however we should not ignore the mistakes that have been made and most importantly learn from them and have intellectual discussions about them.  We have a great community and I believe including Diversity, Equity and Inclusion would only make it better.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_carolyn_sciarrino","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I believe all students deserve to be supported and acknowledged, including LGBTQ+ students.  Our goal as a school district should be to make sure all of our students are safe and welcomed, while getting the best education we can provide so that they can succeed in the future.   Our LGBTQ+ students need to have resources and need to know that they can talk with their teachers if they need to, which means our teachers need additional training to engage students in those conversations.  Our District needs to provide those elements to both our students and teachers."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I want to make sure our students have the best opportunity to succeed. I want to ensure they have the support and resources necessary to see and take hold of these opportunities. I want our teachers to be able to excel at teaching and have the tools to understand the complex sensitivities of our current environment. I want to bring our community, schools and board to a place of transparency where everyone understands each other. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Student Development. To address the emotional, mental and behavioral aspects, I will propose we work with a group that can provide on-site resources for therapy and group. This will help teachers and other support staff do the jobs they extensively train for. This will help students to process through the complexities of everything they are going through, and not have to worry about asking for it. This will allow students to become their best selves. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["We need to be flexible with our plan. I would place our masking with our transmission rate along with trends on quarantine and positive covid rates. Once we are in steady trend of low, we can look to relax. If our rates spike, we revert. This doesn't need to be complicated, but it needs to place proper precautions and measurables that are understandable for all. This way decisions are logical for every level and give the best chance to keep all in schools safe and in school."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. We need to be flexible with our plan. I would place our masking with our transmission rate along with trends on quarantine and positive covid rates. Once we are in steady trend of low, we can look to relax. If our rates spike, we revert. This doesn't need to be complicated, but it needs to place proper precautions and measurables that are understandable for all. This way decisions are logical for every level and give the best chance to keep all in schools safe and in school."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["No. The current climate would over-politicize it and create scenarios that could create divides that should be avoided. We need to bring every with us, not demand that they join. We need to make sure we make every attempt to break through the misinformation amd hesitancy. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Transparent ones. This is a hot button subject that has already be demonized in my district. Showing the need, the want and the how will help increase our students development. Working a clear and transparent process will help parents feel included and give ample opportunities for their input. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Diverse viewpoints that show impacts of each situation. This will provide a much greater education and allow the students to think more critically on how to approach and view future scenarios. We cannot do better if we do not understand what was wrong and how it impacts others."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_david_a._o'donnell","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["The proposal I submitted in an earlier question is the major move. It is a great starting point in providing direct resources to the students. We are constantly learning more about all the various aspects of the mindset, challenges and discrimination that those in the community deal with. We are here to teach all students. That means we need to understand how to reach them all."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am running for school board to assure the success of every child in our community. I bring an important perspective as a pediatrician, mom to four children, and mental health advocate. I am a graduate of the public school system and believe it provides students with the best education and experience. I have centered my life on the wellness and growth of children. I look at education through a holistic lens. I believe that along with evidence-based practices for educational excellence, we also need a nuanced approach to each learning experience. Each child is unique and must have adequate supports for school and life success.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Mental health issues continue to rise in our children. The most common of these are attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder, behavior problems, anxiety and depression. Half of youth with these conditions never receive any kind of treatment in a given year. Schools are uniquely-positioned to provide students with needed and appropriate mental health services where they spend the majority of their productive time.  We need strong resources in school and connections to more intensive ones in the community. Children learn best when their mental health needs are met.  They stay in school and on track. Early identification and effective supports for children and families can make a huge difference in their lives. I have provided mental health care for many patients in the scope of my pediatric practice and continue that work on the county’s behavioral health/developmental programs advisory board. I am able to bring this knowledge and experience to the school setting.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The pandemic has taken a significant toll on children’s education, physical, mental and emotional health.  We must prioritize in-person learning for children alongside their friends and teachers. In order to avoid disruption and support children’s learning and health, schools must follow science and data-driven practices to protect students, staff, and families. The American Academy of Pediatrics and the CDC have clear guidelines for school safety at this time.  These are supported by state and local leaders in education and health. I continue to stay abreast of guidance for children and schools through the American Academy of Pediatrics and its School Health committee. A layered mitigation strategy is key.  This includes vaccination, masking, social distancing, ventilation, disinfection, quarantining, and contact tracing. Communication with families and relationships with local health agencies and medical facilities are key to a successful and safe school year. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["At this time, the data and guidance is clear that schools should have universal masking for students and staff. The CDC, AAP, PA Department of Health, Pa Department of Education and the Bucks County Health Department are all in agreement with these recommendations.  A large portion of the student population is not yet eligible for vaccines and masking is proven to reduce transmission of the virus and to protect those who are not vaccinated. Children do best when they are in school and when there is minimal disruption.  Masks along with important mitigation strategies allow for a stable and safe school environment. They also allow every child, including those who are immunocompromised and have special needs or disabilities, to have access to critical instruction, nutrition, physical/occupational/speech therapies, mental health services, and physical activity along with other benefits. It is important to have strategies to continuously monitor and revise plans as guidance evolves."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["At this time there is no mandate for Covid-19 vaccinations.  Vaccination is the most important strategy to keep our schools and community safe.  They are effective and safe. Vaccinating everyone in the school environment should be a priority. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Every child needs to be celebrated and feel safe in school.  Schools are richer when they respect the identity and diversity of each family and child.  In fact, children who come from schools with strong programs in diversity, equity and inclusion produce better learners, employees, and community members. Each member of our school community can make a difference in a child’s life in this manner. I have been on the district’s diversity committee as a parent and will continue to support its initiatives.  Steps that include curriculum, hiring practices, community connections and professional and student development are key. Central Bucks can be a leader in this area. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["We should be incorporating a broad range of texts and literature for students to learn from.  We have educators who have vast experience and expertise in these areas and can help lead us in these endeavors.  A comprehensive program is important that includes a school culture with curriculum that cultivates community. Incidents can not be ignored but turned into teaching moments. Addressing these issues is important to validate the experiences of students and staff and allow us to grow together. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_mariam_mahmud","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["LGBTQ+ students and staff now more than ever need a safe and supported learning environment where they  thrive.  I will support all initiatives to assure that no child or community member is ever afraid and that all children feel celebrated.  Every student needs to feel their presence is important and needed, regardless of their gender identity and sexual orientation. Initiatives should include supporting student groups, topics in curriculum, professional development, and bullying prevention.  It is important to have schools that  build trust, connection and strategies for intervention and positive action when needed. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a teacher and a parent, which gives me insight into education and experience advocating for children in both capacities. I have experience writing curriculum and serving on educational leadership committees. I have worked with students in grades 7-12 in both the classroom and in extracurricular activities. I am dedicated and committed to bettering public education services. Communication with the community is also important to me, and would be a top priority for me if I serve in the role of school director."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Pennridge’s state and national rankings continue to slide. They have fallen significantly in each of the last three years, and they are significantly lower than all surrounding districts. Partisan politics has become too much of a focus, and our educational services have suffered as a result. I plan to address this problem by assessing the effectiveness of the curriculum and the educational culture in Pennridge. We must develop clear and consistent methods for monitoring success and create action plans for addressing shortcomings."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The school district’s top responsibility is the safety of its students. It must follow the guidance of health experts."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. This is the unanimous recommendation of the local, state, and federal medical community. I am not a medical expert, so in the case of student and community health, I defer to the experts."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["If other precautions like mask wearing are put in place, than no."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Students, parents, staff, and community members should be working together to identify areas of need in the community. We should be facilitating conversations about diversity, equity, and inclusion and finding ways to celebrate each other’s differences. Making sure all students feel safe and included should be a district priority."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe curriculum writing should be led by the experts, our teachers."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_dawn_curran","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Staff should receive training to support these students’ needs. There should be groups available for these students to meet with peers and trained staff. The district should provide supportive resources for students and families. The environment at school should be a welcoming one that recognizes and supports LGBTQ+ students."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Bensalem is the most racially, ethnically, and religiously diverse township in Bucks County. Our school board should reflect the citizens it serves. As the only Black Woman running and and as a graduate of Bensalem High School, I hope to be a much needed voice for Bensalem's School Board. With three children that are currently in Bensalem public schools, I have a vested interest in making sure my children and their peers have the best experience possible."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Being decisive and following through with action plans allows families, teachers, and staff the structure needed to make the best decisions for their families. Transparency and accessible communication are the clearest path to trust. We must do a better job of making important information accessible to all families. Translating information into multiple languages, hiring diverse teachers and staff, and asking the public what they need from the district are ways in which we can build a cohesive community."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Bensalem School District should be following the recommendations of experts within the infectious disease field. The health and safety of our students, teachers, and staff are not a political issue. It is a fact based science issue. The health department and CDC have guidelines that we should be referring to."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a community, we must continue to be flexible and considerate of one another. When guidelines from experts change, we must be willing to change according to what data suggests. The Delta Variant makes our children vulnerable. Masks should be worn indoors until numbers steadily decline."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I will follow the mandates given from our government. There are always exceptions given for specific purposes."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["As a member of Bensalem School District's Diversity and Inclusion committee, I am excited to see what improvements we can make to  include all of our students. We recently posted a DEI Officer position for the school district. This is the first step in the correct direction. I hope to see this position filled soon so that we can begin to collaborate and support our students."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe our students should see themselves reflected in the books they read, songs they sing, composers they play, and scientists they study. American history is rich and diverse. American history has many voices. Our district is full of culture. We must begin to embrace it completely and see each child for who they are without reservation."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_alana_hardison","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["As with all diversity, our LGBTQA+ students must be supported with an equity lens. Seeking to understand the needs of the students in this demographic must come from those that identify within this group. Making sure self identified pronouns are used is a first step."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["​","As a single mother of three who moved to Bensalem for my children's education, I understand the challenges and obstacles parents face with in the public school system. I have a unique perspective as a mother of two autistic children and a gifted child. I know first hand the hurdles a parent has to overcome for education equality for students who do not fall within the standard. As an active PTA member, band parent, fundraiser for school activities and more, I was an involved parent obtaining insight into the education system's negatives and positives. As a para-educator for the Bensalem School District I was able to view the education system from a new level, understanding the challenges teachers and staff face within and outside the classroom. My passion to improve the education system which has been cultivated over years of interaction at various levels providing me with insight regarding our school district's needs and achievements. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The division in the Bensalem School District is disheartening to me. As someone who has been a parent and employee in this district I want to represent,  bridge the gap, and bring us back together. We all need to focus on being here for the children of Bensalem, it is crucial not only for the education of our children, but their well-being.  We are truly better together than divided. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":[" We must stop making this a political issue and start addressing it as the public health issue it is. We must follow the guidelines put forth by pediatricians, the CDC, the Pennsylvania and Bucks County Boards of Health. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Students and teachers should be required to follow all guidelines put forth by the Pennsylvania and Bucks County Departments of Health , and CDC to ensure the health and safety of all members of our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":[" No one should get any vaccine without consulting with their doctor first. As long as vaccines are deemed safe, effective and allow our schools and economy to remain open, our community will be able to prosper educationally and socially."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Bensalem has formed the Diversity and Inclusion Committee,  which I hope to serve on if elected. I believe the Bensalem Township School District is on a positive path for the future. Of course it will take continued efforts of not only the committee, but our community to allow all voices to be heard and included."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["A school curriculum should include our diverse history all year long. Students must be educated on all history, good and bad. Our nation was built on fundamental ideas and ideologies with the purpose of freedom for all, however mistakes and injustices occurred. We must provide our students with the knowledge in order to prevent our negative history being repeated."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_jaime_devery","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["We need to stop using the word tolerance when we are talking about human beings. To say we need to be tolerant implies someone needing to be tolerated. We need to be kind and accept people for who they are as people not just “tolerate” them.  We need to make sure they have a safe place to be heard if they are being targeted with hateful rhetoric and abuse. We must have strict consequences for anyone who perpetrates any of these acts on their fellow students. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been in education for over 10 years, as a public school teacher and as a charter school teacher. I understand education, learning, and curriculum and have a Masters in Education. I've dedicated my adult life to teaching children from all walks of life and from various ethnic, religious, and cultural backgrounds. As a teacher, I spend my days learning about the unique needs of students. As an educational leader, I work with other educators by mentoring, guiding, and training them. Prior to teaching, I worked in healthcare copywriting, communications, and marketing. Therefore, I am comfortable managing several projects concurrently, working under pressure under tight deadlines, and making difficult decisions in times of chaos. Finally, being a Russian Jewish immigrant gives me a unique perspective and experience. I know what it is like to be the kid outside looking in. I care deeply about education and all of our children's futures. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our current School Board is overreaching. A School Board should govern and listen to experts they hire, not meddle in everyday decisions. Not listening to experts and making decisions based solely on personal beliefs are becoming increasingly problematic in our district. I plan to listen to the experts we hire, like experts in education, public health, and social and emotional wellbeing. I also plan on working closely with my colleagues to make the decisions that meet the needs of all of our students. Also, I have heard from way too many parents that our schools don't do a good enough job educating and accommodating kids with special needs. I plan on listening to the directors of Special Education and parents to identify areas of needs and create a better program for our kids. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Most importantly, our School Board should listen to healthcare experts who spend their lives studying public health, infectious diseases, and mitigation. Our schools should offer layered COVID mitigation, including masks, contact tracing, and social distancing protocols. We must do everything possible to keep our schools open and our kids in school. Kids learn best in person, and last year was very difficult for many of us, so safety in schools should be out top priority. Safe schools stay open. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Masks should be required for students in elementary school since they do not yet have the ability to receive the vaccine. However, when the community spread is low, vaccinated students, teachers, and staff should have the option whether or not to wear a mask. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I don't believe schools should require a COVID vaccine, but they should encourage vaccinations for those eligible, offer vaccine clinics, and require other mitigation, such as masks. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Our district should be culturally responsive. Our population is becoming more diverse and our children are going out into the world outside of Bucks County. I know many students aren't prepared for the diverse world after they graduate from Central Bucks. Our district does a great job at teaching kids in the middle and the top of their class, but many students fall off the mainstream grid. All students should be included in their educational experience, including students of color, LGBTQ+ students, and students with disabilities. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Our schools could adopt or borrow from a culturally responsive curriculum which focuses on students' prior experiences and cultural knowledge. Such curricula allow all students to better engage with the material presented and taught, as it is more relevant to students and to their experiences. Furthermore, a responsive curriculum is proven to raise test scores and improve students' critical thinking and analytical skills. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_diana_leygerman","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Every child deserves access to equal education without discrimination. Our district should take more steps to make our LGBTQ+ students feel welcomed and included. I would suggest more education for our students and families, including LGBTQ+ literature in English classes and learning about LGBTQ+ history in Social Studies classes. After listening to our LGBTQ+ students speak about the harassment and bullying they have endured by their peers, I know we need to do better as a district and as a community to support and protect our most vulnerable kids. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience and education make me qualified, but my passion and tenacity help me to excel. I am an independent thinker, not influenced by politicians who may view the District as a companion piece in a larger agenda. My own two children attend our schools, giving me a personal stake in what happens, but I also advocate for issues affecting all of our children. Candidates seeking this office as a stepping-stone to higher office, running for a single issue, or just because they like their community, have neither the ability nor inclination to do the job our children deserve. I never take the passive approach adopted by some. I roll up my sleeves, and have the confidence to take the bold steps our children need."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Bensalem's most pressing issue is academic excellence and equity. I have pressed for us to meet every child where they are, devoting equitable resources and staff to struggling learners, but also challenging more advanced learners with quality curriculum and classroom differentiation. We must remedy the difference in experiences and opportunities between schools, and even from class to class. Our schools have many strengths, but our rankings have lowered and graduation rates need attention. A community relies on our schools to prepare career and college ready young people. Communication is vital, but is frequently lagging in the District - an issue which I have worked tirelessly to address. I see the rejuvenation of middle schools infrastructure, examining elementary enrollment assignments, and bringing back supplemental publicly funded preK as immediate needs, but the majority has not pressed for them. I am seeking re-election as I feel my ability to contribute is not yet finished.",""]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Our schools can play a dual role of both providing a safe environment and information.  Even though we have all been living with COVID for many months, I find that we still have students and families who are not fully informed as to strategies to combat spread and the importance and availability of vaccines.  The Governor recently made available monies to house vaccination sites in schools for anyone who would like to be vaccinated.  I hope that we will be able to access such funds soon.  In terms of a safe environment, frankly, the space available in many schools makes it very difficult to physically distance when all students are in attendance.  We also do not have the ability to contact trace fully without the assistance of the County Health Department.  The only precautions we can offer are enhanced cleaning, encouraging families to report any COVID symptoms or positive cases in the household, not coming to school sick, and the wearing of masks."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["At this time, yes they should be required.  A School Board is not comprised of medical experts.  I certainly am not one.  Currently we have the CDC, the Pennsylvania Department of Health and our local Bucks County Department of Health all telling us that the Delta variant is surging and we should require universal masking at this time.  Neither I nor my colleagues have the personal expertise to contradict them.  There are many decisions which a School Board must make for the children of our community.  Although it is very difficult, this is one of those decisions.  However, as of September this decision was made by the PA Secretary of Health.  It is the District's responsibility to comply with the directives of our Commonwealth officials."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Absent a religious objection or specific medical condition, our whole society is already required to have a slew of vaccinations in order to enter school.  It is likely only a matter of time before COVID is added to the list of mandatory vaccinations.  However, I understand that particular requirement for the students is one which by law would have to be imposed at the state, not at the local level.  With regard to teachers, other public and private entities are already requiring vaccination of their employees.  I am not aware that we keep records of the number of employees already vaccinated, but anecdotally I believe the majority of staff are. Now that there is full FDA approval of the Pfizer vaccine, I am hopeful that more people will have confidence and voluntarily vaccinate.  If they do not, I think it would be wise to begin examining vaccination as a condition of employment as many others have."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Our District is already taking steps to address diversity and inclusion in the District. In 2020 the School Board, unanimously passed an anti-racist resolution.  We  then created a Diversity, Equity and Inclusion Committee of the Board.  I am one of four members of this bi-partisan Committee.  We have since hired a consultant to examine our systems and practices to determine where we are and where we need to be.  We recently received the evaluation results and suggestions for improvement.  At the heart of this work is ensuring that every student has the academic opportunities and support to thrive and learn. The report showed we have children falling behind others - from minority, bi-racial and/or low-income homes, who have a disability, or who are learning English.  Our partners have recommended steps to close this gap. We have also approved a new position for a DEI officer to help improve our inclusivity in the District.  The interview process should begin soon."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["According to the consultants who reviewed our curriculum, it is acceptable with regard to issues of race, racism and inclusion.  We did not receive a recommendation to scrap our curriculum.  Where we can improve is by paying attention to whether curriculum modules which address different racial and cultural experiences are being uniformly accessed in each classroom.  Our students from all cultures and backgrounds need to feel seen and heard within their studies.  This will help them excel academically and feel more confident.  The first thing that Black students learn about themselves should not be the history of slavery, with a touch of MLK and Rosa Parks.  The Hispanic children should see themselves somewhere, other than as a footnote to Columbus.  Black, Hispanic, Asian, disabled individuals, and many others all have had experiences in our history and made contributions to our society.  It benefits us all to study a fuller history and and have a diverse literary experience.    "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_stephanie_gonzalez_ferrandez","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our job is to educate.  To do that, all students must be comfortable in the school setting.  Children who feel bullied, singled out or not accepted do not learn well.  This applies to LGBTQ+ students as well as any other students.  As a parent of a middle school and a high school student in our District, I have noticed from speaking with my own children that students seem to more freely express their orientation, as compared to even just 10 years ago. That said, we still have students who feel unaccepted and without a safe space, and we still have students who tease and bully others.  Our District does attempt to set the tone of being kind to others, including those different from you.  We should continue to emphasize an environment of kindness and let students know that they can reach out to counselors and teachers and expect support if they are experiencing ridicule, exclusion or fear."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am passionate about making our CBSD Schools the best they can be for students and families. I am informed, engaged, and involved as a parent volunteer in many building-wide, region-wide and district-wide initiatives: Rep. on Superintendent/Parent Advisory Council (Tamanend), Home & School President (Barclay), Race For Education Chair/Team Member (Barclay), Rep. on Elementary Progress Report Redesign Effort (district-wide).","","I was instrumental in raising close to $200K for HSA activities, Gaga Pit, recess equipment, field trips, and other resources (Barclay).","","I have a proven track record of working effectively & respectfully with others to build consensus and get things done on both professional and community projects by listening with an open mind and leveraging subject matter experts to achieve results. The Project Management, leadership, problem solving and other skills acquired over the course of my career are directly applicable to serving as an effective School Board Director."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["In addition to the obvious challenges associated with COVID and keeping schools open, our district and community face a level of divisiveness that has sadly become toxic. This has harmed the once sterling reputation of CBSD. We need all stakeholders to listen effectively and interact with respect and civility. As leaders, we must work together to find common ground in order to move forward and rebuild the trust and reputation of CBSD. Our students, families and community deserve our best effort!","","My professional and community service experience has provided me with significant experience and success in problem solving and bringing people together to achieve common goals. CBSD has many other important issues to address, we must work together to move forward! "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["It has been a very difficult 18 months for our students, staff and community. As we start the school year, our children need schools to remain open providing 5 day, in-person instruction for their academic, mental and social well-being. I believe that all members of our community agree on this point, and we need to work together to make it happen. ","","One of the primary responsibilities of our district is to ensure the safety of our children, and in turn our community. I am not a medical professional! Therefore, I feel we must rely on guidance of trusted medical resources (CDC, AAP, PA DOH, BCHD) to assess the current landscape and make recommendations that enable us to KEEP STUDENTS AND STAFF SAFE TO KEEP SCHOOLS OPEN! ","","Addressing safety and mitigation associated with COVID must be considered a public health rather than a political issue by our schools."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["All Pennsylvania school districts have been charged with developing a Health and Safety Plan (HASP) by the state that reflects expert guidance from CDC, PA DOH and BCHD. Although the ultimate responsibility for developing and implementing the HASP lies with our School Administration and School Board, if expert guidance indicates that students and teachers are required to wear masks, I believe that our HASP should reflect that guidance for those who are able. No one enjoys wearing a mask! But we need to work together to be proactive in protecting our community members.","","I also believe that our plan should: be informed by the recommendations of medical experts, contain objective metrics for adopting or relaxing mitigation measures, and be fluid to adjust the need for mask wearing or adoption of other mitigation as community transmission and conditions change."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["At this time, I do not believe that teachers and/or students should be required to be vaccinated against COVID. I understand that not all people are able to be vaccinated for various reasons. Medical treatment decisions that we make for ourselves and our children have risks, benefits and consequences. While I personally encourage individuals to follow the prevailing advice of trusted medical professionals to protect themselves and our community, I accept that people have varied levels of risk tolerance and may be willing to assume the risk and consequences associated with not being vaccinated."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Our schools should provide a safe, accepting, inclusive and nurturing environment for all students.  Children are given the best opportunity to thrive both academically and socially when they feel respected and valued.  Our country was founded to celebrate our diversity of religion, thoughts, customs, etc.  As adults and as a school community, we must model respect, acceptance, and civility to our children to equip them to be successful community members and future leaders regardless of the path they choose after high school.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["In CBSD, we are fortunate to employ highly qualified and dedicated administrators and teachers who have worked for many years to develop their expertise in formulating curriculum and delivering instruction. Although I personally believe in teaching truthful history and utilizing exemplary literature to inform future decision making by students. No student or community member should feel “less” because of their race. As I understand it, the role of a School Director is to provide governance, strategic direction and to review & approve curriculum that is developed & presented by the Administration. I would likely respect the expertise of the education professionals in developing curriculum."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_jenine_zdanowicz","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["LGBTQ+ students, like all students, should be accepted & respected for who they are. They should receive the guidance and support needed to help them to succeed academically and emotionally in CBSD and beyond.  Some LQBTQ+ students may experience the added challenge of lack of acceptance in their home situation. Fortunately, our high schools have a student organization called “Gay/Straight Alliance”.  According to the CBSD website, “The goal of the GSA is to make their school community safe and welcoming regardless of sexual orientation of gender identity.”"]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am passionate about our community and equipping our students for the future. As a father of three daughters, I understand the importance of a comprehensive, well-rounded, and inclusive education for the future success of our children. ","I hold a Bachelors degree from Temple University and an MBA in Finance. My current position is as an HR Executive at a global medical device company. In my experiences, I have acquired a unique skill set that is essential to success in the school board position.","","IN ORDER TO BE SUCCESSFUL, I WILL...","• Listen Generously - Look at things through multiple lenses.","• Explain the reasons why decisions are made.","• Not be afraid to stand up when something is wrong.","• Use conflict resolution skills to produce a healthy outcome.","I have been successful in my professional career by not only being technically proficient, but also recognizing that there are many ways of looking at something and just as many ways of doing those things.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["In addition to the challenges associated with keeping our schools open and kids safe during COVID, our community is facing a level of divisiveness that has become intolerable. This divide is harming the reputation of our district and highlighting many of our community attributes that we would not tolerate from our children but we are displaying as adults. We need all stakeholders to listen generously and interact with respect and selflessness . As leaders, we must work together to find common ground in order to move forward and rebuild the trust and reputation of CBSD. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The last several months have been extremely difficult for everyone.  We are suffering covid fatigue and will look for all ways to return to life before covid.  As we start the school year, our children need schools to remain open providing 5 day, in-person instruction for their academic, mental and social well-being. One of the primary responsibilities of our district is to ensure the safety of our children, and in turn our community. Like many, I turn to medical expert consensus to provide guidance on the best way to move forward based on the current landscape.  This guidance and approach must be continually reviewed as new information becomes available.  The school district needs to keep the politics out of public health decisions---that needs to be left to the experts in their respective areas.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["","Since I am not a medical expert, I must rely on the advice of medical expert consensus to determine masking requirements.  If it is the consensus of our medical experts to wear masks, we should do so.  We should also ensure that we are staying current and evaluating the situation on regular basis to ensure our decisions align with the current community landscape.  There are several in our community that have specialized circumstances and that should be a key point in any decision.  During this time, being selflessness and flexible is key.  The school district needs to keep politics out of the masking decisions, it should be left to experts not google experts.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Although I believe in the science and effectiveness of vaccinations, I personally believe COVID-19 vaccination should be encouraged but is ultimately a choice.  However, I also believe that if someone chooses not to be vaccinated, they should be required to take additional precautions to ensure the safety of others (masking and regular testing).  While we should not push our personal decisions on others, that does not mean that we should allow an adverse impact to others based on personal decisions.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["One of our top priorities as adults and humans should be that we value each individual for who these are.  Our schools should provide a safe, accepting and  inclusive environment for all students. Diversity of thought, religion, gender, disability and ethnicity should be taught and welcomed as this prepares CBSD students to be successful community members and global citizens.  This is what the world outside of CBSD requires as our students move to the next chapter of their lives.   Students thrive both academically and socially when they feel respected and valued."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["In CBSD, we are extremely lucky to have a group of experts that evaluate curriculum and make recommendations for changes.  They have at their disposal, best practices and research that I do not have.  When recommendations are made, they should be looked at through various lenses and if in the best interest of our students and community, these should be adopted.  Race and Racism are a difficult topics to deeply understand and address, which makes them a hot button for misunderstanding and misinterpretation. I personally believe in teaching truthful history and utilizing exemplary literature to inform future decision making by students. No student or community member should feel devalued because of their race. Making every student feel valued should be something the community can agree on.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_robert_dugger","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All students in CB should be accepted, respected and valued with no exceptions.  Statistically speaking, LGBTQ+ students can be more vulnerable and should have available and receive additional guidance and support needed to help them to succeed academically and emotionally in CBSD and beyond.  Fortunately, our high schools have a student organizations with the goal of making the school community safe and welcoming regardless of sexual orientation of gender identity.”  Just as CB would provide additional support to those in vulnerable situations, the LGBTQ+ students would be no exception."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My husband and I have been local community members for 17 years. We have a son in 2nd grade in CRSD. I am a first generation immigrant and my early childhood years were spent in and out of foster homes. I did not have the opportunity to go to school until I came to this country at the age of 7. I grew up in a small, rural town, in a blue-collar family. I know from first hand experience the importance of a quality education. When we relocated to this area, I had recently graduated with my Master's in Elementary Education and we chose to live in the CRSD. I would bring a unique perspective to the school board because of my personal background and experience as a former teacher, a current parent of a CRSD student and an active PTO board member. In my years as an educator, I was a lead teacher, inclusive teacher, mentor and a Dean of Students. I have a deep passion for education and am keenly aware of the difficulties, challenges and hard work it takes to have high achieving schools. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue our school district is currently facing is the physical and mental health of our students through COVID-19. My goal is to keep students and teachers in the classroom for the duration of the entire school year in the safest manner possible. My plans align with the recommendations by the CDC, AAP, PA Department of Health, Bucks County Department of Health and the most recent declaration by the PA Department of Health. We must do everything we can to keep our children and staff safely in school. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The most vulnerable student population are those under the age of 12 years who are not able to receive a vaccine at this current time and those with underlying health concerns. The school district should follow the guidelines recommended by all the major health organizations we seek guidance from when we are facing a health crisis. The district should continue to follow the recommendations until we are no longer at a high or substantial transmission rate. The school board should regularly discuss the Health and Safety Plan to make adjustments as local conditions change. We all know we need our children in school, where they belong, and want them to be safe. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["At this current time when our area is still in high transmission and approximately half our student population is unable to receive a vaccine we should follow the mandate from the PA Department of Health, and the guidelines from the CDC, the American Academy of Pediatrics and the Bucks County Department of Health. We want to keep our children and teachers in school in the safest manner possible. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The school district should strongly encourage vaccination and provide resources for the local community for those who wish to be vaccinated. I believe in the efficacy of vaccines and trust in the science behind them."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The school environment is where life-long friendships are made and a love of learning begins. Schools need to be a safe and welcoming place for all students to achieve academic success. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The CRSD School Board had unanimously supported the approval of a district-wide diversity and inclusion team back in July 2020. The need to address race and racism should be a continual work in progress; we are life-long learners. It is important to educate students about the impact of racism and discrimination, and the curriculum needs to support this. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_nicole_khan","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All students need to have the resources, support, and accessibility to an education. Students need to have systems in place and made readily available to them. Every child needs to feel safe, supported and welcome in a school setting."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have a PhD in Cell and Molecular Biology, so science and critical thinking are near and dear to my heart. Combining my K-12, college, and graduate education I have spent a grand total of 23 years in school. I also have a daughter who attends school in the district so I can see issues from both a student and parent perspective. Strong schools make for strong, well-educated communities and I am committed to making this happen."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["As I have been door knocking in our community, the top issue on everyone’s mind is COVID. As a scientist specializing in the study of viruses, I am uniquely qualified to discuss and disseminate public health information. As we have seen in the news, school board meetings are extremely contentious, more so now than ever. It has gotten very “us vs. them.” However, we are all members of the same community and should have the same goal: a quality education for students in a safe environment. I will always be approachable for discussion if people want to talk and hope that through engagement with the community we can temper some of the anger that we are seeing during school board meetings."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["We are seeing alarming numbers of children infected by the delta variant in the southern United States and we should not wait until the virus starts tearing through Pennsylvania to act. The four best ways to fight COVID are vaccination, distancing, ventilation, and masking. In a perfect world schools would be doing all four, as layered mitigation works best.  However, children under 12 cannot be vaccinated, the return to in-person schooling 5 days a week makes distancing difficult logistically, and ventilation requires time and money to fix. This leaves masks as the only defense against COVID for many students. Additional measures to stop the spread of the virus include testing, tracing, and isolating infected individuals. The Pennsylvania State Health Department offers free COVID testing for all K-12 schools and we should take them up on this offer."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. The scientific consensus on masking is that it works to reduce the spread of SARS-CoV-2 (the virus that causes COVID). Masks work best by impairing transmission from the source (an infected person), and since there is significant spread from both pre-symptomatic and asymptomatic individuals (people who are infected but do not know it), we need to mask everyone. Although vaccination reduces the likelihood of catching and transmitting the virus, we are seeing breakthrough infections in vaccinated individuals and should mask everyone to prevent spread. Masking is a simple yet effective preventive measure recommended by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP), and the Pennsylvania State Health Department. I am glad that starting September 7, the PA Health Department has mandated masking for all students K-12. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Currently the COVID vaccine approved for 12-15 year old children is under emergency use authorization only. However, once it has full FDA approval we should consider mandating it (with an exception if it is medically contraindicated).  Vaccine mandates are already in place for other infectious diseases (measles, mumps, chicken pox, etc.). Vaccination is our best tool to keep kids safely in school, in-person, without interruption."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The mission statement of Centennial School District states, “Inspiring students, building intellect, forging partnerships. A diverse learning community where students succeed through academics, athletics, and the arts.” There is also a diversity pledge, “I pledge to treat everyone as I would like to be treated. I will be accepting of people from all backgrounds and show them respect. I pledge to learn about other cultures and develop an appreciation for everyone’s uniqueness.” Our study body is diverse in terms of race, ethnicity, socio-economic background, religion, sexual orientation, and gender. We should continue to make our school district a safe and equitable learning environment for all students."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["School boards do not set the curriculum. However, many of our students encounter racism as part of their day-to-day lives, and schools could help to lessen this burden by having open discussions about this topic. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tina_m._cairns","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Centennial School District is a “No Place for Hate” community. As stated in the student handbooks, bullying and harassment because of one’s “sex, sexual orientation, and gender identity/expression” are not tolerated. The high school also has a GSA (Genders & Sexualitied Alliance) Club which meets after school. We should continue to build on what we are currently doing and support our LGBTQ+ students."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a 18-year resident of Upper Makefield and a mom.  I want to take my success as a business owner and my passion for kids to bring steady and transparent leadership to the CR school district.  Education has always been very important to me. I have an MBA from Wharton in Finance and Strategy, and Masters’ degrees in Math and Statistics. I will put children first in every decision, no hidden agenda.  I care about the unique needs of each student, and I believe in building a community that supports everyone.  We need to support the parents that raise their families here. For residents without children in our school district, I believe in responsible spending and planning for the future. The erratic decisions made by our school board over the last year have led many parents to remove their children from the district. The strength of our school district is what keeps our property values high.  I will be a voice of reason and source of steady leadership and a different perspective."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Currently the top issue facing our district is making sure we are protecting the health and safety of our students during this surge in the pandemic. Being sensible about how we handle the pandemic at the schools will also decrease the risks of outbreaks and increase the likelihood that our schools stay open. We know kids learn best in the classroom and following the advice of medical experts is how we keep them there. My opponent and the majority of the current board have repeatedly disregarded the opinion of medical experts. ","Disregarding experts has fostered unnecessary division and polarization in our community, another major issue in our school district. I will work to bring the community together with respect, compassion, empathy and thoughtfulness.  We must help our kids academically, socially and emotionally especially as we recover from the pandemic.  We can achieve more by uniting around our common objectives, and being civil to each other."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The school district needs to protect the health, safety and well-being of our students based on the advice of experts and peer-reviewed, validated science. Examples are the CDC, the PA Dept of Health, the Bucks County Health Dept, and the American Academy of Pediatrics.  The school board members need to follow the advice of the experts in order to protect our children and implement mitigation measures to guarantee our children are safe and stay in school."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Unlike my opponent, I trust experts and believe that as long as the experts recommend masking, a mask mandate should be used in order to protect our children and our community from disease. It is important to care about others and not only about ourselves. I understand that for most people it is more comfortable not wearing a mask, but it is a small price to pay to keep our kids and staff safe and our schools open."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The best path to eliminating Covid and lessening the impact on our daily lives is through vaccination. I believe vaccination should be required for students and teachers except for the small percentage of individuals that qualify for a legitimate medical exemption. Vaccinations for polio, measles, hepatitis and other highly contagious. diseases have been required in PA schools for decades. That requirement has nearly eliminated the transmission of those diseases.  Until the point that vaccines are required, we should provide incentives to encourage vaccination for our staff and students 12+. Once a vaccine is approved for our younger students, we need to encourage vaccination for them too."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Every child is different, and we need to build a community that supports everyone, in every step of their journey from elementary school through high school.  We must prepare the next generation to experience a diverse world where they will work with many different types of people.  We need to celebrate the diversity that we have and be broadly inclusive."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Council Rock School District’s 2019-2023 strategic plan has a well-defined strategy to embrace and incorporate diversity in all of its various dimensions, and continue to build an inclusive and welcoming environment for all students and District stakeholders. We need to ensure this strategy is implemented and to take actions to embrace our diversity. My opponent ran on a platform in the Primary insinuating our Council Rock students are being “indoctrinated” by our teachers. This conspiratorial claim has absolutely no basis in fact, is an opinion that is not shared by the majority of parents in our community, and is an example of an extreme and dangerous political agenda that has no place on our school board"]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_yota_palli","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["As I mentioned earlier, we need to celebrate our diversity and be inclusive of minority communities including our LGBTQ students.  We need to understand what the inequities are, and then create a plan to fix them.  No bullying should be tolerated of anyone who is different, and we must have educational classes and seminars where we teach students and staff to be accepting of our differences."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have nearly 30 years of experience in public education.  As a school superintendent for the last eight years, I have acquired extensive experience and skills in all areas of school operations - finance, security, personnel, instruction, special education, and public relations. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Keeping schools open and keeping kids in school.  I plan to promote layered prevention strategies based on science and best practice."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Follow advice of public health experts and implement layered prevention strategies, while planning to effectively pivot as needed.  "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Schools should implement practices endorsed by public health experts/agencies.  Masks or no masks may vary depending on current conditions."]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Schools should implement practices endorsed by public health experts/agencies. "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["All students need equal access to the curriculum to learn.  No one would ever think of denying a far-sighted student glasses to be given the same opportunity as a student with 20/20 vision.  All students with disabilities should be given comparable accommodations to provide access to learning opportunities.  "]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Historical facts should be taught with opportunities for reflection, dialogue, and growth.  \"If you want the present to be different from the past, study the past.\" - Baruch Spinoza"]},{"candidateCode":"council_rock_school_director_roy_rakszawski","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All students should be treated with respect and dignity.  It's important to cultivate a caring school climate.  "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a recently retired Police Officer, having served for 20 years.  Prior to being a Police Officer I was a professional Fire Fighter employed by the US Navy, after which I was an EMT, then Paramedic for 14 years.  I have a total of 40 years in the Emergency Services.  This service has provided me a unique insight into life and people.  It has taught me to listen to, and fully understand and appreciate, every person as an individual.  This skill is critical because every person and situation is unique and must be taken into account.  It has also provided me with the ability to remain completely neutral while determining the best course of action in many different situations.  Most importantly it has taught me the value of service, and of the responsibility that comes with serving.  An elected office, just like the Emergency Services, exists for the people, not for one's self, something that can never be lost sight of."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The debate over mandated masking is a symptom of the problem. The controlling majority of the current board has been completely unresponsive and very disrespectful to parents and voters. They have lost sight of the meaning of service. Regardless of their position on the issue, the way the issue has been handled is the problem.  Broadcasting public meetings instead of holding them in person to be accountable and responsive when in person meetings were possible with accommodations, requiring that questions be submitted via email which completely eliminates responsiveness, shutting down speakers in the middle of their presentation at the mask vote meeting.  These are all indicative of a board that has forgotten who they serve, and why they were elected.  Government of the people, by the people, and for the people, applies just as fully to a School Board as it does to the President of the United States.  The simple and obvious solution to this problem is to be transparent and accountable. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["COVID 19 is a concern for the Country, there is no question about that, but a one size fits all mandate is not the answer.  Parents and school staff obviously want the best for their children and students, and for themselves.  Both school staff and parents are smart, and can be trusted to make the right decisions, given full and accurate information.  Guidelines and policies that are reasonable and consider both health and safety as well as individual rights, need to be in place in accordance with current medical and scientific data.  They must not be dictated by political whims or ideology.  The full information and reasoning regarding how these guidelines and policies are developed must be made available. Most importantly, the absolute right of parents to make the best decisions for their children must be protected."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["A mask mandate eliminates the right of parents to make the best decisions for the children. Parents in this District are smart, and are also caring.  I cannot see anyone making a conscious choice to put any child at risk.  Masks should be optional.  If a parent wants their child to wear a mask, they should be free to do so.  Equally important, if a parent does not want their child to wear a mask, they should be free to exercise that right.  Each decision is highly personal and just as valid.  No one side has the right to impose by mandate their values or views on another."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The answer to this question is the same as above.  Masks are transient, vaccinations are not.  Mandating that a person inject a new medication that has not been fully vetted over many years, like our current standard vaccinations, into themselves or their children is unconscionable.  This decision must be left to the individual parent and teacher. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["True inclusion is at the heart of what makes this Country great.  Equality for all is enshrined in our founding documents.  Every person is different, with unique skills and gifts that should be nurtured and appreciated, not ignored by lumping them into a politically defined group. The discussion around Diversity and Inclusion efforts is complex and not something that allows itself to be packaged neatly into a 1000 character response as required here. I will gladly discuss this topic with any who ask, so that an in depth discussion may occur, free of political speak, but hopefully full of substance and idea exchange. There is no one person with a monopoly on how to address the challenges we face today. Only together, as a local community, can we build the schools that best serve our children."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Racism cannot be tolerated pure and simple.  Those that will use race as a weapon to divide us cannot be tolerated.  My answer to the above question serves well as the answer to this question because the underlying philosophy is the same.  All people are created equal.  This is an undeniable and simple truth. I will speak with any Centennial resident regarding my views on how best to address this issue, but to be able to provide a substantive answer to this issue in 1,000 characters or less is just not possible. Only soundbites and clichés would fill such a small space. These are not small issues with short answers, but profound questions for our items that require serious discussion and engagement. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_mark_gindhart","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["This ties directly to my answers to the previous two questions.  All people are created equal. Period. The very idea of lumping people into politically predefined groups only serves to undermine and eliminate diversity, not strengthen it. Labeling people in this manner highlights differences in a negative way, and is destructive.  Our differences are our strength, not a political convenience. How best to serve any individual, regardless of who they are or how they identify, is again a conversation that cannot be fully and fairly answered in 1,000 characters. I will gladly discuss with any Centennial resident my views on these and any issues, but I cannot summarize my views in such a small space. I reiterate, these are not small issues with short answers, but profound questions for our times that require serious discussion and engagement."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am running for this office because I believe I offer a unique and valuable perspective.  My wife and I have been members of the Quakertown community for the past fourteen years.  As a parent, I want my children to receive the best possible educational experience.  Our children’s education is priceless, and they deserve the best we can provide.  My background is in accounting and I am a regional controller for Georgia Pacific.  I am responsible for managing the budgets of eight plants worth over a billion dollars in revenue and I engage with people from all different backgrounds to brainstorm and solve problems.  I understand the value of being fiscally responsible and if elected, I will work with the Board of Directors and QCSD Administration to reach a balanced budget that meets the students’ needs and keeps the taxpayers in mind.  Finally, my wife is a schoolteacher in a neighboring school district.  I have a front row seat to the effort, struggles, and successes of this profession"]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_todd_hippauf","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["14 Years experience as a Centennial School Director. Served on various boards in Warminster. Knowledge of budgets along with communicating with the public to address their concerns."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Education. As a large percentage of students have fallen behind last year in their studies. My main concern is developing relationships with Parents and Students to identify any areas    extra help is needed to improve their educational experience.  "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The School District should have had a qualified speaker to address the overall subject of Covid. By having an expert, the public could of had their questions answered. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The School District voted to have masks a requirement for all.  There are exemptions for Religion and Medical reasons or conditions. I can not nor will I tell someone what he or she should do. This is a personal choice individuals must decide for themselves."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["This once again is an individuals choice and they alone must decide."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["For many years, Centennial School District has developed policies and procedures to address these subjects."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Follow up on instituted programs and discuss their results."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_jane_schrader_lynch","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I believe Centennial has instituted policies and programs to support these students."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a born and raised Neshaminy person (Class of 2000) with two children that are students in the district. I also come from a family of educators and my wife is a middle school teacher in the district. I am a licensed professional engineer and have built a career as a civil (roads and bridges) engineering planner, designer, and project manager which requires a mindset of information gathering; building consensus among different stakeholders; and being a lifelong learner. Neshaminy is a part of my fabric and I care deeply about the quality of life, education, and success of our children.  "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["There are a large number of Neshaminy schools that need major improvements. I would like to take part in the decision making to determine whether retrofitting existing or building new schools would be more beneficial for the community and to make sure we are implementing the latest and greatest technologies and design practices into those improvements. My background in infrastructure planning and design, along with my understaning of the stakeholder coordination and approvals process, will be an asset regarding this issue. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I believe Neshaminy is adequately addressing COVID in schools, through a layered approach that includes wearing masks, air filtering, cleaning and sanitizing, etc. One approach that has been very helpful for parents is the continuous direct line of communication from the superintendent to the community regarding all things COVID related.  ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, at this point in time it appears to be allowing our schools to remain open, which should be the #1 priority. By taking these precautions now, the hope is to get to a normal learning environment as quickly and safely as possible."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am not in a position to recommend or suggest medical advice for individuals and families. However, if research shows that vaccinations keep our community safer and schools open, it appears that a vaccination requirement should be considered."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Neshaminy is and always has been a diverse community filled with people from different ethnic backgrounds, economic standing, and religious beliefs, which is a benefit to our student body."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I think it is very important for the curriculum to reflect a belief that all races should be equally respected."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_kellen_sporny","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All people should be free to learn and grow in a welcoming environment and free of stigmas, bullying, or other scenarios where they might feel ostracized. I think the best way to maintain this is through educating students and staff that there are other ways of life besides their own and that everyone is equal.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have attended dozens of School Board and committee meetings over the last few years and am very familiar with the topics, procedures, and personalities involved.  I have a passion for education and have been researching public education issues for years. I decided to run because I did not see many of the existing board members putting in the effort that the position demands. I will appreciate and consider and communicate the concerns of everybody in the district, from parents, to custodians, to the superintendent. As a Bensalem graduate myself (and self-described \"Education Nerd\"), and with my own two children in our schools, I am deeply invested in getting it right for my own children, and for all of our children. I willing to put in the time to not just do the job, but to do it well - using creativity, data, and common sense."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["It is difficult to detangle the two top issues of educational performance and school funding. Educational quality typically follows income, especially as Pennsylvania relies more on local funding than 45 other states. Bensalem is therefore underfunded compared to most of the other districts in Bucks County forcing the district to choose between tax hikes and improving educational opportunities.  With a multipronged approach of finding creative revenue streams to bring money to the district, enhancing options and reputation to keep kids here (rather than sending money to other entities), and creating a detailed long-term fiscal plan so that we know where we are heading; we will be able to shore up our financial situation and focus on education. I also intend to focus on increasing parental engagement in English-as-Second-Language families as it will be a key to improving student performance."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["COVID-19 is a highly communicable disease. There are a limited number of places where people are in such close proximity for as a long a period of time as in our schools. However, remote learning was generally a poor experience for teachers, parents, and students alike. Our priority should be to enable safe, in-person instruction in our school buildings. Schools have been provided federal funding to improve ventilation, the ability to distance children when necessary, communicate cases to families, and make up for learning loss from the previous year and a half. Our district should plan to take full advantage of these funds as soon as possible. As we know, younger children are less susceptible to COVID, but it behooves us to put our children in safe surroundings. When community transmission is high, there are a number of, albeit rare, cases where school transmission follows. We do not want to be one of those cases. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, especially while community transmission of COIVD is increasing. Since 1995 I have worn masks at work in semiconductor cleanrooms. We are able to identify each other and each other's emotions through small openings in our hoods. We joke and laugh all day. We can work a full 8-hour or 12-hour shift without becoming weary. We are not embarrassed and we are not sickly. My own children who (trust me) will argue and fight at length about everything imaginable do not give me trouble about wearing masks. Their friends in sports, scouts, etc... are fine with wearing them when necessary as well. I believe that the vast majority of our most creative, flexible, adaptable minds can be masked at school with no consequence. For those that can't, exceptions are permitted. I know many parents who do oppose mask wearing, so as a school board member I would require metrics about what level of community transmission requires school masking, and what age groups would be affected.",""]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, at this point in time it appears to be allowing our schools to remain open, which should be the #1 priority. By taking these precautions now, the hope is to get to a normal learning environment as quickly and safety as possible."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The district commissioned a Needs Assessment early this year that clearly showed educational performance issues with minority and economically disadvantaged groups. Those results are likely duplicated almost everywhere in the world. We have a choice to simply accept that is the way things are, or take the opportunity to make positive change. If we want Bensalem to be the pride of Bucks County, we must help elevate these children so that performance is based on ability, not circumstance. I support the efforts of our Diversity, Equity, & Inclusion (DEI) Committee to hire a DEI coordinator that will help to craft metric-based steps to ensure that these students get the proper resources to improved their chances and elevate the ENTIRE school population. If improvements targets are not met, then we must re-evaluate and make changes. Bringing up achievement district wide is one of my primary motivations for seeking this position."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I recently met a 21-year-old who grew up in Georgia. She was taught in school that the Civil War was fought over states rights and that slaves were happy and content. That is absolutely not what is taught here, but we do not live in a bubble and need to be mindful of the world around us. I love the idea of learning about little known figures in science and history and the arts that were unappreciated (due to gender or race or economic/educational standing) in their times. That is not rewriting of history, but the true spirit of education. Some of the things I learned that I did not \"expect\" have been the most transformative in my life. Also, in Civil Rights curriculum I do believe it is important to note that not everybody has put racial issues behind them. Racism is ABSOLUTELY endemic to humanity and it is only our customs and our institutions that hold it at bay. Our brain chemistry has not simply changed in the last 50 years. So we must always be vigilant and educated."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_school_director_scott_endicter","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["We need to ensure that ALL students can learn in a safe and supportive environment. Our guidance counselors, students, and parents can help inform the district if these children are facing a different experience than non-LGBTQ+ children.  Our Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion Committee and Coordinator would likely be the starting place to address problems in this department.","I would like to add that while this questionnaire spent a lot of time on \"hot topics\" of the day, I have been involved with the board since it was only matters of roofs, pools, maintenance, school busses, math curriculum, fields, clubs and activities, communication, facility rentals, taxes, budgets, and the small matter of making sure our children are the best educated, best American citizens they can be. Long after the other topics have left the headlines, I will remain an Education Nerd to the end. Please vote on November 2nd.",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a businesswoman, I have to think strategically, see both sides of an issue and bring consensus, be able to ask the right questions and manage a budget that delivers results. I am also a founding member of a women's employee resource group and have been an advocate for growth and advancement of women in the workplace. These skills will serve my duties on the school board well.","In addition, as a first generation American, my grandparents immigrated from Eastern Europe during WWII, sacrificing everything to provide their children and now great-grandchildren the gift of living in the greatest country in the world. They worked hard, took personal responsibility to build new lives in a foreign land and taught their families to love America. Growing up close to these experiences gives me a unique perspective that will bring diversity of background, thought and values to our school board, making it a better performing governing body."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Keeping a focus on classic academics and helping our students increase their performance in math, science and English while keeping divisive ideologies and politics out of the classroom. Properly defining the problem will be the first step of the process."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["After dealing with COVID for over a year, our nation has learned children are not impacted by COVID at the same rate or severity as adults. Common sense protocols - staying home when sick, washing or sanitizing hands frequently, eating lunch and holding classes outdoors in the fresh air when weather permits - are the best option for keeping our schools safe while maintaining consistency and in-person learning for our children."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Masks should be optional for students and teachers. They impede verbal and non-verbal communication, make it difficult to breathe, become germ filled from being touched constantly and there is not good evidence that they do much to control the spread of COVID."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The vaccine should not be required for students and teachers. It does not necessarily prevent contracting COVID or spreading it to others, is less effective than natural immunity and the long-term effects are unknown at this point in time. Most importantly, each individual has the right to determine what they put into their body - it is a matter of privacy."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Pennridge schools should be a place of high academic standards and performance, with a focus on creative and critical thinking, life skills and the classics are taught. They should welcome diversity of cultures, backgrounds, experiences, opinions, perspectives and thoughts but leave values, beliefs and identity for parents to teach in the home."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The history of racism in America has been taught in our schools for decades and continues to be taught. Pennridge students know racism is wrong."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_christine_batycki","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Like all students in our district, LGBTQ+ students deserve a safe learning environment where they can thrive."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have 38 years of experience working in education from teaching in the classroom to leading a department that provided preparation for students to enter into their next chaptor in life that being college or work career. I worked with the administration of all 13 school districts in Bucks County in a self-sustaining department and also currently serving as a director at both MBIT and Centennial School District. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Making sure that each school student is treated equally and receive the best possible academic instruction. We need to allow parents and families to have input in today's education and look beyond just data collection.  Expect each student to learn and be challenged by the outstanding teaching staff we have in Centennial SD.  We need to listen to families and keep the administration focused on maintaining cost effectiveness in services and with a positive outlook in the community we service.  Prepare our student to meet success year after year with high expectation and encouragement."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Minimize the impact it has on student with options. Students should be in school full time and have optimal learning. Encourage staff and students12 and older to get vaccinated or show negative COVID test on a weekly basis. "]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["A fully approved vaccine is available for all over 12 years of age and is recommended. With the limited impact of COVID on younger children, they should allow students have the option of wearing a mask or not. Given the choice can protect both sides of the perspectives and assist in reducing the current adversary concerns. It gives families insight in school activity and freedom from an outright mandate."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["It should be highly recommended and a firm health check documenting that a healthy student or staff is entering the school facility if vaccinated or unvaccinated. We want the best learning situation for the entire community and keep COVID under control. We must trust families with the elementary students sending a healthy person to school."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Each student should be treated with respect and equality is expected to be the norm in the classroom. We do need to eliminate bullying in the schools. Academic skills acquisition is our mission."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["We are all Americans many of us from various immigration countries like myself. Our core teaching should be English, Math, Science and Social studies. Centennial SD is already a diverse school district within the community and employees."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_flemming_godiksen","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Bullying is at times a factor for minority groups and every student should be treated as an individual with respect. Centennial has recently added staff to assist any students needing support. Each student will with my support receive the highest quality of education possible in Centennial SD"]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":[" My 10+ years of experience on School Board, or on board committees, informed by my professional experience as a business owner dealing with facility and utility issues. And experience as an educator in mechanical arts and trades."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The primary issue of any school district is to provide a high quality education to our students balanced against the burden of cost to our stake holders. I am well versed in contract negotiations, Labor issues, and facility operations. I am also well read and a life long learner myself. I use that experience and knowledge that I continue to gain during board discussion. I believe my voice and opinions hold value and weight with my peers on the board and I shall continue to use that influence in the best interest of our students, staff, and stake holders.  "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["We have worked closely with the Lower Bucks Health Department to craft an Health and Safety Plan that includes, distancing, mask protocols, and rigorous cleaning and disinfecting. We have significantly improved building environments over the last several years with new conditioning and air handling equipment. Covid brought the additional improvement of UV and Bi-Polar ionization units. In the years leading up this Pandemic we had significantly expanded our servers and online capabilities. Not in anticipation we would need to go all online but it served us well when that became the reality. "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The goal is to keep our children in the buildings. While I prefer to appeal to our students desire to contribute to the common good of our community and voluntarily wear masks if they so choose and that was the directive from our local health officials, the Governor's mandate regarding masks removed that option from the board and administration. The issue now becomes the rules regarding removing children from the classrooms (quarantining) based on status of mask/unmasked, distance, and level of exposure, time. Currently the closer we ask the students to follow those rules the less likely we will be forced into a situation of needing to go back to hybrid education, which we all agree is less then ideal.   "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I prefer the word recommend over require. As I stated in my prior response I believe in appealing to peoples better nature over making demands. Perhaps its my experience in scouting that molded that opinion. I believe if you clearly explain the pros and cons of any given situation, benefits and consequences then allow people to make a choice. I believe the majority will choose to act for the greater good. Our role as educators includes a social element as we prepare our older students for their place in the community. I believe strongly that this is a teachable moment, a life experience that will serve our students well. Which is why I preferred to leave this as their choice. I'm confident the majority would have chosen to wear masks especially as the alternative should covid cases continue to rise would likely be losing the option of in person education.   "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["For one hiring practices, staffing. I'm not suggesting there is a bias in the district but I believe we must remain vigilant and aware that personal biases do not enter into hiring decisions. That should naturally lead to staff reflecting the diversity of our student population. By example and exposure to people of varying race, religion, and culture, our students should see diversity is not something to be feared.  "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["We have educational committees who frequently assess our teaching material. I think that should continue with an eye towards insuring honest facts are presented in the material rather then opinions skewed one direction or the other. I think its important to view history and social studies in particular from various points of view in order to understand it as a whole. I would encourage our educational committees to bear that in mind when choosing course material.  "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_john_allen","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I think that falls back to some of my previous answers in that I believe we should insure that they are accepted and welcomed as members of our community and that our school should not be a place fraught with anxiety for them. a support system of peers and administration should be in place for them as it is for all students. And of course education. Education is now and always the key to overcoming society's problems.     "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["These past two years have been challenging for our students, our families, our teachers, our administrators, and our support staff.  As a parent and an educator, I have a unique perspective that allows me to see the district's issues from a variety of viewpoints.  As an award-winning teacher, I understand, on a personal level, what it takes to make education successful.  And as a parent of four children, I understand the challenges that face our families each day in this district.  Additionally, I spent 15 years in the business world prior to becoming a teacher, so I have the tools necessary to tackle our district's massive $350 million budget.  I believe that we must equip our teachers and staff with the tools they need to provide the best possible education at a price our taxpayers can afford."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["While CBSD currently faces a host of issues, from ongoing support staff contract negotiations and upcoming teacher contract negotiations, to the implementation of new curricula and technologies, to a ballooning budget in the face of declining enrollment, our district has many areas that will require intense focus from our next board.  But the most pressing issue is the fractured relationship between the various stakeholders in our district and community.  The past two years created divisions and distrust, and it must be the top priority of the incoming board to create an action plan to address these relationships in measurable steps.  As a teacher, parent, and taxpayer, I am uniquely suited to bring all the parties together in the best interest of the students."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Schools are in a difficult position at this moment, with pressures from county and state officials to exercise board legal authority that is based in very little case law or precedent.  I believe schools need focused mitigations that are based on local data and designed to protect student health while protecting in-person education.  The one debate where everyone agrees is the need for an in-person instruction model, so all plans should focus on keeping as many kids in school as possible."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["This questions assumes that candidates are in a position to vote on this issue, which is currently a mandate from the PA Dept of Health.  I believe that school boards should have the ability to make these decisions based on local data, as a one-size-fits-all approach for all of Pennsylvania will always be unfair to some groups.  Additionally, as we continue to debate the mask requirements in one board meeting after another, we are taking time away from contract negotiations, teacher professional development, student social-emotional health initiatives, curriculum review, and much more.  We need to get back to managing the nuts and bolts of delivering education."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Creating a mandate that applies to all persons without consideration of individual medical needs and/or personal and religious beliefs would not be a vote I could support."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["CBSD adopted a diversity and inclusion initiative as part of the current Comprehensive Plan.  I believe that a thorough review of the district's current progress through each of the steps in that initiative would need to happen prior to recommending any new steps or initiatives.  It is important that we consistently review our current processes to find successes that can be duplicated and opportunities that need to be addressed so we can approach these issues in a deliberate way to always be moving forward as a district. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe the first step would be to assemble a team of teachers and staff to examine current curricula to determine any areas of opportunity and research-based best practices that address those needs in the way that we would bring forth curriculum changes to a math or science program.  The curriculum review process that already exists in the district should be followed any time we are looking to make adjustments."]},{"candidateCode":"central_bucks_school_director_james_bender","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["As a teacher, I believe that making all students feel safe and supported is the number one priority of any district employee.  We should work with stakeholders, including teachers, students, guidance staff, and administrators to determine our district's areas of success that we can duplicate and areas of opportunity to address.  Every single student deserves to feel at home when at school, regardless of personal identity, so that all students are receiving the highest level of education possible."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a lifelong resident of Warminster, I have always called this area ‘Home.’ My commitment to the community includes all members, though I have a particular passion to serve our youth. In prior roles, I worked as an educator in classrooms and feel strongly that comprehensive educational opportunities are vital to student development and success. I state this as a current professional in the social service sector and former student in this school system.","","I went through my entire K-12 education in the Centennial School District and know firsthand the importance of strong leadership at every level. I am a proud graduate of William Tennent High School and earned Master of Public Policy and MBA degrees. My range of skills includes policy implementation, financial management, and continuous improvement, which are all fundamental School Board duties. I am deeply motivated to collaborate and achieve efficient and effective outcomes for not only students, but for every community member alike."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The ongoing pandemic remains a top issue facing the school district. It is crucial to keep everyone in our schools safe and maintain an optimum learning environment for every student. This is top priority, along with comprehensive supports to ensure each individual’s success.","","Since this issue began over a year ago, schools were forced to adjust and adhere to state mandated requirements, whether that meant online distanced learning or in-person learning with masks. School responses have evolved alongside the virus, and as a candidate, I have been engaging with community members to receive feedback on these measures. As an elected official, my plan is to consider conditions at the time to improve such experiences and inform any future decisions made by the Board."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Learning should be the focus in schools, which is why it is imperative school districts take appropriate steps to address COVID. At this time, the school district is obligated to comply with state mandates of masks and physical distancing. Accommodations, such as the virtual learning option, are crucial components made available to meet any individual student’s needs. Disseminating timely and transparent information about COVID precautions and incidents is also an important step to not only keep parents informed but also communicate important updates to the larger community.","","A comprehensive school district plan to properly address COVID is integral to providing a healthy, comfortable learning environment, so every student may reach their full potential."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Currently mask requirements for students and teachers are mandated by the state. Any future decisions on masks would be relative to the conditions at that time. Even with current school mandates, there are opportunities to safely remove masks at various times, such as during recess. Like many, I was relieved when mask requirements were universally lifted earlier this summer as cases declined and look forward to that happening again."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I find it disheartening that vaccination became such a charged political topic. As a child, I received all the standard vaccines schools (still) require and feel fortunate to not have lived through times when diseases like Polio, Measles, and Diphtheria were commonplace. The advancement of medical science is nothing short of amazing in its progress to lengthen and improve quality of life."," ","Immunization protection impacts us on both personal and collective levels- the reason long-standing vaccine requirements exist. Vaccine hesitancy leads to preventable virus contraction, which further endangers children under the age of 12, who are ineligible to safely inoculate. Approved COVID vaccines for those over the age of 12 provide additional protection- strongly encouraged, but not a current necessary requirement."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Fostering diversity and inclusion in the school district benefits everyone. Our social and cultural differences make us each unique and worthy of meaningful contributions to one another. Engaging with people of varying backgrounds and perspectives enriches our schools for students and staff alike. Representation can also be a powerful confirmation for students to see themselves reflected in school leadership and exposure to people with differing attributes similarly enhances knowledge and broader principles of inclusion. Diversity and inclusion go beyond just fairness and should be celebrated as they provide us all in the school district a vital form of strength."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Curriculum changes do not fall under the purview of the School Board and are not decided by School Board Directors."," ","That said, the School Board carries a responsibility to “ensure educational opportunities for all students of the school district.” I take seriously this dedication to *all* students and worked closely in past roles with vulnerable populations who may experience disproportionate challenges in school and need additional support. Regardless of race, gender, sex, sexual orientation, socio-economic and/or ability status, every student deserves the attention and care that will set them up for a trajectory of success. Racism and other forms of hate and discrimination are unacceptable and infringe on student rights, safety, and overall well-being."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_nicole_rinier","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Schools are critical places for youth development. While any student may struggle as they mature into adulthood, difficulties for LGBTQ+ students compound if they lack acceptance and support. Data shows students who identify as LGBTQ+ face a higher risk of bullying by peers, which can have devastating effects on their physical/mental health and academic performance. In previous positions, I facilitated prevention programs to equip students with tools of healthy friendships and relationships which mitigate bullying and other forms of violence. These programs are one example of significant steps all students may be provided for well-rounded school support."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I’m running as the kind of person my friends and neighbors want to see better represented on our School Board – an involved parent of current students who is tired of the partisan circus that has made that body an embarrassment for too long. I’m entering my second year as President of McDonald Home & School Association and have been an active school volunteer for many years. I want to add the perspective of a dad of an elementary and middle schooler who cares about our students, teachers, and principals. We have begun to see progress over the past few years, with new Directors who are addressing long-standing issues. If we don’t keep up the positive momentum and elect people who will act in good faith, our kids suffer. We can’t afford to fall back. I love our district and want to help make it even better. School Board is supposed to be about common sense. We may not always agree, but you’ll know I cast my votes in the best interest of our children and the future of our community."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Beyond the pandemic, a major issue facing our district is a combination of disinformation and poor communication. People don’t feel heard, and even though meetings are public and CSD has been trying to put out more info, people don’t feel there’s a clarity of message, mission, or curriculum. Our community will always be divided on some issues, but there is no chance of moving forward without some common ground and a general sense that we’re acting with purpose and clear direction. A year apart didn’t help – it’s easy to vilify people when you’re not looking them in the eye, laughing with them at events, hearing what they have to say, and seeing their humanity. Centennial can’t succeed if it’s Us vs. Them. It’s a group project. Running for School Board was the first time I learned how folks I’ve known for a decade are registered to vote! It just doesn’t matter, as long as we’re focused on the right things and behaving like adults rather than the children we’re supposed to serve."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Safety is non-negotiable. Basing decisions on science and health data from experts is a must; making policy based on feelings and unfounded conspiracy theories is irresponsible and dangerous. My children, the children of my friends and neighbors, and our wonderful teachers are at risk if we try to be cute and placate people who are living in another reality. Some are willing to encourage their antics for political gain. It’s inexcusable and shameful. And this sentiment is bipartisan! As I’ve been out knocking on doors, people of all political stripes have been overwhelmingly clear that getting kids back in schools is the goal – and if they have to wear masks or consider vaccines, that’s okay. It’s not about fear – it’s about unity in the face of something we can beat if we take it seriously."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, depending upon health recommendations and data. The “kids don’t get sick” talking point is a dangerous lie. None of us live in a vacuum. Teachers have lives outside of school buildings. Wearing a mask is a simple act that can help prevent spread and keep people safe – especially when not all are vaccinated. The science may change over time. That’s what science does. We learn more, then adapt and move forward smarter and better. With high levels at the start of this school year, we have to take precautions like masking up in the buildings. No one likes wearing masks all the time. I don’t. But we have to pull together and keep fighting through this thing. Children are susceptible as COVID continues to spread and mutate. I know too many people who have contracted COVID, some with nasty, long-lasting effects. It isn’t going to magically disappear."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["While medical decisions belong to families, kids are already required to get several vaccines. I strongly encourage everyone eligible to get theirs. We can’t have COVID jeopardizing our schools, communities, economy, elections, entire way of life, etc. forever. The vaccine is approved. It will soon be available to children. It is safe and effective. Get vaccinated, and let’s get back to living our lives. I miss big in-person school events like Donut Days with parents, dances, and May Fair! Want kids in school? Masks. Tired of masks? Get the shot."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["I love how diverse our schools are! The world is diverse, and it’s important for kids to experience and appreciate people who don’t look, speak, or think like them. Inclusion goes beyond race. Students with special needs want to be included and not treated like a separate subculture among their peers. We have socioeconomic differences that create both challenges our schools must meet to ensure all students have a chance to succeed, and opportunities to show students the importance of empathy, generosity, and community. Educating in a welcoming, constructive way, encouraging conversations, and helping to address any concerns or questions our young people have will make them better people with a richer understanding of the world."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The School Board does not set the curriculum, but kids aren’t just in school to perform well on standardized tests. Beyond reading, math and science, they are in school to gain an understanding of the world around them and how to function in society. We should be having conversations when concerns arise and working hard to ensure every student has a chance to succeed, to feel welcome and accepted, and to pursue their dreams."]},{"candidateCode":"centennial_school_director_tony_sadowski","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All Centennial students should expect a supportive environment where they have every opportunity to learn, grow, and thrive. This is a blanket statement, because it’s not necessary to single out any particular “group” of students. Young people are in our schools at a very formative time of their lives. They are figuring out their own identities, passions, likes, dislikes, causes, career goals, political beliefs, etc. LGBTQ+ students should feel welcome, nurtured, and equal – same as any other subset of the community. If there is an issue, the school should listen and determine the best course of action for resolving it. No one should be made to feel less-than simply for being who they are."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Currently I am the incumbent with one term (4 years) experience.  My undergraduate degree in Business/Accounting and Master's of Education make me the ideal candidate for the position.  I teach in the public school setting and have first hand knowledge and working experience with the education process.  As a former auditor and corporate accountant, I possess over 15 years experience analyzing financial statements and budget development."]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["COVID-19 protocols are the top issue facing Neshaminy School District.  I worked throughout the pandemic during my tenure on school board for both Neshaminy and Bucks Technical High School.  Plans for addressing the COVID-19 issue should be fluid as the situation evolves.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Districts should make every attempt to keep students in school while mitigating the spread of the virus.  I support safely keeping schools, sports and arts programs open for students.   Education about the virus spread and vaccine awareness is in the forefront.  While serving on Neshaminy and Bucks County Technical High School Boards I supported providing  clinics and easy access for students and staff that wished to get vaccinated.",""]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support safe protocols for students and staff within schools.  While serving on the Neshaminy and Bucks County Technical High School Boards, I respected parents' views on how to keep their children safe while attending classes.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["During my tenure, I supported clinics held at the schools for those that wanted to receive the vaccine.  I respect parents' views on how to keep their children safe while attending classes.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Neshaminy has a strong foundation of promoting diversity, building inclusion and educational equity in every classroom.  As an active participant and current Chairperson of the Educational Development Committee at Neshaminy, I assisted on the development of our upcoming comprehensive plan which solidifies practices of a fair and balanced education for all students.  "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Neshaminy has built a strong foundation and community of promoting diversity and inclusion for all students and staff.  Neshaminy has an equity process of reforming practices, policies, and procedures at the school and district levels to support academic fairness to ensure that every student has access to the resources, teachers, interventions, and supports they need to be successful. Through inclusiveness, every student will feel safe, welcome, and included in their classrooms despite race, religion, culture or socio economic status.  "]},{"candidateCode":"neshaminy_school_director_cyndie_bowman","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Neshaminy has an equity process of reforming practices, policies, and procedures at the school and district levels to support academic fairness and inclusion and ensure that every student has access to the resources, teachers, interventions, and supports they need to be successful. Through inclusiveness included in our comprehension plan, every student will feel safe, welcome, and included in their classrooms.",""]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a School Director, I will give back to the Quakertown community and help our schools prosper. Throughout the years, I have volunteered my time to help our community. I recently helped and served on a School Board Committee. I also coached teams for Quakertown Soccer and Quakertown Youth Baseball.","","I have resided in the Quakertown Community for 17 years. My wife Michele has resided in Milford Township for over 40 years and graduated from Quakertown High School. I am the proud parent of 4 children; 2 daughters and 2 sons. Our 2 youngest children attend Pfaff Elementary School. As parents, we value education in nurturing and developing our children and our lives.","","As an engineer and consultant, I provide solutions to clients facing challenges. I am compelled to apply my consulting skills in providing solutions to help our schools. Our community is facing challenges every day. In working together, we can adjust and adapt to life's complexities to help our children learn."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["TAXES, SAFETY and EDUCATION. You can count on me to hold the line on taxes and keep students safe in school for instruction. QSCD is facing financial burdens along with a declining student enrollment. I truly value education for our children. As a School Board member and strong leader, I will orchestrate key partnerships with internal and external stakeholders to achieve goals for our community. This will include strategic solutions for the short-term and long-term. As an engineer at heart, I thrive under pressure to meet the challenges. I usually receive the first call when there is a major problem at hand. I welcome the challenges ahead, and look forward to providing great schools for our children to learn and grow."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_glenn_nicholas_iosue","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a current Board Director, educator, business woman, mother of a QCSD graduate, resident, and neighbor, I have the unique ability to approach the School Board position with practical experience in all areas of this role. By employing my skills of optimizing educational facilities and programs, managing budgets, communicating openly and transparently, and strategizing with leaders at all levels to solve for the educational and developmental needs of students, I will honor QCSD’s steep traditions while ushering us toward progress and continued growth. As a community member and mother of a QCSD graduate, my experience brings awareness to areas targeted for improvement while building on that which makes our district a desirable place to learn, work and live. I recognize my role is to represent the community at large and will objectively listen to the voices of all. I will earnestly pursue the compromise needed to bring our community together."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The key to controlling COVID in our schools is layered mitigation.  This includes:","        Universal masking for all students, teachers and staff in school buildings and on busses with exceptions for students with valid IEPs and 504s","        Physical distancing in classrooms and lunchrooms to the greatest extent possible","        Frequent handwashing/ample hand sanitizing stations","        Cleaning and maintenance of facilities","        Adequate ventilation and an increase of total airflow supply to occupied spaces","        Effective reporting, monitoring, rapid testing and tracing of suspected cases",""]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes.  For the safety of students, staff and the community, the school district should do everything within their power, including masking, to mitigate the spread of COVID-19. Universal masking is recommended by the CDC, WHO, AAP, and the Bucks County Department of Health.  Additionally, a mandate from the Pennsylvania Department of Health went into effect on Tuesday, September 7th, requiring students, teachers and staff to wear masks when indoors.  School districts are agents of the state, and therefore must be compliant with its laws."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID vaccination should be a family/personal decision, not one made by the schools."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Every policy and practice decision should be viewed through the lens of how the decision will impact students from diverse backgrounds.  DEI efforts should be built into the district’s Comprehensive Plan and include:","        Helping all students have stronger relationships and a sense of belonging","        Giving students from diverse backgrounds a voice and an opportunity to be represented in all courses and activities","        Helping students understand the importance of empathy and respect for other cultures and cultural activities","        Providing staff development on topics such as diverse perspectives, privilege, implicit bias, and meeting the needs of all students","        Selecting diverse curricular materials that reflect students’ backgrounds",""]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_jennifer_l._gross","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["        Set and enforce a vision/mission statement that is welcoming and inclusive of LGBTQ students","        Establish a welcoming and affirming environment for LGBTQ students and their allies","        Implement clear, consistent, and comprehensive non-discrimination policies that protect and affirm students’ sexual orientation, gender identity, and gender expression, and prohibit discrimination against students, families, and educators","        Ensure that anti-bullying and harassment policies specifically include protections for LGBTQ students","        Ensure that district and school policies are designed and implemented to support transgender and gender nonconforming students","        Ensure that professional development and educator resources include a focus on creating inclusive learning environments in which all students, including LGBTQ students, feel safe and welcome","        Assess and monitor school climate on a regular and ongoing basis",""]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have worked in and around education for almost 30 years. As a member of the news media, I covered many school districts in PA, NY, and NJ for 10 years. I also worked in the administration of three different PA school districts. I want to use my expertise to provide better educational opportunities for ALL children."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I am a strong proponent of Full Day Kindergarten. My twin boys both attended full-day Kindergarten and benefitted not only educationally, but were able to discover and support developmental issues that would not have manifested in a traditional Kindergarten environment. I feel QCSD missed an opportunity to provide this to all students, and if elected I will push the Board and Administration to make it a priority moving forward."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["QCSD is managing COVID well. As a community we all need to take mitigation efforts seriously and make the health and safety of our students and community a priority. We need to be flexible and adaptive when addressing this very serious issue."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The school district should do everything in its power to comply with state and federal mandates regarding COVID. I commended the Board on its action to allow parents a way to file for exceptions to the mandate for health reasons.","","Politics needs to take a back seat when it comes to the health and safety of our students. "]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The District should be doing everything in its power to reduce the spread and severity of issues caused by COVID. ","","I do not believe the District should mandate vaccines for students and staff. However, since it is the role of the School District to educate we need to make sure we are providing quality, third-party information that informs the community on the safety and effectiveness of the vaccine and other measures that will reduce the spread and severity of COVID. "]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["It is important to consistently monitor and review the actions and policies of the District in relation to diversity,  equity, and inclusion in education to make sure all students have equal access to high-quality educational opportunities.","","We should all be able to learn from examples of success in what we are taught and how we learn. By providing equal access to educational opportunities we allow students the ability to see successful versions of themselves and their cultures in their school work. ","","Diversity, equality, and inclusion goes beyond instruction and should include how we promote opportunities and conduct ourselves as professionals."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Curriculum should be reviewed regularly to ensure our students are getting the highest quality education and that everything taught is a true and verifiable depiction of facts."]},{"candidateCode":"quakertown_community_school_director_2-year_term_joseph_lyons","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Board Policy 103 states: The Board declares it to be the policy of this district to provide an equal opportunity for all students to achieve their maximum potential through the programs offered in the schools without discrimination on the basis of race, color, age, creed, religion, sex, sexual orientation, ancestry, national origin, marital status, pregnancy or handicap/disability. As a member of the policy setting Board of School Directors, it would be my responsibility to ensure those provisions are met for all students."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experiences as an African- American parent in the district, proven leadership and commitment to the community and over 20 years of experience in the pharmaceutical industry make me qualified to perform the duties of a school board director.  I bring with me a diverse strategic and tactical background in advocacy, leadership, collaboration, policy/procedure development, financial management, project management and process improvement."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issues our district is facing are addressing the dramatic slide in district rankings and ensuring that all students in the district have what they need to be successful, promoting a safe, inclusive and enriching environment for all students and encouraging community involvement and Board transparency. My plan of action would consist of: Conducting community-wide equity surveys which allows us to hear from all voices across the school district. Conducting routine quantitative and qualitative policy equity audits which ensures we are creating a sense of mental and physical safety for all. ​Supporting and empowering our educational professionals to do the jobs that they were hired to do. ","​Expanding and advancing our support, resources, academic programs and opportunities for the success of our students today and tomorrow. ​Facilitate a collaborative, responsive relationship with students, educators, administrators and the community.  Ensure fiscal astuteness and responsibility."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Our school district's responsibility is to ensure the health and safety of all of our students, educators, support staff and administrators and to minimize the districts' part in the spread of communicable diseases. The priority should be for all students, even our most vulnerable, to receive an in person education and for employees of the district to work in a safe environment. Our school district should be making decisions and ensuring that the health and safety plan align with the recommendations and advice of the governing health authorities and experts.  In doing so the district should have systems and measures in place to ensure an appropriate level of communication and awareness to the community. In addition within our schools and on buses the appropriate cleaning protocols, social distancing and measures for protection need to be in place.  There should be a robust process in place that allows for expert based and approved exemptions as needed.   "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The requirement to wear masks should be aligned with the recommendations of local, state and federal health agencies. There should be a robust process in place that allows for expert based and approved exemptions as needed.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The required vaccinations should be aligned with the recommendations of local, state and federal health agencies. There should be a robust process in place that allows for expert based and approved exemptions as needed.   "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["It is the responsibility of schools to care for and support all students to ensure their success.  Therefore being aware of and acknowledging the full breath of diversity that exists among your student population and the world that you are preparing them for is a must.  School districts should ensure that ALL students have the appropriate support and resources that they need to be successful, feel safe and included. School districts should ensure that all students are able to connect to what they are doing in the classroom and see themselves as a part of the school. School should have leaders that can speak to and lead work in this space.  Students should see diverse leaders within their schools that they can identify with and that can support them.  This not only helps those students, but it helps all students by exposing them to varying teaching styles and teaches them to work and communicate with people that are different from themselves. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Complete and factual history should be taught in schools. Perspectives across the vast spectrum of diversity should be part of the curriculum. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_adrienne_king","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["School districts should ensure that ALL students have the appropriate support and resources that they need to be successful, feel safe and included. School districts should ensure that all students are able to connect to what they are doing in the classroom and see themselves as a part of the school. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I believe that I listen well and ask good questions - two things our community needs right now."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe the top issue in our district is the current lack of willingness to engage the full spectrum of diversity that exists not only locally but around the world. My plan to ensure that there is a tiered, methodical approach to teaching about difference and learning how to have genuine discussion surrounding experiences of others. I believe that means hearing from and being led by a committee that is as diverse as is possible."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I think the district should trust trained medical professionals and should heed their advice. We still have much to learn about COVID but should, for the sake of those around us, bear the burdens it places on us together."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I teach at a school that requires everyone to wear a mask. It is not a problem for upwards of 85% of the students, and the 15% who struggle to remember are compliant without issue when asked to pull their masks up. For the sake of those that cannot afford medical care and those that are immunocompromised, I’m happy to wear a mask and ask people to do the same."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I’m not a medical professional and cannot speak to the medical reasons people should or shouldn’t get vaccinated. That said, my family and I trust the science behind vaccinations and defer to the medical professionals."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["There needs to be a committee that meets o a regular basis and creates a bank of resources to aid teachers in presenting the spectrum of the world around us."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["We should read from a diversity of voices on a regular basis. If that isn’t happening it needs to be."]},{"candidateCode":"pennridge_school_director_2-year_term_jeremiah_f._link","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I think students need to know and feel they are safe, so we should ask them what that would look like and move to make that a reality."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_john_b._lewis","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Elected in 2015, I have a proven track record of delivering on the issues of:","","* Increasing Open Space","","* Investing in Parks and Recreation","","​* Advocacy for Neighbors","","* Open Government","","* Public Safety","","* Infrastructure","","Check out https://www.john-b-lewis.com/accomplishments for more details on what I have accomplished for Lower Makefield residents.​"]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_john_b._lewis","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I strongly oppose the proposed sewer sale. The Board selected the lowest of the three bids and the winning bid was lower than the appraised value for the system.  Second, ratepayers often pay much higher rates when systems are sold to PUC regulated entities like Aqua.  And third, the board did not consider the needs of the community and ratepayers like you and me.  ","","That's why I am formally objecting to the sale with the PUC.  Please see the attached letter for more details.","","https://www.scribd.com/document/518327023/PUC-Letter-from-John-B-Lewis","",""]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_john_b._lewis","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Lower Makefield Township is a great place to locate a business.  We are uniquely positioned along the Northeast Corridor between Philadelphia and New York.  We have an elite workforce, a competitive cost of business and great transit options for commuting, air travel and freight.  ","","We recently welcomed Crown Holdings to Lower Makefield.  Crown Holdings is our first Fortune 500 company located in our community -- bringing approximately 250 jobs including their senior executive leadership.  Additionally, the Lower Makefield Corporate Center landed the U.S. Headquarters of Clinigen in 2016 and Cenlar in 2017.","","Supporting business growth means building on our strengths such as no earned income tax and improving infrastructure.  To that end, I have opposed all efforts to enact an EIT.  Additionally, I recently supported the liquor referendum which provided restaurants and grocery stores with the ability to obtain liquor licenses.  "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_john_b._lewis","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["1) Continue to invest in road repair: My advocacy of road repair is well known and Lower Makefield has aggressively increased investment in road repair from $565,139 in 2016 to $953,154 in 2020.","","2) Develop a long term solution to sewer conveyance and treatment that does not involve selling the conveyance system to Aqua.  We can work with neighboring municipalities to create a new sewer authority or Bucks County Water and Sewer Authority to better serve ratepayers over the long run.","","3) Increase Bike Path Network:  I have worked to secure a number of grants for bike paths.  We need to complete those projects and continue to look for ways to increase our network."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_john_b._lewis","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support the legalization of recreational use of cannabis by adults over the age of 21 and supported the following resolution at the Bucks County Association of Township Officials.","","https://www.bcato.org/media/1692/revised-bcato_2021_resolutions-multi-member-muni.pdf"]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_john_b._lewis","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, I support local ordinances to protect LGBTQ+ residents from discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity in employment, housing, and public accommodations.","","Neither Pennsylvania law nor federal statutes specifically prohibit discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity. However, federal courts and some federal agencies have recognized discrimination against LGBQ&T people as a form of gender or sex discrimination. Additionally, in August 2018, the Pennsylvania Human Relations Commission - the government agency that enforces the commonwealth's nondiscrimination law - announced that it accepts complaints of discrimination against LGBQ&T people in employment, housing, and public accommodations as a form of sex discrimination.",""]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_john_b._lewis","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am not certain that Municipalities can successfully enact general mask mandates under the Second-Class Township Code.  If empowered to do so, such general guidance would be better coming from the County of Bucks or the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.","","In general, I support mask mandates in Township-owned properties and I am open to the concept of requiring Township employees to be vaccinated with reasonable exceptions for immuno-compromised and a religious exception.  However, given that our employees interact with the public, it is also reasonable to require recurring testing for those who are unvaccinated.","","Having lost close friends to COVID, I have profound respect for the importance of public health efforts and challenge of evolving science around the pandemic."," "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_2_years_elen_snyder","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I love my town. The history, beauty and sense of community here is like no other. I look forward to getting Newtown on sound financial footing while also preserving the historic nature of our town. We must promote sustainable growth while protecting open space, managing building and zoning, and helping local businesses thrive. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_2_years_elen_snyder","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Climate change is the number one issue facing small towns and big cities alike. By managing open space, reducing energy consumption, and using alternative energy sources we can help insure our future. Planting trees and reducing single use plastics will help, while having a strong plan for green infrastructure in our building plans. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_2_years_elen_snyder","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We need to modify our zoning in portions of our township in order to attract new businesses since a limited amount of space is available to us."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_2_years_elen_snyder","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our roads are in dire need of repair. We are unable to keep up with the repair that is so desperately needed. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_2_years_elen_snyder","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am very much in support of the decriminalization of marijuana. The classification system that marijuana now resides in is false. We have seen medical marijuana used successfully to treat a number of ailments. With the taxation of marijuana we could see a lot of that money used  to booster our education system along with other needs. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_2_years_elen_snyder","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["All people are equal despite their race, sex or sexual orientation. I support any and all laws used to strengthen those ideas in the strongest possible manner. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_2_years_elen_snyder","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I absolutely support mask mandates especially in our schools to protect our children. We should follow the CDC guidelines at all times. I trust the science."]},{"candidateCode":"bedminster_township_supervisor_morgan_cowperthwaite_jr.","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Experience in all areas of the township government"]},{"candidateCode":"bedminster_township_supervisor_morgan_cowperthwaite_jr.","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Adequate police and EMS support.  Provide additional funding to fire companies and EMS in this COVID-19 pandemic"]},{"candidateCode":"bedminster_township_supervisor_morgan_cowperthwaite_jr.","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["By granting incentives to those businesses that apply"]},{"candidateCode":"bedminster_township_supervisor_morgan_cowperthwaite_jr.","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Paving township roads and repairing township bridges.  "]},{"candidateCode":"bedminster_township_supervisor_morgan_cowperthwaite_jr.","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"bedminster_township_supervisor_morgan_cowperthwaite_jr.","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"bedminster_township_supervisor_morgan_cowperthwaite_jr.","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_barbara_n._lyons","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have served  Doylestown Township over the last 20 years and helped lead it into an award winning municipality noted for fiscal responsibility, inter - government cooperation, resident access to government, communication with its residents, excellence in police services, a responsive public works department, environmental stewardship, parks and recreation services for all ages and abilities, and a professional and responsible governing Board of Supervisors, who treat each other and the public with respect and grace. I have the skill, ability, stamina  and experience to continue this tradition  of excellence by continuing to serve the public as Supervisor."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_barbara_n._lyons","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["There are more than one, and not necessarily in this order of priority. We need to build a parks and recreation community center providing for the needs of our community balanced with our commitment to provide 100% clean energy by 2050. We will be facing a challenge with our volunteer fire and emergency services  organizations which are having difficulties sustaining these services without more community and governmental support. We have aging infra-structure that needs attention and together with the myriad of the township services we provide, we need to approach all these concerns with fiscal responsibility."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_barbara_n._lyons","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Doylestown Township welcomes business and commercial projects that seek to best serve the needs of our residents, meet our zoning ordinances and enhance the aesthetics of our community. Our staff meets regularly with individuals and businesses with proposals  for  potential developments and redevelopments and recommends where appropriate, review by our Planning Commission and professional staff. We encourage business and private partnerships at every opportunity -- which is how for example, we were able to build 30 miles of trails over the last 20 years. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_barbara_n._lyons","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Regarding our aging infrastructure, we have developed a roads program which prioritizes roads in need of attention and we have a similar program to address our bridges. In addition, we need to remain vigilant with our water supply by supporting the efforts of our Doylestown Township Municipal Authority to expand its infrastructure necessary to provide public water where needed; we need to maintain our septic management program and follow the science which will determine areas of the Township that may need sewer expansion and installation."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_barbara_n._lyons","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I serve as Chairman of the Board of Supervisors and Director of Public Safety for Doylestown Township. In these roles I work closely with the Chief of Police in law enforcement matters and would follow his recommendations on this issue. I cannot speak to what position the Board of Supervisors might take on this issue, but personally, I support decriminalization."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_barbara_n._lyons","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In Doylestown Township government we are open to any and all opportunities and programs that support inclusion and protection for the LGBTQ+ Communities."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_barbara_n._lyons","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. We continue to mandate mask wearing in and among Doylestown Township Administration."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_tom_tosti","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have served on the Board of Supervisors in Middletown for the last 5 1/2 years. Two of those years I have been the Chair of the Board. We have faced different issues in our Township over this time and I feel as though I along with others on the Board have been up for the challenge. I understand Government and know it cannot be ran the same way a business does. We deal with the public which has a lot to do with your success if you can relate to and understand their concerns. We are still in the middle of a pandemic and we as a Board and a Township did very well in managing our residents, staff and our finances during some very difficult times. We lost over 3 million dollars in revenue last year and still we're able to balance a budget without having to consider raising any taxes. We have had no tax increase during my term on the Board and our Township have earned a triple A bond rating the last 2 years. "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_tom_tosti","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Sustainability. Are Township is running real well. We have a top notch Police Department, our Public Works Dept. does an outstanding job, Park and Rec., our staff in L&I and all of our departments work hard for the residents of our Township. We have to be able to sustain the services we provide at the level we provide it, so our residents know we are working for them. We also have the pandemic that won't go away. We will continue to support the small businesses by pushing for residents to buy local. Our local small businesses live and work here and we have to make sure they don't falter. Finally, we need to continue to support our youth. The new skatepark, revitalizing our fields and parks are issue we need to continue to support so our youth have a place to go and play. We will continue to revitalize these areas so our youth will have a place to go with things to do. "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_tom_tosti","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["This past year and a half was something that none of us have ever faced and had to deal with. Our small businesses and businesses throughout the township struggled to survive. We put a committee together of residents, business owners and staff to gather ideas that could help them thrive and get thru the pandemic. We passed an ordinance to allow for outdoor dining in areas of the Township that never had it, we posted every business in the Township on our website and encouraged resident to support them. As we moved forward we will continue to make Middletown a Township a place where businesses want to come and grow. "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_tom_tosti","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our roads and walking paths are 2 of the biggest projects we do each year. We will continue to repave 5 miles of roads each year and with the new walking bridges in the Gates it helps for pedestrian traffic. We have also have made the walking paths at Community Park longer and  go to Core Creek Park. We are looking to turn the Township Bldg. to solar energy which will reduce cost for the Township over the year. We will apply for grants to help secure money which should off set the cost of the project. "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_tom_tosti","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. I would want to work with our Police Dept. on how to handle it in way that works for all parties. Our Police would be the ones who would have to handle this so their input would be vital in making it work. "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_tom_tosti","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. We created a Human Relations Committee (HRC) the past year to look at all inequalitiies in the Township. We had a proclamation for Gay Pride month last year and this year in June and flew the LGBTQ flag for the month of June for the first time. "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_tom_tosti","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support wearing a mask if need be. As a member of the Board of Supervisors we do not have the authority to mandate wearing a mask. Restrictions, I would not want to see us go back to where we were. We need to get vaccinated so we can get out of this pandemic. The vaccine is safe and the whole issue became too political. This is a health crisis and we should listen to the scientist and our doctors and not politicians. "]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_jeff_dence","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am passionate about our local community and committed to driving Falls forward. In my 12 years on the board, I have championed numerous efforts aimed at bolstering our local economy. I understand the importance of a strong economy and have rolled up my sleeves to push for progress in Falls. During my tenure, our board has approved more than 70 land development plans. Many of those, including the massive NorthPoint redevelopment of the former U.S. Steel site, have resulted in countless new local jobs. Under my leadership as chairman the last two years, our board has banned smoking on township-owned property and worked with PennDOT to enable our public works department to remove litter from state-owned roads. I also supported measures to prohibit smoking near playgrounds and sports fields, as well as a measure to allow residents to add their properties to a no soliciting registry. Falls has been my home for more than 20 years. I want to make it the best home possible for all residents."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_jeff_dence","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Economic development and helping our local businesses recover from the COVID-19 pandemic are the top issues. I will continue working collaboratively with developers interested in doing business in and creating new jobs in Falls as I have throughout my board tenure. My role is two-fold in that I strive to have businesses feel welcome in Falls, but never at the expense of our residents or their quality of life. I will continue working to balance our residents’ needs with the objectives of incoming businesses. To help our small business community – particularly post-pandemic – the Supervisors are preparing to launch the Falls Township Jumpstart Program in 2022. As part of that effort, business owners, entrepreneurs and solopreneurs can lease a portion of the available 9,000 square feet of space at the municipal building. Based on their needs, businesses could rent a desk, a full office, or an office suite, while sharing amenities including a receptionist, IT support and conference space."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_jeff_dence","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will continue working collaboratively to strategize and create out-of-the-box approaches to growing business while keeping residents’ best interests in mind. A good and recent example is the NorthPoint redevelopment project. Seeing thousands of new jobs come to the all-but closed U.S. Steel site is a dream come true. I, along with the rest of our board worked hard to make this vision a reality. Our board approved a Keystone Opportunity Investment Zone designation for NorthPoint, which waives taxes for the developer through Dec. 31, 2035. Instead, NorthPoint – as part of our negotiation – agreed to a payment in lieu of tax arrangement which calls for the company to pay 110 percent of the taxes owed to the three taxing authorities each year (Falls Township, Pennsbury School District and Bucks County). In return, Falls Township will benefit from a remediated site, new industry and an estimated 5,000 to 10,000 new jobs at that site alone."," "]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_jeff_dence","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The major infrastructure issues I see in Falls Township are centered on state-owned roads, which our governing body has no control of. Falls has identified a few smaller road projects in need of repair. Our engineers are already working on those projects. The Falls Supervisors have remained proactive in maintaining our locally owned infrastructure. Each year, the township budgets for and undertakes full-depth reconstruction, milling and paving of at least one township-owned roadway. Beyond that, our board has applied for and received grant funding from PennDOT and other agencies to help cover the expense of major improvements on roadways, including traffic signal improvements and upgrading traffic lights with adaptive signalization at 23 busy intersections."," "]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_jeff_dence","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support efforts to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties for several reasons. First, if someone is struggling with drug addiction, they may be more likely to seek treatment if the fear of serving time in prison is removed from the equation. According to Partnership to End Addiction, one in every 10 Americans aged 12 and over – or 23.5 million Americans – are addicted to drugs and/or alcohol. Of those, the organization estimates that only 11 percent receive treatment. Any measure we can implement to help remove obstacles associated with receiving drug treatment is worth championing."," 92 percent of marijuana arrests were for marijuana possession alone, meaning there were more arrests for marijuana possession annually than for all violent crimes combined. While possession of marijuana could be considered trivial as compared to violent crimes, both offenses can cause irreparable damage."," "]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_jeff_dence","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I fully support the LGBTQ+ community. That said, protections for marginalized groups such as the LGBTQ+ community have no teeth on the local level. The Falls Township Supervisors have no authority to impose binding ordinances related to the LGBTQ+ community. Adopting such protections is the role of our federal government."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_jeff_dence","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Falls Township has not and does not mandate mask wearing or other COVID-19 restrictions on its own. Instead, the township looks to the Bucks County Health Department and the Centers for Disease Control for guidance on implementing mitigation efforts. If our county mandates the wearing of masks or implements other restrictions, I would support it as I have in various instances over the past year and a half. I want my community and our residents to remain healthy and safe. If our county officials determine that wearing a mask or undertaking other safety precautions will help us move in that direction, how can I not get behind it?"," "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_brendan_peppard","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["The current Board of Supervisors is made up of a group of well intentioned people who are all one party. This has resulted in poor decision making, or \"bad choices” as my young son used to call it, in many cases. I have spent my career working in and with state and local governments and have an understanding of the way to effectively get things done for our community. My wife and I moved to Lower Makefield 12 years ago and fell in love with the community. We want to ensure that it remains the kind of place people can raise their families and be proud of. My experience in government can best serve our community."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_brendan_peppard","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["While we have a beautiful community, our current Board of Supervisors has neglected to appropriately prioritize our needs. The roads throughout the Township are in desperate need of repaving, and we need a check on the poor decision-making of the current Board. I can provide that balancing voice for the Township and effectively advocate for policies that will continue to improve our community."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_brendan_peppard","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["In addition to working in government, I have also spent much of my career in the private sector. It is important that the Township have clear and easy to follow rules for opening and operating a business. They should be consistent and not subject to changes on a whim. The rules should be updated if there are problems in the market and should be designed to ensure that businesses and their customers are treated fairly."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_brendan_peppard","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our Township roads have been allowed to deteriorate to an embarrassing degree. It is vital that road repaving and maintenance be prioritized by the next Board. It is also important for the Board to ensure that we are meeting our maintenance responsibilities on the properties owned by the Township."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_brendan_peppard","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Marijuana is still categorized as a Schedule I drug at the federal level under the Controlled Substances Act. While many states have moved to legalize marijuana in some capacity, before our Township takes such an action we should carefully consider all of the implications."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_brendan_peppard","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I believe that everyone deserves respect. Government should ensure that inappropriate discrimination does not occur and ensure that the rules that are set establish an even playing field for everyone, within the boundaries of the United States and Pennsylvania Constitutions, and that no one receives an unfair advantage or disadvantage as a result of those rules."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_makefield_township_supervisor_brendan_peppard","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["We should continue to follow the science on this question. There are highly effective vaccines available for everyone over the age of 12, and we should be working to encourage those who have not yet decided to take advantage of the protections afforded by those vaccines to do so. Anything we do should be with an eye toward ensuring the safety of our community, and those most vulnerable among us."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_daniel_hilferty","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Experience.  I have been a supervisor for almost 12 years.  I have stood up to developers who challenged the township zoning and supported preservation of land when the opportunity arose.  I listen to residents, seeking their input on matters that impact the community.  I\"ve worked out solutions to difficult problems where all parties walked away with a workable solution.  I have a record of working to keep Plumstead Township's rural character and family friendly environment.  I continue to work to maintain the township's strong financial position while providing the services residents require."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_daniel_hilferty","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Plumstead Township is under development pressure.  While it is impossible to halt growth.  It is possible to work with landowners and those who wish to develop the land and create    plans consistent with the character of the township.  Preserving land when possible and working with the developer to reduce the impact of the development while creating a community environment."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_daniel_hilferty","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Plumstead Township works with the business owners as they bring forward their expansion plans or new business plans.  Working within the existing zoning ordinances the township professional and board of supervisors help integrate the propose plan into the community. "]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_daniel_hilferty","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Plumstead Township has about 69 miles of roads to maintain.  While Public Works has done a great job of keeping up with these road, there are new tools available to assist them in this effort.  Plumstead Township is in the process of implementing these tools which will allow for better management of repair and replacement."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_daniel_hilferty","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["At the Township level supervisors do not make law concerning the use of substances.  Such matters are controlled at the state and federal level."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_daniel_hilferty","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In my professional life I have always been employed in organizations that have respect for the individual.  I have continued this practice in my role as supervisor.   Individual rights are protected under state and federal law."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_daniel_hilferty","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["The Plumstead Township board of supervisors follows the guidelines set down by county and state authorities. The authority for disease control and prevention lies with the county and state governments.  "]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_blake_h._eisenhart","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a long time 40+ year resident of the township and a formerly elected township supervisor, I bring invaluable accumulated knowledge about township government, township resident concerns and township priorities as well as my professional and corporate background and experiences to bring thoughtful, collaborative bi-partisan leadership and common sense to our township’s needs and priorities.  My experience as a CPA, my financial acumen and integrity will ensure strong financial oversight of taxpayer dollars and township expenditures and my commitment to maintain our township's rural character."]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_blake_h._eisenhart","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The most pressing issues facing our township residents are the health/safety risks from the local Quarry operations and the corresponding deterioration of our township air and water quality.   Our fellow residents have banded together to lead citizen efforts to convince state authorities to cease quarry operations.  The township must take all necessary actions by partnering with county, state and federal representatives to obtain a cease and desist order.  The major risk, however, is that future state officials will change DEP quarry permitting rules which could allow the quarry to reopen.  Our township supervisors must continue to champion a long-term solution by marshaling financial resources and expertise, which I will bring, with our county, state and federal partners to close the quarry permanently - and ideally structure a transfer of the quarry property to the adjacent state game lands."]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_blake_h._eisenhart","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["East Rockhill is a rural residential community with existing business corridors on Route 313 and adjacent with Perkasie.  Township government has a responsibility to ensure that zoning and commercial ordinances are fair and reasonable while also being consistent with resident priorities of maintaining our rural character and preserving clean air and water.  Property rights must always be respected, and township government must prioritize supporting both our residential and business communities and minimize the burdens of bureaucratic requirements and fees. "]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_blake_h._eisenhart","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The most significant and pressing resident concerns related to infrastructure are that all roads, bridges and flood-mitigation structures should be well-designed, regularly monitored for resident, pedestrian and driver safety, and proactively maintained.  While the township road and maintenance crews are friendly, responsive and perform their duties well, I strongly believe the responsibility of township supervisors is to provide the financial resources to maintain these infrastructure expectations.  I will apply my financial management, auditing and accounting skills and experience to ensure that township resources will meet the infrastructure demands of our township residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_blake_h._eisenhart","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The Township Supervisors must always minimize regulations, ordinances or impositions on township residents and taxpayers.  Marijuana and possession/use legality, criminal laws, regulations and penalties are within federal and state jurisdictions.  The township’s government sole burden is only to ensure the safety of all township residents and taxpayers.  Township government has no business interfering in the private lives of residents on their own property who do not disturb or impair the safety of their neighbors or fellow residents."]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_blake_h._eisenhart","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Bucks County, including our East Rockhill Township community, has been recognized for our acceptance and respect of the character and personal choices of our residents, neighbors and friends who identify as LGBTQ+.  Those who self-identify as LGBTQ+ are welcomed within our neighborhoods, been elected to public office, and invited to serve in our various religious, business and social organizations.   East Rockhill is a small residential township which has neither the need, the expertise nor the resources to maintain the bureaucracy accompanying such ordinances, particularly since East Rockhill residents value the contributions of our residents, friends and neighbors who identify as LGBTQ+.   The protection of the constitutional rights of our residents, friends and neighbors who experience bias based on race, religion, ethnicity, nationality, gender, and sexual orientation and identity, known as HATE crimes, is and rightly should be the responsibility of state law enforcement."]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_blake_h._eisenhart","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I strongly affirm and believe that the least government is the best government, and that any decisions impacting individuals/people is best determined at the local government level.   At this time in Pennsylvania, a mask mandate can only be declared based upon a state of emergency and defined under state law.  The township is not permitted to declare state of emergencies or mask mandates under our state constitution"]},{"candidateCode":"west_rockhill_township_supervisor_james_e._miller_jr.","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My focus has been on transparency and making changes that will improve the lives of our residents.   Actions already taken include installing a video system to record our meetings and make them available for everyone to view on our website. Adding the monthly list of expenses to the website so everyone knows how their tax dollars are being spent.  Moving our Tax Collector’s office to the front of the Admin Building for security and ease of access.  Addition of the Compassionate Friends Garden in James Park.  Continued expansion of our park system.  Renovations to our 50 year old Holiday House Pool.  Working with PennDot and Representative Staats on upgrades to Finland Road that eliminated weekly accidents.  ","There is still a lot more to do and I am asking you to allow me to continue.",""]},{"candidateCode":"west_rockhill_township_supervisor_james_e._miller_jr.","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We need to take actions now that will safeguard our future.  West Rockhill has the lowest tax rate of any municipality in Bucks County with their own Police Dept.  I’ve already taken actions to prevent tax increases.  The elimination of taxpayer funded health insurance for Supervisors and their families is saving approximately $145,000 annually.  The renegotiation of loans for the Police Dept. building and Open Space Fund has cut long term debt by $300,000 and the installation of solar power had eliminated approximately $375,000 of electrical expenses over the life of the system.  An energy audit followed by building upgrades has further reduced expenses, I have a plan that will allow us to safely and systematically continue lowering expenses and redirecting these tax dollars back into the community without increasing the tax base for many years. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_rockhill_township_supervisor_james_e._miller_jr.","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will continue to support our local businesses by using their services.  My first priority is to use a business in our township and/or a business owner who lives in our township.  I follow up on social media and by word of mouth about these businesses.  My goal is to show our township and the surrounding area the benefits of shopping local."]},{"candidateCode":"west_rockhill_township_supervisor_james_e._miller_jr.","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Roads are always our number one issue.  With the reduction in expenses that I have been pushing for several years, we have been able to put more of an emphasis on road repair and resurfacing.  This year we invested $500,000 into the infrastructure.  The largest amount we've ever been able to allocate."]},{"candidateCode":"west_rockhill_township_supervisor_james_e._miller_jr.","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As an elected official I take an oath to follow the laws that are passed down from our Federal, State and County officials.  I will continue to do that.  My personal opinion has no bearing in the matter."]},{"candidateCode":"west_rockhill_township_supervisor_james_e._miller_jr.","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["As an elected official I take an oath to follow the laws that are passed down from our Federal, State and County officials.  I will continue to do that.  My personal opinion has no bearing in the matter."]},{"candidateCode":"west_rockhill_township_supervisor_james_e._miller_jr.","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["As an elected official I take an oath to follow the laws that are passed down from our Federal, State and County officials.  I will continue to do that.  My personal opinion has no bearing in the matter."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_john_palmer","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I live and work in Falls Township and care deeply about my community and our residents. Prior to joining the Falls Township Board of Supervisors in 2020, I served for 11 years on the Pennsbury School Board. I also volunteered as a firefighter and later Captain, with Levittown Fire Company No. 1. For the last 16 years, I have served in various head coaching positions in sports, including boy’s and girls’ basketball, baseball, and football. My community involvement outside elected office gives me insight for the work I do as a Supervisor. It provides me with invaluable time to talk one-on-one with residents about concerns they have and address them with the rest of the board. In all that I do, I strive to embody local government at work. I view my Falls Township Supervisor tasks through the lens of a resident and analyze how every land development, every ordinance and everything that we do as a board could impact our fellow residents. I will continue to follow that approach if elected."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_john_palmer","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Economic development and helping our local businesses recover from the COVID-19 pandemic are the top issues. I will continue working collaboratively with developers interested in doing business in and creating new jobs in Falls as I have throughout my board tenure. My role is two-fold in that I strive to have businesses feel welcome in Falls, but never at the expense of our residents or their quality of life. I will continue working to balance our residents’ needs with the objectives of incoming businesses. To help our small business community – particularly post-pandemic – the Supervisors are preparing to launch the Falls Township Jumpstart Program in 2022. As part of that effort, business owners, entrepreneurs and solopreneurs can lease a portion of the available 9,000 square feet of space at the municipal building. Based on their needs, businesses could rent a desk, a full office, or an office suite, while sharing amenities including a receptionist, IT support and conference space."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_john_palmer","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will continue working collaboratively to strategize and create out-of-the-box approaches to growing business while keeping residents’ best interests in mind. A good and recent example is the NorthPoint redevelopment project. Seeing thousands of new jobs come to the all-but closed U.S. Steel site is a dream come true. I, along with the rest of our board worked hard to make this vision a reality. Our board approved a Keystone Opportunity Investment Zone designation for NorthPoint, which waives taxes for the developer through Dec. 31, 2035. Instead, NorthPoint – as part of our negotiation – agreed to a payment in lieu of tax arrangement which calls for the company to pay 110 percent of the taxes owed to the three taxing authorities each year (Falls Township, Pennsbury School District and Bucks County). In return, Falls Township will benefit from a remediated site, new industry and an estimated 5,000 to 10,000 new jobs at that site alone."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_john_palmer","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The major infrastructure issues I see in Falls Township are centered on state-owned roads, which our governing body has no control of. Falls has identified a few smaller road projects in need of repair. Our engineers are already working on those projects. The Falls Supervisors have remained proactive in maintaining our locally owned infrastructure. Each year, the township budgets for and undertakes full-depth reconstruction, milling and paving of at least one township-owned roadway. Beyond that, our board has applied for and received grant funding from PennDOT and other agencies to help cover the expense of major improvements on roadways, including traffic signal improvements and upgrading traffic lights with adaptive signalization at 23 busy intersections."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_john_palmer","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support efforts to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties. If someone is struggling with addiction, they may be more likely to seek treatment if the fear of serving prison time is removed from the equation. According to Partnership to End Addiction, 1 in every 10 Americans aged 12 and over – or 23.5 million Americans – are addicted to drugs and/or alcohol. Of those, the organization estimates that 11 percent receive treatment. Any measure we can implement to help remove obstacles associated with receiving drug treatment is worth championing. That is why Falls Township launched a Supporting Recovery effort this year. Falls was the first municipality to implement this co-responder model which pairs a certified recovery specialist with police to assist with overdoes and substance abuse calls. Since it began in February, 1/3 of substance abuse calls have led to treatment. Also, as a school board member, I served on the Mental Health/Opioid Taskforce, “Pennsbury Committed to Life.”"]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_john_palmer","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I fully support the LGBTQ+ community. That said, protections for marginalized groups such as the LGBTQ+ community have no teeth on the local level. The Falls Township Supervisors have no authority to impose binding ordinances related to the LGBTQ+ community. Adopting such protections is the role of our federal government."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_john_palmer","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Falls Township has not and does not mandate mask wearing or other COVID-19 restrictions on its own. Instead, the township looks to the Bucks County Health Department and the Centers for Disease Control for guidance on implementing mitigation efforts. If our county mandates the wearing of masks or implements other restrictions, I would support it as I have in various instances over the past year and a half. I want my community and our residents to remain healthy and safe. If our county officials determine that wearing a mask or undertaking other safety precautions will help us move in that direction, how can I not get behind it?"]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_victor_corsino","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the only candidate that would actually be representing the diversity of our community."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_victor_corsino","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The loss of tax revenue due to Covid-19. I will use my business background to revamp and balance our budget."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_victor_corsino","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will support our local business buy including them in the process, all local businesses will be listed on our website and will be featured at our meetings and activities though a random system."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_victor_corsino","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We need to increase our stormwater management program so that our roads remain safe in inclement weather."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_victor_corsino","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["No. I have young children and I will not be a hypocrite. "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_victor_corsino","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. One of the first things we can do is recognize Nondiscrimination Protections for all county employes and on all public grounds."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_victor_corsino","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. Because all workers deserve a save work environment, our country has always been on the forefront of worker safety and now is not the time to stop."]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_kevin_m._morrissey","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As one of the current Supervisors, I was the lead or a key player in all of the following projects that added significantly to the quality of life in Solebury.","","•        The New Hope Crushed Stone quarry discontinued operations. ","•        I helped create the Solebury Farm committee, which protects agricultural land and supports and strengthens our farming economy.","•        I was the conduit between the Supervisors and other committees, including Parks and Recreation, the Planning Commission, and the Environmental Advisory Council. ","•        I worked with the other Supervisors to provide access to 24-hour emergency care; as well as to continue the land  preservation program.","","My corporate background, including an MBA in Finance, has led me to advocate for a balanced and conservative budget.  The strong financial condition of the Township is a product of my working together with the other Supervisors who believe as I do.",""]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_kevin_m._morrissey","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["","Financial stability of the Township is the top priority facing the municipality.  The strong financial condition of Solebury Township has been the major tool to develop numerous improvements to the quality of life in the community while keeping Solebury Township millage rates at the current low level.","","I will continue to support a conservative budgeting process.",""]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_kevin_m._morrissey","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will continue to poll and  follow the community consensus as to the appropriate level of business growth in the community."]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_kevin_m._morrissey","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["It is critical to manage the population of the significantly growing deer herd which has developed to adversely affect many aspects of community life.  I support the current plans to reduce the herd in as financially responsible as possible. "," ",""]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_kevin_m._morrissey","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["","This issue is determined at a higher government level than the Township municipality.",""]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_kevin_m._morrissey","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Currently, our Township have  rules of conduct  in place to respect the rights of all individuals, regardless of differentiating features.  Additionally, I believe it is important to review these procedures to ensure that they are being observed as well as determine opportunities to improve them."]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_kevin_m._morrissey","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["The COVID pandemic is a serious attack on our society reducing every aspect of our lives, killing many of us of all ages.  We have been continually been advised by scientific experts that wearing masks assists with fighting this virus. While wearing a mask is not a panacea, I believe it should be considered part of the set of  tools we are developing toward getting us back to the life that we had.  ","","Currently, Solebury Township has a mask wearing regulation relating to municipal functions.","","Unfortunately I believe we need to consider other restrictions if a mask regulation or participation in this regulation is not effective.   ",""]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_colleen_mullin","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["","I place a high priority on clear and transparent communication with ALL residents of the Township, not just a select few.  Good communication includes not only providing information, but also listening, acknowledging, and being open to change.  I don't believe in simply \"doing what we do because that's how we've always done it\".","I have been a volunteer for the Township Ways and Means and Pension Committee for the past few years, which has provided me with a clear understanding of the Township's taxation, budgeting and capital spending needs, and I look forward to taking that to the next level as an elected official.  I can hit the ground running, as I am well informed of our fiscal priorities. ","As a wife and a mother, and in my professional career where I hold a fiduciary designation, I continually put others' needs ahead of my own.  A critical trait of an effective elected official is putting residents' best interests first, which is what I am committed to doing at all times. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_colleen_mullin","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["While there are many issues we are facing, I believe the top issue all of humanity is facing is our changing climate.  The Township can take a leadership role in addressing how we approach energy consumption in all operations. Residents can personally invest in alternative energy sources for their homes, or choose to take simple actions such as composting organic waste - the Township can get creative by incentivizing and supporting residents in making those choices.   Collectively we can have a big impact, even by making small changes.  Right now there are plans to build a new Community Center for Doylestown Township.  We should prioritize the use of sustainable materials and methods, so that the impact on the community goes beyond simply creating a physical space.  Such a project should have a lasting impact that contributes to the health of our residents AND our environment at the same time.  We need a Board of Supervisors who are motivated to lead our residents in that direction."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_colleen_mullin","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We are fortunate to have a diverse mix of businesses in the Township, from small home-based companies, to mid-sized closely held companies, to large corporations and national and international publicly held companies.  Helping local businesses succeed and grow is a priority, especially as we begin to get back to work during a pandemic.  I look forward to supporting business owners and their employees by keeping taxes low and providing top-notch services and infrastructure.  It's incumbent upon the Township to attract loyal customers to our area, so they in turn can take advantage of the many shopping, dining and retail experiences available, and benefit from the myriad of services our businesses have to offer.  I am always happy when I can make connections between businesses as well, so they can network and collaborate to fuel each others' success!"]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_colleen_mullin","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["While our budget has many competing priorities, the top of the list includes paving and road improvements, and am glad to see a more formal plan being put in place by Township staff this year.  I will continue to support those efforts.  ","I currently serve on a subcommittee that includes Bucks County Water and Sewer Authority, Doylestown Township, and my own neighbors.  We are in the midst of installation of public water and sewers.  Ours is the first of three planned phases to be undergoing this kind of infrastructure upgrade in the Township.  In these cases, homeowners take on the public and private cost of tapping into the new systems.  It is my belief that the Township could better support residents by putting more effort toward seeking grants and other funding resources, and possibly in the way we manage and and negotiate construction contracts. ","I am committed to investing in infrastructure that will see Doylestown Township thrive and grow well into the 21st century."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_colleen_mullin","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The legality surrounding cannabis use should be addressed at the Federal and State level, before it can be effectively addressed at the local level.  At the very least, our Federal government (through the DEA) should remove cannabis from its classification as a Schedule 1 substance, as it has been proven to have medical benefits for many.  There is enough data and experience from other \"recreationally legal\" states that the PA legislature can consider, in order to take a serious, unbiased and balanced approach to the legalization of cannabis for recreational use.  Locally, I would consider decriminalizing cannabis for small amounts of possession, but only after first consulting with our Police, Solicitor and Social Service agencies.  I would need to ascertain what, if any, measures we COULD consider, and weigh the positive and negative impacts to our residents and staff.  Finally, I would require resident input before making any decision on such an important topic. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_colleen_mullin","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely.  I believe all people, regardless of sexual orientation, gender identity, or gender expression, should be protected by their local government, so they can be free to pursue the lifestyle they desire without having to battle against discrimination, and without having to live in fear.  I will ensure these protections are strong and explicit on behalf of all of our residents.  I also strongly support the efforts of the Rainbow Room locally, who have proven to be an invaluable resource for our LGBTQ+ youth."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_township_supervisor_colleen_mullin","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes.  Masks help stop the spread of COVID. "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_charles_mccarthy","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I proudly describe myself as a political outsider.  This carries the privilege of only being beholden to the people of LOSO.  I am running to give a voice to everyone, while having the honor of giving back to my community.  I promise to bring a fresh way of thinking that includes the entire community, that I will shed light on the process of governing."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_charles_mccarthy","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["In listening to people, the top issues include getting a fresh voice on the Board and exploring new ideologies; this is the reason why I plan to start the process to bring term limits to all elected positions within LOSO.  Second, the on-going “garbage-gate” situation is prominent for many.  I am committed to having a thorough and very public investigation.  Finally, there is a great deal of mystery to many when it comes to understanding the daily financial operations of the Township.  I will work to bring a meaningful and EASY to understand explanation to all expenses and income township budget."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_charles_mccarthy","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Supporting business growth starts with understanding what the ongoing needs of our local businesses.  How can we make working with the Township easier?  What plans or ideas are being generated in our local business associations, and clubs that we can strengthen?  I want to explore success strategies from the Commonwealth and County but customize to our community."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_charles_mccarthy","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Instead of providing the standard answer based on street repair and traffic studies, I’ll tell you the simple truth…I am not well versed with infrastructure jargon.  I can promise you that I will listen to and ask questions of the experts while carrying the responsibility of always doing what is best for the people of LOSO."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_charles_mccarthy","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes.  Many of the penalties associated with this common every day vice are as dated as the prejudices associated with it.  "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_charles_mccarthy","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely.  One’s sexual orientation should never play a role as to how we treat one another as humans.  When we learn to accept, show respect, and love each other, we move closer to a community capable of great advancements."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_southampton_township_supervisor_charles_mccarthy","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["In a heartbeat.  The last eighteen months have shown that any step to beating the pandemic is a responsibility that we all own.  What some may see as an unpopular decision today – I see as a solution to making a safer and healthier tomorrow."]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_robert_j._salzer","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My years of working for Bucks County as an Assistant District Attorney, my legal background and and my knowledge of issues affecting the quality of life in our Township based upon discussions with those who currently oversee it. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_robert_j._salzer","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I am happy to say that I do not believe there is a specific \"top issue\" facing Northampton Township. I want to ensure that the Township continues to be run in a fiscally responsible and safe manner for all residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_robert_j._salzer","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["By making fair and fully informed decisions related to any matters brought before the Board of Supervisors affecting not only prospective businesses, but those already located within the Township. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_robert_j._salzer","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The most common infrastructure needs relate to road maintenance and repair. I think most residents would agree that our public works department clears snow better than any surrounding municipalities. It is important to continue that tradition, while demonstrating the same efficiency in repairing damage wrought by various weather events. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_robert_j._salzer","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["My municipality does not legislate, and it is not for me to decide which laws should be followed and which should not be followed. I have to respect all laws of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, independent of my personal opinions. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_robert_j._salzer","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support equal protection for all citizens of Northampton Township, Bucks County, the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and the United States of America."]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_robert_j._salzer","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support our citizens maintaining the freedom to decide what is best for themselves and their families. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_john_c_bishop","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Good governance is the purpose and by-product of community-minded leadership - leadership which embodies responsibility and accountability. As supervisor, it is my goal to be the community-minded leader that our township deserves. A Northampton Township resident since 1994, I have served in various coaching and other capacities in support of local sports organizations. I have also served on community boards sponsored by the township - as an inaugural member of the Northampton Township Wall of Honor Committee and am currently serving on the Northampton Township Parks and Recreation Board. As a life-long educator, I have been actively involved in all aspects of the school community and have demonstrated the listening, learning, and leadership skills required to successfully serve the needs of various constituencies. My running mate, Crissy Richardson, and I are honored to have the opportunity to bring our experiences and community spirit to serve the residents of Northampton Township."]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_john_c_bishop","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We must provide greater care and oversight of the commercial space in our township. As commercial businesses provide for both the financial health of the township and vital services for the community, we will work with the township administration to continually review our community planning and zoning ordinances – removing or revising those that are outdated or ambiguous."]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_john_c_bishop","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We must continue and enhance our outreach and collaboration with local and county organizations – including the Northampton Township Business & Professional Association and the Bucks County Economic Development Corporation – to promote effective business and economic development in our township. We will also work with the township administration, school district, and county agencies to explore the reenactment of the Northampton LERTA Program, promoting tax abatement for new business construction and improvements to aging or deteriorating properties."]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_john_c_bishop","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We will continue to work with PennDOT and our township administration to create safer road and bridge configurations, reduce traffic congestion, and accelerate the repair and repaving of township roadways and transportation surfaces. We will also work to protect and enhance our community by ensuring our police, fire, EMS, and parks and recreation personnel have the facilities, tools and training they need."]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_john_c_bishop","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_john_c_bishop","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["A welcoming community - like ours - is achieved and maintained by an involved and caring citizenry. Such a community recognizes and respects the responsibilities we have to each other; to create and maintain peace and prosperity while providing all residents with the ability to contribute to the community and raise their families. As community leaders, we will foster the ideals of our welcoming community by supporting all our residents and protecting them from discrimination in any form."]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_john_c_bishop","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["The health and safety of our township employees, families and residents is paramount. The Board of Supervisors and the township administration is responsible for providing a safe environment in all township facilities and spaces. As community leaders, we will fulfill this responsibility, and data will drive our decision-making process."]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_jim_nietupski","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Having lived in East Rockhill Township for over 25 years on a 65+ year old family farm, I have a passion for this community and a genuine interest in the welfare and quality of life for all the residents.   My past performance and twelve-year experience as a supervisor, my approachability, and background as a Penn State mechanical engineer makes me the best qualified candidate to continue as the supervisor.   I have consistently been an advocate for the residents and will continue keeping an open mind and treat every resident equally and fairly.   I will continue listening to residents, practice full transparency and proactively notify residents when their property may be affected by a potential township initiative. I will continue balancing the needs of the township while looking out for the needs of the individual residents.  "]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_jim_nietupski","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The most important issue facing East Rockhill Township is protecting our residents.   I will continue supporting and fully funding the Pennridge Regional Police and continue opposing the quarry operations that threaten the health, welfare and safety of our residents (all residents, not just those living in the vicinity of the quarry).  "]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_jim_nietupski","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Balanced Economic Development is needed to keep the township financially viable and to avoid increasing taxes.  Economic development should have equal priority with land preservation.  When first elected, I proposed an Economic Development Advisory Committee to promote community supported economic development.  That proposal was ignored by the majority of the board at that time and still goes ignored by the majority of the current board today.    I will continue to promote and support balanced economic development.  Regrettably, economic development is not addressed in the recent 2020 Comprehensive Plan (that I voted against)."]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_jim_nietupski","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Traditional “infrastructure” in East Rockhill is relatively good due to an ongoing five-year road plan that is updated on an annual basis.  The “flooding bridge” on Stone Edge Road and traffic calming on Old Bethlehem Pike need attention.  At the August 2021 Supervisor’s meeting, a commitment was made by the board to compile the history and review options for improving the “flooding bridge”.  A traffic circle is being designed for the intersection of Three Mile Run Road and Old Bethlehem Pike as the best option allowed by PENN DOT for traffic calming."]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_jim_nietupski","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Decriminalizing or loosening penalties for marijuana is not and will likely never be a municipal level matter.  Enforcement of laws governing marijuana however, falls upon our municipality through Pennridge Regional Police.    I support upholding any state level decisions regarding marijuana.  If asked, I’d be amenable to having a conversation with our state officials to debate the science and the pros and cons of legalizing marijuana or the penalties.  "]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_jim_nietupski","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["LGBTQ+ (as well as any other group) are entitled to the same equal rights and protections under the law as everyone else – no more and no less.  Discrimination, tormenting, and abuse of any group or individual is unacceptable.   No group should expect or receive any special treatment because of their race, color, nationality, sexual orientation, or religious beliefs.   All people are afforded the same protection and rights under the law, and any lawbreakers should be prosecuted to the full extent of the law.    "]},{"candidateCode":"east_rockhill_township_supervisor_jim_nietupski","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe in personal freedoms and parental rights as well as following the law.  At the municipal level, I support following any legally binding mandate from our governor regarding the wearing of masks.   There continues to be an enormous amount of conflicting data and “expert opinions” arguing both the pros and cons of wearing masks as well as to vaccinated vs. unvaccinated.   Heath care is an individual decision.  No one has the right to impose their views and positions onto anyone else – including a supervisor.   However, if the situation presented itself, I would be willing to consider a mask mandate only after careful evaluation of the circumstances at that time."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_bernadette_hannah","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the best candidate for Supervisor, because I believe in Middletown families and our community. We have amazing families and citizens that make Middletown a great place to live. I am dedicated to ensuring that Middletown continues to be a great place to live, work, shop, and play. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_bernadette_hannah","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Middletown Township needs to ensure that our citizens are able to support their families and households. We as Supervisors can support families by not raising taxes. The Middletown Township has done an excellent job of demonstrating fiscal responsibility, and shielding tax payers from increased taxes. I would continue to support those efforts."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_bernadette_hannah","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As a Supervisor, I will work to keep Middletown a safe place to do business. I will also  oppose tax increases. When our residents have more disposable income, it results in a boost in consumer spending and improves our businesses. The Middletown Township Board of Supervisors has continuously worked to support businesses. They previously changed ordinances to allow for outdoor dining, advertised for local businesses, and encouraged our citizens to patronize local businesses during the pandemic. I will continue to support business growth with the same dedication."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_bernadette_hannah","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The revitalization of the Oxford Valley Mall area is a major infrastructure need that has to be addressed. Revitalizing the Oxford Valley Mall would require the Board of Supervisors to continue with the recommendations from Township's Comprehensive Plan and the Planning Commission. The sooner we redevelop the Oxford Valley Mall area, the sooner our community will have more housing and business opportunities. It will no longer be a financial burden on the township and its citizens."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_bernadette_hannah","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support incremental steps in the decriminalization of marijuana, for several reasons. First, it would allow our police officers to focus on more serious crimes. Secondly, individuals incarcerated or arrested for such crimes related to possession, would no longer be an undue burden on our justice system. Third, and finally,  the taxes from the sale of marijuana could be used to support Middletown Township initiatives and programs. We need to research exemplar programs that decriminalized marijuana, and replicate those successful programs."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_bernadette_hannah","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["As the current Chair of the Middletown Township's Human Relations Commission, I actively support, promote, and protect diversity, which includes the LGBTQ community. The Human Relations Commission is charged with addressing discrimination within the township. Discriminatory actions against anyone in the LGBTQ community are addressed as directed by our HRC Ordinance and mission statement. We meet monthly to review complaints, plan educational trainings, connect with other HRCs, and access pertinent resources. "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_bernadette_hannah","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support mask mandates in the presence of children who are under 12 years of age, as they are not able to be vaccinated against the COVID virus or its variants at this time. "]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_hanna_howe","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I will work for preservation and progress. I want to keep Solebury the wonderful place it is, and can do that without being rigid or stuck. I’ll listen to the residents and advocate for what makes their lives better."]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_hanna_howe","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["An ongoing and pressing issue is preserving what makes this township unique, including the land and history, while being prepared for progress and future needs. I will continue the fiscally responsible approach of the current supervisors to be ready for what comes next, while staying committed to preserved land and resources. "]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_hanna_howe","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["It’s important to maintain the zoned business areas and be open to the needs of business owners. This is a topic that calls for regular data collecting to know what will help business owners, and to know what the community wants in the business zones. "]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_hanna_howe","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["I’m committed to expanding the biking and walking paths in the township. This effort has already begun in some areas and I will continue the work, connecting as many of our parks and neighborhoods as possible. "]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_hanna_howe","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is a matter appropriately legislated at the state level and the township follows the laws determined by the state. "]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_hanna_howe","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, I support protecting the rights of all people. Everyone deserves to be safe, respected, and heard where they live, work, or visit. "]},{"candidateCode":"solebury_township_supervisor_hanna_howe","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do support mask mandates. I believe masks prevent the spread of viruses and endorse every precaution possible to keep people safe, especially if COVID cases continue to rise."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_6_years_david_d._oxley","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am running to make a difference. I believe that by using my education and experience I can attract new businesses which can provide jobs and tax revenue. My vision is getting the Township on a sound financial footing, long-term planning for responsible growth, attracting new businesses, promoting a family-friendly community while protecting open space and managing building and zoning. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_6_years_david_d._oxley","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe that we must be good stewards not only of our financial resources, but of our unique and vibrant community. Governing requires leadership and leadership requires tough decisions that are made for the good of all the people, not of special interests. "," ","When I became a Supervisor in 2020, I knew that a long-term financial plan was necessary for us to regroup and build back. I reached out to other Townships across Pennsylvania to get ideas and recommendations on consulting resources to guide the Board in our budget process. I brought in a municipal consulting firm with whom the Board of Supervisors and the Budget Committee to developed a 5-year budget, which we are implementing now. I have a strong financial background and my expertise was a driving force in getting us to address today’s situation and plan for tomorrow. We now have an approved 5-year plan that is our fiscally-responsible roadmap for the future.",""]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_6_years_david_d._oxley","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I believe we can offer businesses a thriving environment to relocate and grow. New businesses bring energy, jobs and revenue to our community. The Business Commons and many other commercial spaces are here and ready. And I have a plan on how to bring new business to the Township. Newtown is OPEN FOR BUSINESS!","","I serve as the Board liaison to the Economic Development Committee. I am the only candidate who is actively reaching out to real estate developers, to commercial brokers, to CEO’s, to high-tech and pharma companies to bring them to Newtown. I have many local, state and national contacts from my financial planning business and my extensive network; this is a critical asset in finding and working with people whose companies would be a good fit for Newtown. ","","I will be partnering with the Township and County Planning Commissions, and the Economic Development Committee to expand our reach to aggressively recruit new business. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_6_years_david_d._oxley","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["I believe we need to invest in our community to maintain the quality of life that makes Newtown the special place it is. This means having a long-term investment strategy that puts our money where our priorities are, most importantly our roads. In the most recent Township budget, I supported increased spending to repave municipal roads and that this would be an annual investment. "," ","Poorly maintained roads cost money. It’s estimated that the average annual cost for vehicle repairs due to rough pavement for individual motorists is $500 – which varies by market. Repairs typically involve tires, shock absorbers, suspension systems, struts, rims, wheel alignment and catalytic converters. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_6_years_david_d._oxley","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_6_years_david_d._oxley","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"newtown_township_supervisor_6_years_david_d._oxley","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe in the individual having the right to decide what is best for him or herself and their children.  We rely on parents to make good decisions for their minor children to the extent that those decisions do not endanger other children.  This community has had a tradition and long history of doing just that with the inoculations that most if not all of us has in our bodies at this very moment.  My children are accustomed to wearing masks whether at school or another public place.   Wearing masks is designed to preserve the health and welfare of ourselves and our community members.  While it’s not easys impose decisions on anyone, as a leader of my community I support the preservation of the health and welfare of my community.  I respect those who think otherwise, but in this case, as a leader, I support wearing masks in the close environment of the classroom."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_joan_m._graves","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Falls Township has been my home for 45 years. Working for a Nationwide Retail store, I was responsible for reviewing and submitting Zoning Applications relative to future store expansions and worked with local Zoning Boards throughout the US to ensure criteria for expansions were met. Negotiated Budgets, Contracts and Expenditures with Clinical Research Hospitals, and Doctors around the US and internationally. Managed Clinical Study teams and cross functional teams. During clinical trials I led Vendor selection activities, was responsible for final Vendor selection, and managed their performance. Managed the maintenance of Clinical database systems, ensuring accurate, updated and complete data. I ","served as President of a Private School Board for two years and Individual Committees for years. Volunteer at my local Church in various capacities, including teaching religious education for 20 years. Volunteer with the local Cops for Kids program. Teaching ESL classes for several years."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_joan_m._graves","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["There are several issues to address: Protecting our Environment specifically our water and air quality, Supporting Law Enforcement, the Opioid crisis, preserving ethical government practices. Subsequent to strict Covid restrictions being lifted, MV accidents have increased due to distracted drivers/proper driving safety habits. Coordinate with police personnel to bring hazardous driving habits to the attention of residents through public forums, brochure mailings, and communication through other forms of media. This increase can be addressed through proper re-education. Continue to support the Falls Police Dept. in their ongoing efforts to alleviate the Opioid Epidemic. Participated in the successful opposition against Elcon, and will continue to fight for the Health and Safety of Falls residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_joan_m._graves","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I would poll residents and inquire the type of companies they would favor being brought into the township. Review the types businesses that have recently been added to surrounding municipalities and see if they coincide with what interests Falls residents. I would inquire which companies have an interest in locating within the township. Discourage industries that would negatively impact residents and the environment. Attract new businesses/jobs through community outreach."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_joan_m._graves","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Work closely with Falls counterparts in County and State government to address the hazardous road issues. The State slowly continues to update their highways, but the pace needs to increase to meet the townships needs, and function in line with local repairs. Encourage developers to reutilize existing structures if viable. "]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_joan_m._graves","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Considering the various drugs that may be available, I would address what would still appear to be the most crucial drug problem, the Opioid crisis. The Marijuana state law signed into place in 2016 should remain intact without challenge or changes. "]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_joan_m._graves","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I would support protections for and within any group at the local level, contingent on the circumstances posed at the time."]},{"candidateCode":"falls_township_supervisor_joan_m._graves","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["","Fluctuations continue in the Covid-19 virus cases across the state. Masks continue to be suggested in many of our local business, etc. and residents abide by the restrictions based on what particular groups recommend. I follow the recommendations."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_mary_owens","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have experience dealing with people as a lead business representative. Following contracts and acknowledging members rights are conversations that I regularly engage with companies. My experience and knowledge are tools that I bring as a candidate to my township."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_mary_owens","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The biggest issue that my municipality was facing was bankruptcy. As a current supervisor on the board the goal was and remains to be to control spending."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_mary_owens","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["The best way to support business growth is to continue using the R. C. O.( Responsible Contractor Ordinance)"]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_mary_owens","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Road paving improvements are currently in happening within the township. We paved over 20 miles of township roads by moving road paving into the capital budget where it belongs. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_mary_owens","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Marijuana is a controlled substance as is alcohol and these are governed by the state of Pennsylvania."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_mary_owens","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Everyone deserves to be treated equally and have the same rights. Nobody should be discriminated against!"]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_mary_owens","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Mandates come from the governor and as a supervisor I am required to follow the mandate that is put into place within the Commonwealth."]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_william_connolly","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I bring a lifetime of in government leadership and problem solving. Currently a Warrington Township Supervisor I have also served as a member and Vice Chair of the Warrington Planning Commission. I have an understanding of municipal government in Pennsylvania, as well as the problems and opportunities in Warrington.","Prior to joining the Warrington Township team I had 32 years of senior management experience in state government and 42 years experience in volunteer positions in local government.  I have served as Chair or Vice Chair of the of the Planning Commission in the four municipalities where I have lived and also Chair of the Zoning Board for 22 years in one of them. At the state government level I served for 32 years at the sub-cabinet level  ( that’s the second step below Governor), under 8 consecutive Governors, both Republicans and Democrats, having responsibility building and development regulation throughout the State.",". I am also an Architect and a Professional Planner.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_william_connolly","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Between 1997 and 2015 the population of Warrington nearly doubled. The then Boards of Supervisors seemingly never met a development they didn’t like. Developers were permitted to write their own zoning ordinances All that unchecked and often poorly planned growth was not in the interest of the residents. Since 2016 the current Board of Supervisors has made major progress in managing growth but keeping developers out of the drivers seat and the residents of the Township in it remains the top priority.","I was privileged to chair the Committee that wrote the entirely new and recently adopted Zoning Ordinance.We still need a new set of Development Standards which the committee is working on now. We also need to give all new development proposals serious scrutiny. Our ordinances are now based on the vision of our residents, as expressed in a community wide survey, and we need to make sure that every proposal measures up. "]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_william_connolly","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["The most important thing that a local government can do to support business and job growth is to create a favorable business climate. That involves eliminating unnecessary regulatory barriers and simplifying those rules that are necessary. The new Zoning ordinance simplifies the rules in business zones to encourage private redevelopment and expansion.  A new zone for high tech and bio tech.businesses was created. I support reviewing all our other regulations and fee structures with representatives of the business community to make sure we are as supportive as we can be consistent with public safety."]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_william_connolly","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Traffic and roads are a top infrastructure priority. Improvements to the Easton Road/Street Road and the Easton Road/ Bristol Road intersections are badly needed. While all three are state roads, Pennsylvania law provide room for municipal initiative. The Current Board of Supervisors is moving on both fronts and I will strongly support those efforts.","Open space and recreation are also infrastructure. The zoning ordinance now provides for the preservation of 65% of the area of new housing development. I also strongly support additional grant assisted purchases of open space. Additional active recreation such as playgrounds, playing fields, and our swimming pool need support. The sound fiscal management of the existing Board of Supervisors has enabled the creation of a $12 million capital fund. I support a community wide citizen effort to establish needs and priorities that can be supported by all.","","","","","","",""]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_william_connolly","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support initiatives to decriminalize marijuana use. It is simply not the dangerous drug we once thought it was. It also clearly has some medicinal properties. Pharmaceutical developments based on those properties are inhibited by its criminality. That said, criminality is a matter of the State Criminal Code. Municipalities do not have the power to alter the Criminal Code. Some municipalities have banned marijuana use and attached penalties that are lesser. I don’t believe such efforts are helpful because the State Criminal Code remains. Police Departments get caught in the middle. Which law do they enforce, the local one or the state one that they are also sworn to enforce? We need to attack this problem but we need to do it the right way.",""]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_william_connolly","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["All forms of discrimination against LGBTQ+ persons is wrong. I support laws to that effect at the local, county, state, and national level"]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_william_connolly","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support mask mandates and other necessary restrictions when warranted to control the spread of the disease. The steps that individuals can take are not hard. The need for everyone to take those steps, when rates of infection warrant, is manifest. Failure to take those steps leads to unnecessary deaths. It is as simple as that.","As in all matters regulatory the authority to adopt health based rules rests with the State. The State can, and does delegate its authority to local units of government. In the case of health based regulation in Pennsylvania that authority is delegated to local health agencies. In Bucks County that means the County Board of Health and the County Commissioners, working together. I support those actions at state and county levels whenever conditions warrant.",""]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_2_years_ben_weldon","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I’m a business owner, a husband, and father of four children: ages 4-8. I was born and raised in Bucks County. I’ve been closely involved and actively engaged in local government for over ten years. I believe it’s important to both know what is happening in and be willing to serve a community you love. I’ve demonstrated that commitment over the years. I currently serve on the Investment Committee in Upper Makefield and was also appointed to serve on the Communications and Information Technology sub-committee at the County. I will bring a responsive, reasonable, and forward-thinking voice to our Board of Supervisors."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_2_years_ben_weldon","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["1. We need to continue to preserve and improve the open space and the natural character of Upper Makefield. For purposes of maintaining infrastructure, keeping taxes reasonable, providing necessary benefits to our environment and upholding the quality of life in Upper Makefield, it's critical that we ensure that both our land and neighborhoods are taken care of properly.","","2. Upper Makefield is a unique township. We can and should do more to highlight the history, the natural beauty, and work to build a stronger sense of community within the township. The simplest way to do this is through more consistent communication from our local government about all that goes on within the township.","","3. We also need to continue to plan for the future. Too often local governments get into trouble when they make financial decisions that provide benefits for the short-term. One of my priorities would be to make sure that we are looking forward so that the township is prepared for future generations.",""]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_2_years_ben_weldon","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Upper Makefield is largely a residential community with most retail businesses located in Washington Crossing. One way to improve this area of our township is, as opportunities arise, to plan a more cohesive design and flow that is more inviting, allows residents to park and walk safely among shops. I also would support more communications from our local government that highlight our businesses as well as organizations like the Upper Makefield Business Association that does great work on behalf of our local businesses."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_2_years_ben_weldon","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["There are many opportunities to encourage green energy improvements in Upper Makefield. Our County Planning Commission recently passed a Model Alternative Energy Ordinance. I’d like to see in what ways we can adapt the ordinance for Upper Makefield.","","Increased water runoff and flooding will likely continue to be a major issue in our township as the climate changes and development in neighboring townships drives runoff into Upper Makefield. We need to continue to seek out opportunities to partner with groups like the Heritage Conservancy and others who have the resources to not only preserve land but also help us mitigate the impact of this flooding on our roads, bridges, and homes.","","Additionally, I’ve heard from many residents about the lack of consistent cell service throughout Upper Makefield. While I would be reluctant to add more towers to our landscape, I’d certainly be interested in seeing if there is a way we can improve service using the existing towers. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_2_years_ben_weldon","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While this needs to be driven by a change to state laws, I do support decriminalizing marijuana use and loosening penalties at the local level, where it is within the authority of the Township government. Medical marijuana use is already legal in PA. Our police have a tough job and they shouldn’t need to spend any unnecessary time monitoring the personal use of marijuana."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_2_years_ben_weldon","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. Upper Makefield should be an inclusive township. Many of our neighboring boroughs and township governments have passed resolutions in support of our LGBTQ+ community and I would support the same here in Upper Makefield. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_2_years_ben_weldon","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. I trust experts and care about the health and safety of others in our community. As a Supervisor my job is to know when to defer to the guidance of scientific, medical, and other expert agencies. When those agencies recommend mask mandates or other mitigation measures as a means of helping suppress a surge in a global pandemic, I support adopting that guidance and making sure we are communicating that guidance to the Township. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_6_years_yvette_e._taylor","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a 25 year Bucks County resident and I love living in Upper Makefield with our parks and open space.  I raised my children in Washington Crossing and they attended the great Council Rock schools.  Because I believe in helping families protect the interest of children and seniors, I started my estate planning law practice in Washington Crossing.  I am running because I am an advocate for children and seniors, I believe in a government of inclusiveness, I believe in a government of democratic principle, I believe in making a difference and I believe in giving back to the community where I live and work.  Local government addresses important issues affecting people's lives and it is important for Supervisors to listen to their constituents.  I will take action in the best interest of those I serve, I will encourage community involvement in local governance and I will expand resident access to information and township communication."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_6_years_yvette_e._taylor","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We just had unprecedented tornado warnings and the health and safety of our residents is of grave importance.  During times of distress, from the local impact of the pandemic to severe weather, local government has to serve as a key resource for sound information and clear direction.  The Township must help with preparedness and recovery from natural disasters that are more prevalent than in the past.   ","The historic character and the rural landscape of Upper Makefield Township can serve as opportunities for us all to come together and build community.   We belong to something unique in Upper Makefield and together we can preserve its character in order to maintain our quality of life.  As part of on-going Township management, I would engage participation of the citizenry in all aspects of local living governance.   ",""]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_6_years_yvette_e._taylor","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We have wonderful businesses that have enriched the community for a number of years with the quality services they provide.  Businesses such as Skerdlant’s Shell, Colonial Farms, Diana Vincent Jewelry Design, Dominick’s Pizza and others serve as great partners in addressing the needs of the community.  ","As Supervisor, I will work with local businesses to support initiatives that enrich the community and will work to promote the services of businesses that improve the lives of community residents.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_6_years_yvette_e._taylor","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["During any weather event, severe or otherwise, the loss of electricity to our residents occur more often than should.  Many residents having to invest in generators.  We need to take a better look at all aspects of our infrastructure and develop plans that will look at the most feasible options to best address the issues in our community.   As Supervisor, I am committed to the work required to ascertain infrastructure issues and to make the improvements. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_6_years_yvette_e._taylor","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["There is so much about marijuana that is still unknown.  Medical benefits have been noted in recent times.  With decriminalization even more research can be done to ascertain information on the benefits of marijuana.  I believe our policing resources should be devoted to more serious crimes.  "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_6_years_yvette_e._taylor","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["LGBTQ+ are our neighbors.  They are our nieces, nephews and children.  On all levels, LGBTQ+ rights and protections are human rights and human protections. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_makefield_township_supervisor_6_years_yvette_e._taylor","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["The health and safety of our community is of paramount importance.  It is more important than politics. We have to follow our doctors.  As a Supervisor, I would follow the leadership of our doctors and of the science in supporting whatever we all need to do if COVID cases and death continue to rise.  We do not want our hospitals to be overwhelmed as in other parts of the country.  "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_vitaliy_velenchuk","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My reason for running for Township Supervisor is so that I can contribute to the stewardship of this community. Warminster is a community that has welcomed my family and I feel strongly that we must do more to protect our quality of life. What that requires is hard work and dedication to others. I possess a strong work ethic, a record of community involvement and , due to my role in running a small business, I understand the balance between providing quality service and controlling spending. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_vitaliy_velenchuk","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Quality of life issues from a lack of enforcement is the biggest issue we currently face. How do we address it? We must address the underlying issue - the unfunded pension and retirement benefits. Money that could be used to address quality of life and safety issues, is not available because it is being spent elsewhere. We must come up with a plan to shore up these funds instead of heavily borrowing money and reducing services. Our current board has drastically increased debt and increased taxes while services being provided to the residents have dropped and properties are being allowed to become overgrown. We must reverse this trend. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_vitaliy_velenchuk","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Warminster's business community needs the township to be a partner and advocate for our business community. We must return to working with businesses to address concerns and strategize solutions as we had done in years past.  Previous boards prioritized economic development, something that has seemingly disappeared with the current board. We also must prioritize redevelopment of existing parcels. We have a diverse portfolio of real estate in our community and it can serve many purposes. The township must have a seat at this table to ensure that the growth that does happen is in line with the 2018 Comprehensive Plan that balances the need for growth with accessibility and quality of life issues for our residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_vitaliy_velenchuk","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Warminster has 100 miles of roads, many of them well overdue for resurfacing. The Public Works crew that rebuilds our streets do a terrific job but we must find a way to do more roads, more often. There are roads that have not been touched in over 20 years. Right now, we rely on state liquid fuels tax disbursements to pay for road work.(The liquid fuels tax payment is each municipality's share of the nation's third highest gas tax)  But even money that does not allow us to be aggressive enough to avoid 20 year gaps. We need to redirect budget to supplement the liquid fuels money and try to stay ahead of the need rather than always chasing after the biggest problems. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_vitaliy_velenchuk","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Marijuana policy is dictated by state and local governments. I would not expect the Board of Supervisors to flaunt the will of the people. Medical Marijuana is permitted in Pennsylvania. Should the commonwealth or the federal government decide to decriminalize it, I will follow the law. Until that time, I do not believe it is appropriate for the Board of Supervisors to disregard the rule of law. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_vitaliy_velenchuk","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I believe in the inherent worth and dignity of every individual. As an immigrant from for a Soviet bloc country, I know what it means to be singled out for being different. The best way to ensure protections for any group of people is through the creation of Federal and/or state laws.  Township Supervisors lack the ability to impact these areas beyond passing resolutions that are largely statement of beliefs. My goal as  a supervisor is to serve all residents of Warminster, including communities that are not always visible in our township. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_vitaliy_velenchuk","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I immigrated from the Ukraine nearly two decades ago. I saw firsthand the impact of government-enforced compulsory behavior. I do not support mask mandates as I do not feel comfortable with the government imposing beliefs upon others that they may not share. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_andy_warren","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My qualifications include service in both public, (township, county and state governments) as well as the private sector (PENJERDEL Council).  Respectfully interacting with members of the public, oversight of multi-million dollar budgets, reasonably resolving complex issues have all been aspects of my professional life.  In varying degrees each will be addressed by township supervisors.  I consider myself an \"open door\" manager, responsive to community concerns -- always."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_andy_warren","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["First, I would address transparency.  It is the only way to deal with current township issues.  Public safety is a major concern  which includes not only oversight of police and fire personnel, but also traffic issues.  Middletown is growing and planning is essential as development impacts all of the above.  Middletown supervisors must address development and other quality of life issues with important community input from those who are most impacted."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_andy_warren","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Businesses will locate and flourish in municipalities that provide access to, and familiarity with, elected officials.  In addition to actively partnering with business leaders in organizations such as local Chambers of Commerce, input from the small business community is a vital component of all township planning."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_andy_warren","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Bridge maintenance, road repair, and access to public transportation are all infrastructure issues that demand the attention of township supervisors.  Having previously worked with PENNDOT, Bucks County Commissioners plus serving on the SEPTA Board, will provide valuable insight toward a working relationship with all of these infrastructure agencies."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_andy_warren","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Marijuana use as prescribed by a doctor is not a crime; therefore decriminalization of marijuana should not be a township issue.  I would not endorse marijuana use for any other reason."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_andy_warren","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Middletown Township is an equal opportunity employer and current anti-discriminatory laws are the guide.",""]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_andy_warren","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Federal and state governments have far greater access to \"studied research\" regarding the effectiveness of mandated mask wearing---I would follow the guidelines."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_kathy_frescatore","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have served as Township Supervisor since being elected in 2015, and am the current Vice Chair. I am a lifelong Warminster volunteer including coach of Warminster Boys and Girls sports including baseball, softball and basketball. I've served on various township boards and was the first female coach in Boys Baseball. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_kathy_frescatore","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our board has implemented a strong financial plan which enabled our township to avoid bankruptcy. I intend to continue to support our fiscally responsible plan. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_kathy_frescatore","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I support our Responsible Contract Ordinance."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_kathy_frescatore","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We will continue to pave our neglected roads and address our stormwater issues.. Under our new road paving program, 23 miles of roads have been completed. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_kathy_frescatore","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As an elected official it is my responsibility to follow all state guidelines."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_kathy_frescatore","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I believe in equal rights for all."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_kathy_frescatore","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I will  follow all state guidelines.."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_dana_kane","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Professional expertise and a love for this township. A significant part of the board responsibilities lie in setting the budget, making financial appropriations, and levying taxes.  As an Actuary with over 15 years of financial modeling, budgeting, and forecasting experience, I will provide expert oversight and accountability over how our taxpayer dollars are spent. Being born and raised in Middletown, I know the impact overdevelopment has had on our township over the last decade. I plan to utilize my expertise in forecasting to address what I believe has been insufficient board planning and transparency causing issues associated with overall quality of life including storm water management, traffic, and stalled economic growth.   "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_dana_kane","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Transparency. Our current board is one party, and many decisions are made 5-0 without discussion. Voting decisions should not be made without considering different points of view. There needs to be robust discussion that challenges the status quo. I will make sure that alternate viewpoints are heard, and that the decisions being made are in the best interest of every resident of Middletown. I believe that in all these decisions we need to consider both the short term and long-term effect on our community. We have big decisions to make as a township over the next 5 – 10 years, that will determine the future of Middletown. I will ensure the community is well apprised of the impacts, prior to decisions being made, and will work to ensure a high degree of transparency in all decisions going forward."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_dana_kane","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Fiscal responsibility and Planning. Having a BS in Economics, I recognize the importance of small business and the challenges they face in today’s climate. I hope to use my expertise to shape policy and ensure they stay a part of our community for years to come.  In addition I plan to reach out to local businesses and find ways to create opportunities to grow existing business and bring more business operators into the township."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_dana_kane","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Overdevelopment, Traffic, and Stormwater Management. Our township needs to make sure we are continuing to correct immediate problems and plans are in place, taking advice from experts in the field, to address the issues going forward. I would work with both County, State and Federal officials to ensure the Township is leveraging all available assistance."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_dana_kane","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While I believe this is not under the purview of a municipality, I would support any changes made by our state and federal legislators.   "]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_dana_kane","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I am proud that Middletown Township adheres to all federal and PA state laws to protect individuals from discrimination, which includes LGBTQ+."]},{"candidateCode":"middletown_township_supervisor_dana_kane","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would continue to align our township with the most up to date guidance from both our county health department and the CDC, making sure vaccinations are available to those that are eligible and willing, and continuing to educate the community with best practices for limiting the spread of COVID-19."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_maggie_rash","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Buckingham has a total of 6240 protected acres in Buckingham. I personally have brokered easements on 1,584 of the 4,000+ acres of farmland and open space by developing relationships of trust in our community; I now have 182 more acres in the preservation pipeline. Because of my leadership, Buckingham has a AAA bond rating since 2014 and the LOWEST TOWNSHIP TAXES in Bucks County.  Every acre saved is one less house built and fewer children to educate, contributing to lower school taxes, our greatest burden.  Buckingham is the #1 safest township of our size in the state of Pennsylvania, also ranking 3rd on the list of top 100 safest towns in the U.S.  All of the above supports my mission to continue to serve the residents of Buckingham Township and keep it a great place to live and raise a family."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_maggie_rash","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Speeding is our greatest complaint.   Most of our police calls are traffic related and consequently we have beefed up traffic enforcement and posted more electronic speed signs. My huge concern for Buckingham as well as all municipalities in Central Bucks is helping our volunteer fire companies.  Our population continues to increase while the volunteers decrease.  As president of BCATO (Bucks County Association of Township Officials) and a township supervisor, I am working with Doylestown, Lingohocken, and Midway Fire Companies to strategize on recruitment.  There also is great concern for our emergency management ambulance services.  Right now I'm working with Central Bucks Emergency Medical Services to solve their funding issues.  Central Bucks EMS services over 150,000 residents and it's critical that we help them survive.",""]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_maggie_rash","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Firstly, Buckingham does not have a commercial tax.  We're working to expand our trail system to connect our community to local shops and businesses such as our farm stores.  We are in the midst of a Cross Keys revitalization project and are working on making that area more walk-able.  The  Pennsylvania Biotechnology Center in Cross Keys is a nonprofit life sciences incubator dedicated to the promotion of regional economic development and job creation; and to the education and training of tomorrow’s researchers.  The Buckingham Township staff works hard to help the Bio Tech in their expansion projects, and enables the center to comply for grants in a timely manner."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_maggie_rash","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Keeping our roads safe and in good shape is a priority.  Our road crew is efficient and keeps township streets in excellent condition on a rotating schedule. Buckingham cannot improve or repair a PennDot Road and that's where the pothole problem lies. If we go onto a state road Buckingham assumes liability and our taxpayers pay the price. Of course if there is an emergency, such as a fallen tree or a pothole that is causing damage and danger, the township does respond. Our crew worked 24/7 after the recent storm and tornado to get the roads open as soon as was safe.  Regarding potholes our township manager has fostered an excellent relationship with PennDot and they have come out to patch an extremely dangerous stretch of road not on their schedule, as an example, Swamp Road. I personally have put pressure on that state agency and our State Reps to provide better and quicker road repair."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_maggie_rash","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Recreational marijuana remains illegal in Pennsylvania and the law still makes it a crime to possess marijuana.  I would not direct my Chief of Police to usurp Pennsylvania law as he has to charge under the correct State statute.  That said,  drug cases go directly to the the District Attorney's office and the DA has a system in place that offenders go the treatment route and the sentence is diverted.  Diversion takes place at the County level."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_maggie_rash","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["So far, I'm not aware of an instance in Buckingham where LGBTQ+  have needed protection and if that's been the case this is a perfect forum to contact me.  Truthfully, I have several LGBTQ+ folk in my personal sphere and I only know they are such because they choose to discuss it.  In Buckingham my colleagues and I, along with our very able police department, strive to protect all our residents from abuse."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_maggie_rash","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Before vaccinations became available, masks were required in the Buckingham Township Administration building.  The initial mask mandate was discontinued and our staff became vaccinated.  I choose to wear a mask in certain circumstances but it's my personal decision and Buckingham Township is not requiring masks."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_township_supervisor_deb_rendon","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience of over 40 years in local government: 20 year professional career in PA township management,  20+ yrs appointed New Britain Township planning commissioner, as well as Land Preservation/Open Space committee member.  "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_township_supervisor_deb_rendon","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I plan to address the ineffectiveness of the township's current infrastructure maintenance of local roads, bridges, parks, storm water control, etc. by obtaining expert assessments of the impacts of development and climate change while reaching out for available local solutions with maximum citizen input, increased regional cooperation and improved township financial management."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_township_supervisor_deb_rendon","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will continue to support development of the township's existing commercial and industrial zoning districts and encourage smart infrastructure development to attract redevelopment."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_township_supervisor_deb_rendon","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Immediately I see significant infrastructure needs in our bridges, roads and culverts but if elected I will have the opportunity to learn of others, possibly in the parks facilities and the municipal buildings. These are just the hard infrastructure needs."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_township_supervisor_deb_rendon","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While not versed in the laws on this issue, I can see some very positive reasons to consider decriminalizing it such as reducing over burdened prison populations, eliminating the need for bogus medical marijuana prescriptions and taxing the already booming industries' revenues. That said, laws would need to be reviewed to control new, unintended impacts this could have on the general citizenry."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_township_supervisor_deb_rendon","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely, in fact in the 1980's I successfully amended my township's non-discrimination policy to include protection for \"sexual preference\" (the term used at that time), in addition to race, age, etc.  These protections should apply to include all programs and employment practices of the township government, as legally permitted."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_township_supervisor_deb_rendon","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support the science based mandates and recommendations intended to protect all citizens and eliminate this pandemic.  Collectively we can do it; individually one may or may not be lucky."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_janice_charlton","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the best candidate to represent the citizens of Warminster since I genuinely care about each and everyone of the residents.  I am not a politician, but I am a problem solver.  As a mother of nine, I am often called to hear both sides of an argument and find solutions that each person leaves feeling as though their opinions were heard and valued.  The problems facing our nation and communities have never been greater and now is the time for a new form of leadership.  I am not afraid to take a stand up for the rights of the residents of Warminster and will speak up where necessary and lead by example.  "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_janice_charlton","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The trash is definitely to biggest problem facing our community.  Our current board has had little effect on the contract with our current company.  I will propose a credit to each homeowner since the trash company has neglected their responsibilities to our community.  They claim it’s due to a limited number of employees which would cause them to have additional revenue to be able to refund our residents a third of their trash, recycle and yard waste.  We have a few years remaining on our contract.  If they fail to process refunds to our residents I will personally file a breach of contract against them until they can meet the needs of our community.  Additionally, I will personally hold their business responsible for the health hazard their lack of waste removal is causing our community."]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_janice_charlton","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will become better acquainted with the current businesses already in Warminster and find out their concerns.  I will address them and assure their strength before adding similar businesses to take customers away from their business.  Our small businesses have suffered a lot over the past year and a half.  It’s important that we help support  them while they rebuild their business.  "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_janice_charlton","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The traffic within Warminster township is a constant concern of our residents.  Many of our neighborhoods with children have speeding cars that cut through to avoid the major roads and traffic lights.  I think it’s important that we address these safety issues thru changes in traffic patterns such as no left turns across major streets during peak times and speed bumps at school bus stops. "]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_janice_charlton","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I think there are too many people incarcerated for possession of Marijuana.  That takes tax payers money to keep them in jail when these spaces would be better served to house criminals that have committed more violent crimes.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_janice_charlton","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I believe everyone should treat each other the way they wish to be treated regardless of race, religion or sexual preference. It’s time for adults to act like adults and set the example for our children.   We should be showing how we can be understanding of each other and know that we are not here to judge each other but to build each other up to strengthen our communities.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"warminster_township_supervisor_janice_charlton","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I feel that every American has access to the research on Covid and that everyone should have the freedom to make their own choices to protect their family.  Our small businesses suffered and many even permanently closed.  I don’t think shutting our economy down benefits everyone.  We have learned from the last year that their was no standard that determined what businesses remained open which consequently effected small businesses, not the corporate stores what were allowed to remain open.  We need to keep everything in perspective and focus on what is best for our community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_paula_gasper","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My lifelong experience in building  a successful business in Northampton township and having  a great regard for my entire community. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_paula_gasper","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Fortunately there is not a specific top issue currently. Our township has been operating responsibly, I will address any issues as they arise. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_paula_gasper","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As a business owner I would certainly do the necessary research and make an informed decision on our business growth in the community"]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_paula_gasper","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The major infrastructure need in the township is the repair and care for our township roads . Our township has done a very good job of maintaining roads and public parks. We will continue to do so. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_paula_gasper","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["These measures are not decided in local municipalities.",""]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_paula_gasper","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["We ALL have the right to protection under the law.","I support all protection for every citizen including the LGBTQ. "]},{"candidateCode":"northampton_township_supervisors_paula_gasper","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support individual and family choice in deciding on the mask mandate. "]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_patti_bye","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I want to keep Buckingham a great place to live. My roots here run deep: the Bye family has lived in Buckingham for 300+ years. In the 3+ decades here, I’ve built a successful career as a business manager and security and emergency management professional. I’ve helped local, state and federal agencies plan/respond to extreme weather, hurricanes and pandemics. I’ve also raised two children with my husband Randy, and volunteered my time and business expertise for local organizations such as Bucks Beautiful, St. Mary Medical Center Healing Gardens, and the Bucks County Audubon Society.","","Now I want to use my skills and passion to deliver for you as Township Supervisor. Today Buckingham faces many challenges. Maintaining our local character. Making our infrastructure more resilient. Helping our businesses thrive in a post-COVID world. As an entrepreneur, emergency & infrastructure expert, and committed citizen, I bring fresh ideas and perspectives to keep Buckingham a great place to live.",""]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_patti_bye","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Being prepared for whatever the future may bring is the top issue facing Buckingham Township. We need to keep Buckingham Township a great place to live well into the future. This means maintaining our distinctive mix of open spaces, farms, businesses, parks, homes and history. Continuing the work to preserve open space is important. We committed to help keep Buckingham beautiful when we preserved our property from development in 1999.","","More crucial is the need to evaluate any proposed changes or development in terms of how well it maintains or improves the character of the township. At the same time, we need to address flooding and other impacts of today's more intense storms such as tornados.  I can offer years of expertise helping federal, state & local transportation and emergency agencies on ways to prepare for and respond to weather emergencies and other challenges.",""]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_patti_bye","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As an entrepreneur myself, I know business growth is key to maintaining the vitality of our community. Let’s make it easier to do business in Buckingham, to attract new commercial, retail and other business so we don’t have commercial buildings and storefronts sitting empty. I want to create a “one-stop shop” resource for doing business in Buckingham on the Township website. Let’s make it easy for new businesses to come into the community instead of forcing them to figure out for themselves which documents and materials are important. Let’s partner with local and state organizations that provide support to new and existing businesses to help them grow. Let’s work with property owners and the community to understand the evolving business needs of the Township. And let’s raise awareness of the existing businesses in the Township through high-profile community events that highlight local businesses. There is so much more we can do to support this crucial part of our community."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_patti_bye","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Infrastructure is all of the systems and resources required to support a thriving community not just roads & bridges. So many problems have gone on for too long – we need pothole-free safe roads, better storm water management, safe drinking water, reliable power. We cannot keep doing what we are doing. I’ll address these needs by working in partnership with state agencies, utilities, property owners, and others in the community to look beyond short-term quick fixes and instead take the longer-term view. ","","COVID changed how we live & work. Let’s make sure our infrastructure keeps up.  ","Virtual meetings, online services, more walking & bike paths, better traffic management for people, cars and commercial vehicles. All are crucial and don’t need to be expensive. Often funding is available to help cover the cost. Beautiful areas like Buckingham attract workers from all over the country. Let’s make sure our community can grow and thrive while keeping it a great place to live."]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_patti_bye","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["It’s important to keep in mind that decriminalization does not make marijuana legal - it reduces the penalties from criminal charges to citations or fines. These fines typically range from $100 in Delaware to $250 in Mississippi. Doylestown Borough recently passed an ordinance with a $25 citation for the 1st offense.","","I believe decriminalization would allow our police and courts to focus their limited resources on other, often more serious issues. And there are other benefits: for example, states that have decriminalized marijuana were found to have fewer opioid-related deaths and hospitalizations than states that did not. ","","Nationally 69% of all Americans, from both major political parties, favor legalization of marijuana. Medical use of marijuana has been legal in Pennsylvania for five years. In our state 58% percent of resident voters now support legalizing marijuana for personal uses too. As a society, we have changed the way we think about marijuana. Our laws should change too. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_patti_bye","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Voters may not know that Pennsylvania law does not specifically prohibit discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity. Some local governments in the state -including those surrounding Buckingham Township such as Doylestown, New Hope, Newtown Borough and Township, Hatboro, Lansdale and others - do have ordinances that provide protections for LGBTQ+ from discrimination in employment, housing, and public services (which includes prohibitions on being denied service or entry to places that are available to the public).  ","","I believe it is crucial for local governments like ours to provide protections for our LGBTQ+ citizens when our state does not. I would join our neighbors to ensure that all members of our community have the same protections in the law. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"buckingham_township_supervisor_patti_bye","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a security and emergency management professional, my career is all about protecting others from harm and doing whatever is necessary to help a community get through an event with as little loss of life and damage as possible. ","","COVID has been with us for some time now so we know more about what works and what makes things worse. Wearing masks indoors have been demonstrated to protect ourselves as well as others from COVID. Currently, the CDC recommends mask wearing indoors for everyone in areas of high COVID transmission rates. That includes people who been vaccinated because even they can, unfortunately, transmit COVID to others. And not everyone is, or can be, vaccinated. ","","If COVID cases continue to rise, I will continue to do what I do – work to protect people and the community. To do that I would follow the guidance and recommendations of credible health officials.",""]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_matthew_given","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["In my professional life I work for a major regional non-profit theatre company.  It is my job to take the big, creative ideas and make them happen.  It is my responsibility to know and prepare for the big picture and every little detail.  I collaborate with the creative team and the technicians to take the idea from the page to the stage.  Often times this work requires reworking of the initial idea to fit the tight budget.  I understand that major accomplishments are always the product of great planning, hard work, and compromise.  This is the experience that I will bring to our Township and why I am the best candidate for the job.  "]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_matthew_given","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The invasion of the corrosive national discord into our local government.  Our local government should be focused on the betterment of our community not who to blame, focused on the good ideas not which party the idea originated from.  Sadly, the national screaming match is inching closer to our collective doorstep.  My goals as supervisor are simple: to serve my neighbors, and to better our community.  I will bring a centrist, well-reasoned voice to the board.  I will foster collaboration with my fellow board members and transparency with the community.  Neighbors helping Neighbors."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_matthew_given","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will support business growth, if and only if it fits into existing zoning ordinances and serves to better our community.  In those instances where growth is appropriate, I will advocate for locally owned businesses.  I do not believe in unfettered growth or development."]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_matthew_given","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Severe weather events have now become common place in our part of Pennsylvania.  Whether it be tornado, flooding, blizzard or high winds, these events are here to stay.  We need to determine how these severe events affect our Township infrastructure and then plan accordingly.  As Supervisor, I will push to include this issue in the upcoming Township comprehensive plan.  On the short term, I will seek guidance from our Public Works Director, experts in the field, and representatives from state and national government.  "]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_matthew_given","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The legalization of any controlled substance is an issue handled at the Commonwealth level not the local municipality.  As such, I will defer to the Commonwealth on this matter.  "]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_matthew_given","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I fully support, and strive to be an ally to the members of Plumstead's LGBTQ+ community.  As Township Supervisor I will have an open door for our LGBTQ+ friends to make their voices heard and help to keep Plumstead an inclusive community. "]},{"candidateCode":"plumstead_township_supervisor_matthew_given","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["The Bucks County Health Department and the Pennsylvania Department of Health are responsible for setting guidelines for disease prevention and the local and state levels respectively.  As Township Supervisor I will support both agencies and do everything within my power to encourage our community to follow their guidelines.  "]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_seth_p._gansman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Experience, dedication and follow-through.  I have experience in both finance and local government.  I have been an elected Warrington Township auditor since 2019 and in finance since 2011.  I want to solve problems facing the township today and help plan for those we may face in years to come.  Keeping our township fiscally sound while ensuring service are fully funded is not easy, but with my experience I feel I can help get it done. "]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_seth_p._gansman","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We must balance growth with the health, safety and welfare of the residents who already live here and the economic viability of the businesses that have been struggling since the beginning of the pandemic.  Quantifying a \"top\" issue is difficult as different residents are facing different issues daily."]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_seth_p._gansman","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["My focus is on both supporting existing small businesses, helping them grow and thrive in Warrington and on attracting the entrepreneurs who can flourish here.  Revitalization of the 611 corridor with new and exciting enterprises, those that will both be attractive to local residents and bring revenue to visitors, is a key goal for me. "]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_seth_p._gansman","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Road repair.  There have been several ideas put forth about how best  to repair more of our local roads while keeping our budget intact.  Working with other local municipalities to purchase equipment that can be shared, or bulk purchases of supplies would be one possible solution.  With increased traffic and severe weather our roads are eroding at an alarming rate.  We need to find a long term solution. "]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_seth_p._gansman","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["This can be a divisive issue, and should be openly discussed with residents, experts and law enforcement to understand their viewpoints.  There are a great many factors to take into consideration and these are questions I continue to study."]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_seth_p._gansman","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, every person has the right too feel safe and secure in our township.  Our country was founded by those fighting  too be heard and to have a free and open society.  Township Facilities designed too ensure basic needs are met should be a focus of our local government.  Just as with other township issues, listening to all viewpoints to understand how better to help those inn need is key."]},{"candidateCode":"warrington_township_supervisor_seth_p._gansman","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["We need to defer to the medical and scientific experts regarding COVID.  I follow multiple news sources with wide ranging viewpoints daily.  Protecting our residents is of paramount importance to me and I will make decisions based on the best interests of Warrington Township and its residents.  "]},{"candidateCode":"warwick_township_supervisor_john_w._cox_iii","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been a supervisor for Warwick Township since 2006. During that time, we have preserved almost 1200 acres of open space, built and paid for an EMS building.  We opened a new 50 acre park with a pavilion, passive recreation field and safety town bike village.  We continue to link the township with walking trails.  Most importantly we have done all this with fiscal responsibility. We have retired all debt and have not increased taxes in 12 years.  "]},{"candidateCode":"warwick_township_supervisor_john_w._cox_iii","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We need to control growth to be sure that the rights of landowners and the quality of life of our residents are all protected. By meeting our goals of a rural appearance for new development we can keep our small-town feel.  "]},{"candidateCode":"warwick_township_supervisor_john_w._cox_iii","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Good business growth occurs when zoning and land development are well written and enforced.  When we see a need we contact and encourage different desirable business to consider our township in their expansion plans."]},{"candidateCode":"warwick_township_supervisor_john_w._cox_iii","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We continue to work on linking our entire township with walking and biking trails.  We have recently completed a major link under York Rd. Between Memorial Park and the Moland house. The ultimate goal will be for access to all of our 7 parks and neighborhoods via off road trails."]},{"candidateCode":"warwick_township_supervisor_john_w._cox_iii","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The legalization of marijuana is a state legislature issue.  I think that there is a danger of a patchwork approach to decriminalization that will ultimately result in uneven enforcement. I strongly encourage our state legislature to take on this issue to create a unified approach.  It is obviously an issue that needs to be addressed."]},{"candidateCode":"warwick_township_supervisor_john_w._cox_iii","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support equal rights for all.  Once again I believe that this is a state legislature issue that would avoid unequal enforcement at a local level.  It is important that local government create laws that they have the resources to enforce."]},{"candidateCode":"warwick_township_supervisor_john_w._cox_iii","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Once again this is an issue better left to the county or state who have the health departments that are in place to make determinations as to the need and effectiveness of such orders.  As a township we do not have the expertise to make these decisions except as a personal opinion."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_4_donald_mcgowan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a commissioner, I can best represent the neighbors of Hatfield Township Ward 4, because I share their values and their concerns. I understand what makes Hatfield a great place to live, and how we can work to make it better. Since I am not a typical politician, I can bring a more realistic approach to our local government. As a project manager for an engineering company, I know what it takes to create high value, cost effective benefits to those I serve. I can use the unique skill I have obtained throughout my career to build a better Hatfield."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_4_donald_mcgowan","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["As we have seen over the last several years, new housing developments are overwhelming our community. They are consuming our open spaces, and congesting our roads. The consequences of over-development are alarming and impactful. It will have negative effects on our roads, schools, and utilities. Housing developers are too often granted permission to develop without the concern for the residents that already live here. The only way to slow or stop the housing developments is to have a compassionate Board of Commissioners that understands the consequences of over-development, and truly represents the people. As a commissioner, the rubber stamp stops with me. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_4_donald_mcgowan","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As commissioner, it will be a priority of mine to drive new businesses to Hatfield, and allow existing business to grow. Because I studied business in college, I have a profound understanding of how economic activity can benefit a community. I will work with the business advocacy organizations, as well as the county and state government, to find innovative ways to bring business to Hatfield that will create jobs and economic growth. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_4_donald_mcgowan","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Hatfield Township is in desperate need for reconfiguration of some of our intersections. Also, because of the over-development, there will be a greater need for more rainwater runoff and waste water capacity. As commissioner, I will work with the township engineer and manager to secure grants for major infrastructure improvements. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_4_donald_mcgowan","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While township commissioners have little, if any, impact on marijuana laws, it is my belief that the criminalization of marijuana has had a negative impact on society. I will use any influence I have as commissioner to encourage our state legislature to move to decriminalize marijuana at a state level, or give more authority over the matter to local governments. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_4_donald_mcgowan","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["As a candidate endorsed by the LGBTQ+ rights group, Ricky's Pride PAC, I am in full support of protections for this community. One of my first initiatives as commissioner will be to introduce a non-discrimination ordinance for the township."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_4_donald_mcgowan","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I will always follow the science when it comes to COVID-19. If the scientists recommend mask wearing as an effective way of reducing virus transmission, I will support mask mandates and other necessary restrictions. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_john_a._taylor","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been been on Telford Borough Council since October 2016 and currently hold the Council seat as President, since 2020. I have also spent nine years with Souderton Telford Main Streets (STMS) working with the community. I have hands on experience and have a passion for my community.",""]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_john_a._taylor","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Getting local businesses back to being successful after a tough 2020 & 2021.  Actively engage with businesses and the community through community events, such as the Telford Nite Market and active promotion of our local businesses."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_john_a._taylor","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Promote local businesses in all our community events.  Promote Telford as a safe, community-driven Borough to live, work and thrive."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_john_a._taylor","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Currently supporting the Borough's ongoing infrastructure work at the Water Sewer plant and the paving and improvement of local streets with minimal disruption to our constituents."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_john_a._taylor","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. I would support alternative measures, such as drug treatment programs/facilities rather than arrest, depending on the incident and the individuals history. The issue is rather complex and not ideal for simplistic solutions."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_john_a._taylor","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. Maintain and/or strengthen the existing non-discrimination policy currently in place with the Telford Police Department and Telford Borough Office."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_john_a._taylor","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would support the recommendations provided by the CDC, state, county and medical community guidance."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_council_rich_girard","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["37 year borough resident and my working background in management and finance"]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_council_rich_girard","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Governmental transparency. Online and in person council meetings and other gatherings"]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_council_rich_girard","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Maintain and improve electrical and other infrastructure"]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_council_rich_girard","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Roads. I would seek to get grants through our state representative"]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_council_rich_girard","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, because have more pressing issues to contend with."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_council_rich_girard","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, but not sure how at this point."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_council_rich_girard","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes because everyone has a right to live even if others want to die."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_william_gallagher","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["The time that I have served on Horsham Township Council has been a great experience and has showed me that we have so many amazing people who have done so much to make our community a beautiful place to live, work and enjoy.  I think I have learned how to work with  many organizations, groups and individuals and I support their efforts in making Horsham \"even better.\"  That also includes the ability to work with people from different political parties in the best interest of our community.  I think I can help to maintain the very high level of public services for our residents while keeping the lowest possible costs to our tax payers.  I am very aware of the many challenges our township faces in the years ahead and think that I can work with my colleagues on Council to meet those challenges as well as even improving many of the services we provide our residents. My focus will be to look for ways to enhance everything we already do well for all members of our community.",""]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_william_gallagher","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I am very concerned about the over development of our township.  This impacts the quality of life for all our residents.  It can also have an impact on the cost of providing services for our community and lead to increased taxes.  There is also an impact on our schools that can result in tax increases.  The impact on traffic congestion should always be considered.  We have a beautiful community and planning for the future development of Horsham is of critical importance.  I will always consider the benefit to our township and the impact that future developments have on our community before approving any development projects."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_william_gallagher","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["The businesses in Horsham have had so many challenges over the last year and and a half.  The need to organize and support local businesses was an important role played by the Horsham Chamber of Commerce.  I would work to strengthen this organization and recruit new members to carry on this great work.  Our community also started Horsham Connected.  Horsham Connected brings local groups and organizations together to support each other.  I hope we can also use that group to support and strengthen our local business community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_william_gallagher","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["I think traffic congestion in Horsham is a concern now but will be a major concern in the future.  We should continue to look at every area of our township and look for ways to improve the traffic flow in Horsham during peak drive times.  There is a huge need to improve the traffic flow through the intersections and and we should continue to work to improve them.  I am also a supporter of making Horsham a more \"walkable community.\"  I will continue to look for ways to increase the number of sidewalks so that we can safely enjoy walking in our community."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_william_gallagher","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do not support measures to decriminalize marijuana.  Penalties should be loosened.  Too many people are in prison for non violent and minor marijuana related offenses.  This costs our tax payers and hurts the families of those in prison.  I do have concerns about the impact of marijuana on our community.  I think we still need common sense restrictions and penalties.  "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_william_gallagher","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I do support LGBTQ+ protections in Horsham  I believe in diversity and equality for all our citizens.  I will work with  members of the Horsham Government and our great community groups and organizations to enhance our efforts to provide these supports and protections.  I would also support actions on Horsham Township Council that might help to make sure that all our residents had equal opportunities and did not face discrimination in our community."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_william_gallagher","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would support mask mandates and other restrictions if COVID cases continued to rise.  We have a responsibility as elected officials to do our best to keep our community safe and our schools and businesses open.  We should continue to inform and communicate with our residents as much as possible regarding COVID and its spread in our community.  Data is frequently shared at Council meetings for Township Council to consider any actions that might be necessary in our community.  We make that information available to our residents.  Our meetings are now televised and we also send alerts, updates and notifications through e-mails, text messages and township web sites.  It should always be about the best interest of our residents and how we in Horsham Government can help to keep our community safe.  "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_commissioner_ward_3_charles_whiting","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have experience and proven leadership in the Upper Moreland community.  I am dedicated and resourceful. As an Eagle Scout, who continues to provide mentoring to our younger scouts and provide service to my scout troop, I have transitioned my service to supporting the Upper Moreland community. Being, also a former teacher and Principal, I enjoyed  serving as the President of the Upper Moreland Free Public Library, one of the best libraries in Montgomery County. I have been instrumental in fighting for and preserving open space in my county by, for example,  protecting the Sycamore Village Playground.  I have made certain that Upper Moreland is a safe place for our residents to live, learn, and be by continuing to support our Police, Fire, and EMS through funding, training, and equipment needs. I helped to maintain financial solvency in our township through the budget process so that we protect our taxpayers. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_commissioner_ward_3_charles_whiting","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["In Upper Moreland, one of the top issues facing our community is Public Health and Safety, especially in light of the COVID Pandemic and how to keep the members of our community safe and alive. We have encouraged all residents to wear a mask, get vaccinated, and maintain the proper distances in enclosed areas. We follow the CDC guidelines in all of our businesses and educational facilities. We have provided distribution for obtaining the vaccine and COVID testing in our communities. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_commissioner_ward_3_charles_whiting","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I continue to support business growth in our township, making certain that Upper Moreland is business-friendly.   We encourage new businesses to relocate and maintain their business  here to support the revitalization of the township and our Township Center, which is currently underway. In Upper Moreland, we work as partners with all of our businesses to maintain and sustain the growth of our diverse community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_commissioner_ward_3_charles_whiting","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Currently, in the area of infrastructure, we, in Upper Moreland Township are working on upgrading traffic patterns and the  flow of traffic in the community. We continue to improve our streets through repaving them while also refitting outdated pipe systems.  Our township continues to work on storm water issues, as we, also,  upgrade township lighting issues and broadband usage for the community."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_commissioner_ward_3_charles_whiting","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. I would support measures to decriminalize and loosen penalties for marijuana possession offenses to help lessen the conviction rates and flow of offenders through our court system for this minor offense. Measures have already be taken, approved, and supported in surrounding states, like New Jersey, to help decriminalize the possession of marijuana, in small amounts."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_commissioner_ward_3_charles_whiting","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. I support the right of all citizens to have equal access to health care, housing, employment. All citizens should be free from discrimination. I continue to support the Equality Act passed in Upper Moreland Township."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_commissioner_ward_3_charles_whiting","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. I support the wearing of masks to help eradicate the pandemic that we are currently, still experiencing. This will ensure the health and safety of all of our community members."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_alex_myers","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["During this four-year term, I am asking for the responsibility of bringing you the best public services, overseeing several infrastructure projects, continuing to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic, responsibly managing community growth, and providing transparency and support to you, our business district, and our various community partners. I’m a 3rd-generation Hatboro resident and an Army veteran that honorably served as a Korean linguist. I hold a liberal arts degree, a business mgmt. degree, and am currently working on an advanced degree in psychology. I previously served one term on Borough Council’s vacancy board, I am an active member of Hatboro Rotary, and I am currently serving as the president of the Elm Street Philanthropic Board. I have volunteered around town with HAT Packs, The Union Library, the Hatboro Fall Festival, and as an EMT-B with Second Alarmers Rescue Squad. I work as a political consultant and volunteer as a Toys for Tots campaign coordinator and notary public."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_alex_myers","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Stormwater management is a top issue that continues to face our Borough that can be addressed in several ways, and I discuss some options for mitigation later in this questionnaire. The recent impact from Hurricane Ida highlighted some of our most vulnerable areas but also showed the resiliency of our residents, our emergency services, and our Public Works department. A recent survey attached to the Hatboro 2040 Comprehensive Plan also asked residents for their priorities with future community growth, with \"Historic Preservation\" coming in first. The current Council, the Historical Commission, the Planning Commission, and the Montgomery County Planning Commission and staff have been working to bring a Historic Overlay Ordinance to both protect our historic properties and preserve our history for years to come as we continue to grow. I look forward to continuing this effort and other efforts that directly address the needs of our residents."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_alex_myers","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Hatboro has a very active Chamber of Commerce that works to enrich our business community through events, networking opportunities, and other supportive programming, and we should continue to find ways to work in partnership with them. The Borough also includes a business spotlight in their social media and website, arranged a local networking event that was paused during the pandemic, and suspends parking meter payments throughout the year to encourage visitors to our main street and promote our local commerce. Along with encouraging these existing partnerships and programs, I plan to explore opportunities for enhancing our main street corridor and parks system. During a recent tour of the Eastern Center for Arts & Technology, I was able to learn more about their commercial art program and see a fantastic opportunity to partner with the students there on installations here in Hatboro, such as murals and memorials."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_alex_myers","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We will need to address the climate control of our Borough Hall, identify new property for our Public Works department, maintain our vital emergency services, and preserve and optimize the accessibility of our various parks. With the closing of Pennypack Elem. we should ensure that we reacquire this property and work with a commission to permanently preserve the property as open space and examine upgrading the facility to a community center. Oversight and enforcement of our stormwater management and drainage codes remain essential as we identify opportunities to convert existing impermeable surface areas to permeable within our business districts. Identifying grant opportunities for improvements is paramount to keeping the financial burden of these expenses from our various taxpayers. Flexibility in our lawn maintenance requirements should also be explored as summer heat, and annual rainfall will continue to rise, and higher vegetation growth can work to absorb and filter runoff. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_alex_myers","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Changes to marijuana laws coupled with restorative justice should continue to come from the State-level. With medical marijuana approved five years ago, over 300,000 Pennsylvanians have since registered to receive the medical benefits available. The costs remain prohibitive without approved insurance coverage, and current laws do not allow for home growth or allow for remediation of mold by extraction into new products. The majority of Pennsylvanians support the full legalization of marijuana, and I stand with them."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_alex_myers","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["34% of Pennsylvania's municipalities have enacted LGBTQ+ protections in housing, employment, and public accommodations while waiting for HB300 to come up for a vote in Harrisburg and while waiting for The Equality Act to become Federal law. Hatboro enacted its version of these protections in 2018, and I fully support their leadership in this action. As someone who directly experienced employment discrimination when I was honorably discharged under the since repealed \"Don't' Ask, Don't Tell\" policy, I have seen firsthand the lingering effects that discriminatory practices can take. As the first open member of the LGBTQ+ community to serve on Hatboro Council, I look forward to opportunities to facilitate education and understanding as an elected official."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_alex_myers","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support restrictions that follow the public health guidance regarding local transmission rates and the best available mitigation options. Throughout this pandemic, I have worked with other volunteers to help neighbors find appointments for vaccinations, have provided rides to appointments, volunteered at a local event with the Montgomery County Department of Health to administer shots at one of the HUD properties in our Borough, and as president of the Elm Street Philanthropic Board oversaw over $48,000 in donations to address food insecurity. I also watched my family-run business close its doors after 27 years and, like many of you, experienced several personal losses. As a member of this community and an elected official, I will continue to find ways for us to work together to minimize the negative impacts on our Borough, our families, and our businesses."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_thomas_rafferty","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["There is no such thing as a best candidate for Borough Council.  The Council is made up of seven members instead of one, so the ideal candidate is one who can work in a group environment.  ","During my 21 years in emergency management at the state level, I have worked with political and community leaders of both parties respond to and recover from major disasters.  I have listened to the community needs.  I have reached consensus with the political desires.  I have been a part of joint solutions to the most pressing concerns in a high stress, time sensitive environment.  These are similar skills that one needs to be a good Councilman."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_thomas_rafferty","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Keeping our small town character while managing population and economic growth is a key issue for Council.  We have a Main Street, historic buildings, and a train station as focal points of the Boro.  Our citizens live in single and multi-family homes, high rise towers, above stores, and in factories converted to condos.  Businesses include small shops, restaurants, bars, industrial, medical, and professional services.  In short, a vibrant community.","To maintain this our zoning code should be reviewed and strengthened.  We have a cluster of buildings that could be turned into an historic district.  Is this the right location for a gas station or are there better options?  We have a walkable Main Street.  Is this the right location for high rises or are there better options?  ","Growth is necessary to any town’s survival; smart growth is welcome.  For 315 years Hatboro has been growing. Managing our growth so that we continue to have a sense of place instead of just another suburb is key."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_thomas_rafferty","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We are fortunate to have a Main Street as our town center.  It is very important to keep that for future generations.  The challenge comes in attracting new growth to the Boro while keeping the Main Street Community vibrant.  ","The Boro recently adopted a 20 year comprehensive plan, Hatboro 2040, which I plan to follow.  It details recommendations from community and Boro leaders on how we should grow while keeping Main Street Main Street.  ","Hatboro has a high occupancy rate on York Road.  I grew up in a town where less than half the stores were occupied and experienced what that does to a community.  I will work with The Chamber of Commerce to help attract new businesses and stores.  They do an amazing job of organizing events every month of the year to attract people to shop local in town.  ","I would also like to attract a few more BYOB restaurants.  Having a State Store would help.  Numerous other small munis in our area have one, ours closed in 2018. Having one again would be a plus."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_thomas_rafferty","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We are an older town with aging roads and traffic signals.  Maintaining roads and replacing traffic control devices with modern more efficient signals is a service of municipal government that impacts our citizens quality of life.   Two intersections in town recently had their traffic signals upgraded to the latest technology.  One project was completed in short order, one project has taken over a year to complete.  Work was halted on the second project. Sidewalks sat roped off over a year to prevent people from falling in holes all because the railroad was not contacted, even though the intersection crosses train tracks.  Ensuring all stakeholders are a part of a project is in my background as an emergency manager, I would work ahead of time to make sure all are at the table.","Flood management is another need for the Boro.  As Ida recently reminded us, we are still vulnerable to significant flooding.  As a former member of a state hazard mitigation team I have the experience to help."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_thomas_rafferty","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["In 2020 the AAA Foundation for Traffic Safety issued a report that shows a significant increase drivers involved in fatal crashes testing positive for THC, the chemical in marijuana that causes most of the high. In the five years prior to Washington State legalizing marijuana for recreational use, 8% of drivers involved in fatal crashes tested positive for THC.  In the following five years that number increased to 18%.  ","In 2021 the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety released a study of crashes in CA CO NV OR and WA (states where marijuana laws were relaxed) versus other western states.  They found a 6% increase in injury crashes and 4% increase of fatal crashes in those states versus the others.","Medical marijuana typically has more CBD than THC. Those users typically feel the therapeutic affects without the high recreational users do.  In other words medical users get greater benefits with lower risks to public safety.  For those reasons I do not support further decriminalization."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_thomas_rafferty","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Happiness.  Founding words of our Nation.  Unalienable rights which apply to all Americans.  Sadly, there are times when those rights are denied, a limited government can step up to protect them.","In 2018 Council passed the Hatboro Borough Human Relations Ordinance.  It is a non-discrimination public policy which insures all persons, regardless of race, color, age, religious creed, ancestry, sex, national origin, handicap, use of guide or support animals, sexual orientation, gender identity, or gender expression enjoy the full benefits of citizenship.   ","Many more words than those famous seven in the Declaration of Independence to say the same.  An ordinance I support."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_thomas_rafferty","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I encourage everyone who is unvaccinated to talk to your doctor.  Not everyone can receive the vaccines, but if your doctor says it is safe for you, I encourage you to get the jab.  I work in emergency management, the work we’ve put into rolling out the vaccine was tough but rewarding.  It is one of the best tools to combat COVID-19. ","Supporting other mandates should be on a case by case basis at the time they come up and should be addressed at the local level.  A one size fits all mandate is not the best solution.  Something seemed illogical to me that I was legally allowed to drive over 400 miles to Erie without any restrictions but if I traveled just 40 miles to Delaware it was two weeks self quarantine.","One mandate I will oppose is lockdowns. The list Gov. Wolf dictated of non-essential jobs is one of the reasons I decided to run for office. Every job is essential, especially to the one who works it.  If it is safe enough to go to the grocery store it is safe enough to go anywhere."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_david_stockton","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["It has been my honor to serve as Hatboro’s Council Vice-President for the past four years and that time in office has proved invaluable. I also recently served as the co-chair of the Hatboro Steering Committee where I helped to create and adopt the Hatboro 2040 Comprehensive Plan.","","As a current council member, I am well-aware of the unique challenges our borough faces, as well as the opportunities for growth and improvement in our shared future. I am a dedicated, organized, and level-headed leader who is committed to making our community better for all of us. I hold a degree in Music Education from Indiana University of Pennsylvania and I have a strong background in management and education.","","I am extremely proud of the work I have done for our beautiful borough and this November I am humbly asking for the chance to continue that work on behalf of the wonderful residents and business owners of Hatboro."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_david_stockton","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["As the chair of the borough’s Finance Committee, it is sometimes difficult for me not to view Haboro’s challenges through the lens of dollars and cents. To me, improving the borough’s financial position to avoid wasteful spending or substantial tax increases is the most important thing that council members are empowered to do for our residents.","","With rising waste disposal fees, soaring healthcare costs, and a growing desire for more community services and events, balancing the budget in a responsible way is always challenging. Owing to successful contract negotiations, aggressive pursuit of grant funding, and the refinancing of existing debt at lower interest rates, Hatboro was one of the few municipalities that did not raise taxes during the pandemic.","","If re-elected, I plan to continue using responsible and innovative financial planning to give our residents the level of service they have come to expect without placing an unrealistic financial burden on our community."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_david_stockton","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["A thriving main street is a staple of any small town in American and Hatboro is no exception. Our diverse group of businesses along York Road and throughout the borough offer our residents a growing number of essential services, many of which are walkable and accessible via public transportation!","","With such a strong shift to online shopping, it is important for Hatboro to encourage unique and service-oriented businesses that simply cannot be replicated online. One of my first tasks in office was to establish a Business Spotlight - each month we draw attention to a different local business, helping to get the word out via Facebook and our website. Since then we have also added a business directory and a list of resources geared toward new business just starting out.","","This pro-business philosophy is already yielding results, with local favorites like Artifact Brewing, The Laboratory, and even our own Moose Lodge chapter joining the borough within the last few years."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_david_stockton","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Stormwater management continues to be one of the most pressing infrastructure challenges facing all of Pennsylvania. The recent aftermath of Hurricane Ida was a stark reminder that our changing climate continues to present new and difficult challenges for municipalities in our commonwealth. Fortunately, the borough has a comprehensive MS4 (municipal separate storm sewer systems) plan to address these issues.","","More frequent maintenance of our storm drains, a job handled by our dedicated public works department, helps to prevent flooding and keep our roads safe. Additionally, recent projects like the Eaton and Memorial Park streambank restorations help to mitigate runoff from the Pennypack Creek. ","","The costs to update our aging infrastructure are substantial, but can often be offset by grant funding, as was the case in the projects mentioned above. That is why I am committed to continually seeking out state and federal funding that can help lessen the financial burden on our borough."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_david_stockton","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While I personally have no significant objections to the decriminalization of marijuana, I believe that the issue should be decided and legislated at the state level. We are a commonwealth of laws, and local politicians should not be in the business of deciding which of our state’s laws should be enforced and which may be ignored."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_david_stockton","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In 2018 I proudly voted to extend Hatboro’s discrimination protections for our LGBTQ+ community. While they are certainly, and sadly, not our only marginalized community, my own experience has taught me that our LGBTQ+ neighbors face cruel behavior and harassment every day, and I believe we have a shared responsibility to put an end to it.","","It may sometimes feel like there are few things that we can all agree on anymore, but to me the kind and decent treatment of our fellow citizens is not up for debate, regardless of gender, race, status, age, religion, disability, or economic status. We are all Americans, and we all have a responsibility to look out for each other. Civil disagreement is part of what makes the United States such a wonderful place, and I sincerely hope that we can continue to remember that moving forward."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_david_stockton","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Perhaps the most frustrating element of this terrible pandemic has been how quickly the virus can mutate and spread. Despite increasing vaccination rates in our county, the Delta variant continues to move quickly throughout our population, often inflicting the worst harm on our most vulnerable citizens.","","From the start of the pandemic, I have been publicly committed to following the guidelines established by the CDC, the Pennsylvania Department of Health, and the Montgomery County Office of Public Health. I strongly believe that these experts are our best resource when it comes to mitigating COVID and protecting our families, friends, and neighbors. If cases continue to rise, I will support any and all reasonable measures that may help us defeat this awful virus."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_peggy_hanes","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I love where i live!"]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_peggy_hanes","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We need to re-energize Hatboro with more shopping options. I have lots of ideas I will share at a date. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_peggy_hanes","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Possible tax breaks"]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_peggy_hanes","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Flooding issues and the bridge on Warminster rd. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_peggy_hanes","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Marijuana is the least of our problems."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_peggy_hanes","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support protections for all of Hatboro’s citizens. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_council_peggy_hanes","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would not support local mandates. In a study by the CDC, they said that masks do not stop the virus from spreading  so why would I make someone wear something that does not work. "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_veronica_hill-milbourne","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have resided in Horsham with my family since 2003 and began serving on Horsham Council in January 2018.  I am devoted to serving my community and making Horsham an even better place to live and thrive.  I will take time to listen to the residents of Horsham and to understand those issues that are most important to those I seek to serve.  I will work tirelessly to improve the quality of life for the constituents of our community and to provide transparency within our local government."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_veronica_hill-milbourne","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing our community is the need to ensure the quality of life for all those living in Horsham.  When re-elected, I will continue working to ensure that our drinking water adheres to the strictest federal and state regulatory guidelines. I will act with care in my financial responsibility to avoid waste and keep taxpayer expense low. I will work with state and federal officials to secure funding to rebuild homes and businesses impacted by recent floods and weather related disasters.   I will continue to support legislation that improves and enhances our open spaces, business park development, and offers affordable housing options that  allow families to grow and thrive. I will also work to ensure that all constituents are safe, and have equal access to Township programs and services. In addition to the newly televised Township meetings, I will continue to explore new ways to keep community members informed and engaged through community partnerships and outreach.  "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_veronica_hill-milbourne","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will continue to support an active recruitment strategy and campaign to attract new businesses to Horsham.  I will work to promote the design of a central marketplace and public transportation system within in Horsham to encourage local entrepreneurship and business growth and development.  "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_veronica_hill-milbourne","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Horsham must continue to invest in environmentally sound and energy efficient alternatives to protect township such as storm water management solutions. I will continue to support remediation of the contaminated soil conditions and promote actions as necessary to ensure safe drinking water for all in Horsham.  I will promote the development of a public transportation system needed to support growth and business development.  With the loss of businesses in our township resulting from the closure of the Naval Airforce base, recent economic impacts of COVID 19 and weather related disasters, I will work tirelessly to support environment enhancement to our roadways and open spaces, new business development, affordable housing, and public transportation.  I will work with state and federal elected officials to  secure funding for redevelopment, enhancements to community programs and services."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_veronica_hill-milbourne","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would not support measures to decriminalize recreational marijuana use at this time. With the recent introduction of more marijuana dispensaries across the state, we need additional time to analyze the impacts to our community before we loosen penalties within our municipality. As a medical professional, I acknowledge the tremendous benefits that the use of marijuana has for those who suffer from medical conditions such as chronic pain and anxiety. I support those who have a medical certification to use medicinal marijuana.   There is also extensive research conducted by substance abuse experts that suggest that recreational use of marijuana should be viewed as a gateway drug that can pose serious consequences for those who maybe predisposed to addiction.  Thus, we must carefully review the data before attempting to amend the current legal ramifications associated with marijuana use.  "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_veronica_hill-milbourne","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support equal protections under the law for all residents of Horsham regardless of sex, sexual orientation, identity and/or sexual preference."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_veronica_hill-milbourne","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a Registered Nurse practicing for over 30 years, I have researched and trust the science behind the effectiveness of masks in preventing the spread of the coronavirus.  As a healthcare professional who has been battling the COVID 19 pandemic since March of 2020, I support other scientifically validated restrictions that will halt the spread of the coronavirus.  I have witnessed countless deaths associated with the coronavirus and support all efforts to prevent the loss of life of innocent children and adults due to COVID 19.  I have personally witnessed the effectiveness of adhering to the recommendations of the Centers for Disease Control (CDC) in preventing the spread of COVID 19 and I would support a local mask mandate.  "]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_joanne_cunningham","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have lived in this community for 30 years and I feel that the current board is no longer putting the needs of the residents at the forefront of their decisions.  A one-party perspective now runs the township and balance needs to be restored. As director at three different schools, I took on additional responsibilities including resource management, budget planning and allocation.  I understand the importance of listening – not only to  students but to parents and staff - to ensure I implemented the best path forward that benefited the most people. I will bring that same dedication, commitment and experience to my position as Township Supervisor and serve everyone in my community.  I will bring balance back to the township leadership and ensure that the needs of our community are heard and addressed.  And most importantly, I do not desire this position for a political future or to promote any political agenda.  I am running to serve the community I have lived in for so many years."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_joanne_cunningham","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing our township is the foreclosure of the Montgomery Mall in the heart of our township.  The uncertainty of the future of this site is in every resident's mind.  It provides jobs, business revenue and is a shopping destination for our community and surrounding communities.  I plan to address the revitalization of this site by hiring a consulting firm that has worked with revitalizing outdated malls and determine the needs of the community and create a strategic vision project.  I would also ensure that this work would include direct community/committee work.  It would be of the utmost importance that the mall site be revitalized to meet the needs of families and residents in 2020+."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_joanne_cunningham","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I would partner with businesses to help meet their needs and support them to the fullest extent possible.  I would support business growth with tax incentives.  I would also demonstrate to businesses how the culture of our community would help their business grow and thrive.  Business is the tax base of a community and needs to be encouraged and supported.  "]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_joanne_cunningham","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The major infrastructure needs in my township are creating better traffic flow, updating intersections along Route 309 with better turning lanes, and creating safer pedestrian walkways throughout the township.  I would partner with PennDot to address these issues. I would also partner with businesses and landowners to develop safe pedestrian walkways along high traffic corridors like Horsham Road and North Wales Road.  At a recent township vision planning meeting I attended, traffic, congestion and pedestrian walkways were identified as top issues of concern with township residents."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_joanne_cunningham","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would uphold the laws currently in place.  A key component to being a township supervisor is keeping the community safe.  This position does not legislate law and I would not support any new law that creates an unsafe environment in my community."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_joanne_cunningham","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support treating every person fairly and equitably.  Our township created a Human Relations Commission in 2021.  The purpose of the commission was to ensure that all who work or live in Montgomery Township and all visitors, are protected from unlawful discrimination.  Our township is at the cutting edge of creating a safe and inclusive community free from discrimination."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_joanne_cunningham","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would follow the mandates put forth by local and state entities as required by law. I also support an individuals right to make their own choices related to their health.  A person's health is private and between themselves and their physician. I also support a business owner's right to continue or not to continue to operate their business as they so choose during this time.  A person's rights, guaranteed by the Constitution of the United States, do not disappear under these circumstances."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_2_karla_d'alessio","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a professionally certified project manager, formally-trained executive leader, staff manager, and PSU-educated scientist I have a lifetime of professional experience to dedicate to my community.  I am a 30yr property owner with an established history of advocating for my neighborhood at Board of Commissioners meetings.   I want to serve and preserve Hatfield Township.",""]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_2_karla_d'alessio","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Hatfield is losing open space at an alarming rate due to over development.  I will vote to preserve open space and protect taxpayers facing increasing school property taxes propelled by new development.  I favor sensible development and will not rubber stamp excessive variances.  I will require developers to improve roads, walkways, and stormwater runoff worsened by their projects."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_2_karla_d'alessio","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I advocate for Smart Growth so the community gets the benefits of jobs and new businesses, but at the same time protecting open space by planning more effectively for traffic flow and ensuring growth doesn't create more taxes for residents.  "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_2_karla_d'alessio","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Congestion is impacting our ability to travel our roadways safely and quickly.  I will look for opportunities to improve dangerous intersections by leveraging state and local grants and by appropriately leveraging CARES act funding.  I will work with local fire and police to ensure their facilities get the support and funding they need to continue to serve our community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_2_karla_d'alessio","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am an advocate for the benefits of medical marijuana (e.g. pain, anxiety, glaucoma, seizure, fibromyalgia, etc.).  As a taxpayer concerned with sustaining revenue at the state level, I support its legalization in PA."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_2_karla_d'alessio","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I speak publicly to challenge homophobia, biphobia, and transphobia and to advance the rights of all people.  I will work to pass a nondiscrimination ordinance in Hatfield as it relates to LBGBTQIA equality."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_township_commissioner_ward_2_karla_d'alessio","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do support County and State Health department recommendations on mask use and other restrictions as necessary if cases rise.  As a trained scientist and former executive leader for a major healthcare company I know the benefits science and vaccines offer to our society and support sensible precautions aimed at protecting everyone's health."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_rick_miniscalco","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a registered Professional Civil Engineer. I graduated from Villanova University. I have run a successful construction company for the past 30 plus years and managed people and budgets over that time for projects up to 10 million dollars. Most of the projects in the township are related to construction, engineering and cost. I have previously served on the North Penn School Board and Montgomery Township Board of Supervisors."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_rick_miniscalco","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing Montgomery Township is maintaining our quality of life. In these economically challenging times. Revenues are going to be down compared to recent years and it will take long range planning to provide for the most important job of a supervisor which is maintaining the public's safety."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_rick_miniscalco","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Montgomery Township has grown very quickly since the late 1980's. The township is basically built out which means there is very little open ground for development. We need to acquire open space when it becomes available. The township is changing from a developed community to a redeveloping community. Most of our revenues will come from redevelopment. We must work with businesses to make it attractive for them to invest here."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_rick_miniscalco","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Because the township grew so quickly the traffic infrastructure has been difficult to keep up. The traffic infrastructure is the number one update needed. We have to work with our elected officials to make sure we get our fair share of state and federal taxes earmarked for transportation."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_rick_miniscalco","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Decriminalizing marijuana is beyond the scope of township supervisor."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_rick_miniscalco","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["When you take the oath of a township supervisor you pledge to uphold the laws of the state and federal governments. The constitution of both bodies guarantees the rights of all citizens and as an elected official I would support these laws."]},{"candidateCode":"montgomery_township_supervisor_rick_miniscalco","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["If the state or federal government mandated a legal mask requirement, based on the science then I would support following the mandate."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_nicole_spiese","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am engaged with residents to understand their needs and I am actively involved in the community. I am good at working with others who might have a different viewpoint than myself."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_nicole_spiese","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We have some red tape when it comes to getting new businesses in the borough and resolving problems that residents have. I actively talk to the new businesses and residents to understand what works and what doesn't. If elected I would work with the borough manager and Council to better understand the process of resolving problems."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_nicole_spiese","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As a board member of the non-profit that oversees the Telford Night Market we as a board try to encourage local businesses and non-profits to attend the market to promote their businesses. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_nicole_spiese","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["I would need to work with the public works division to better understand what needs to be prioritized for infrastructure such as road repairs and replacement of piping. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_nicole_spiese","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would not decriminalize marijuana because that should be a federal decision, not a local. However, if someone is caught with a small amount I wouldn't seek to penalize them too hard if it is a first offense."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_nicole_spiese","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Difficult question because we have a mix of people in the borough who are very conservative and many who are very liberal. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_nicole_spiese","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would follow state and federal guidelines for public spaces regarding mask mandates."]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_council_daniel_bencsik","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My leadership and communications skills give me the tools I need to best serve the constituency.  I just finished up serving a 3 year term on my trade associations board of directors and am currently serving as the President of the ARIEF education foundation.  I have a unique ability to understand the past while planning for "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_council_daniel_bencsik","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Maintaining the momentum the borough has achieved in the past few years while developing and implementing a new strategic vision for the borough that incorporates the changing reality we are facing with regards to the changing climate while maximizing the opportunities for those who work and live in the borough. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_council_daniel_bencsik","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Continuing to support Souderton Connects and the Business Improvement District and being an advocate for the borough to attract new companies to do business here.  There is some space opening up in town that would be very attractive to many different companies.  The Main Street and Arts District have a great core to build on.  Maintaining the unique cultural district and advocating for the businesses in town are two ways to help support business growth in Souderton"]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_council_daniel_bencsik","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["As storms become more severe in their impacts, doing what we can to develop plans for the new realities of storms that bring more water and ways to mitigate the damage done to properties in the borough needs to be a priority.  By developing an environmental working group comprised of the various stakeholders and working with our state officials, we can mitigate the worst effects of these severe weather events that are becoming more common place.  ","","Souderton staff does a wonderful job with clearing our roads after snow storms and our sewage treatment plant continues to be vital infrastructure component that needs to be maintained."]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_council_daniel_bencsik","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["With the proliferation of medical marijuana in the state, our current marijuana laws are antiquated and in need of review.  I support efforts to decriminalize and loosen penalties for marijuana in the municipality and more broadly in the state. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_council_daniel_bencsik","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Minorities of all kinds should be supported at all levels of government.  Part of what makes our community such a wonderful place to put down roots is the cultural diversity.  Ensuring that LGBTQ+ people feel safe and welcome in the town they live and work in should be a priority.  Working with the LGBTQ+ community to develop ways to make Souderton a more inclusive and welcoming place would be one way to support LGBTQ+ protections. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_council_daniel_bencsik","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID-19 continues to be the most important economic issue we face today.  I support following the science and listening to the experts with regards to mask mandates and other restrictions.  If the science supports masking or other restrictions than we should be following their recommendations.  Making vaccines available to kids 5-12 would be a great step towards putting this pandemic behind us and giving our town the most opportunity for growth!"]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_w._william_whiteside","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been a Horsham Councilman since 2000.  I have overseen the construction of numerous municipal buildings, an award winning library, acquired over 900 acres of open space, built a high quality trail system and only raised taxes twice in the last 21 years keeping Horsham's taxes among the lowest around.  We have a AAA bond rating and at one time was rated by CNN as the 34th best place to live in America."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_w._william_whiteside","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Horsham is a great place to live.  Our top issue is providing outstanding fire and municipal services for our residents at the lowest possible cost.  We work closely with every business and developer to ensure that they do their part to contribute to that success."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_w._william_whiteside","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We work closely with our business parks to ensure that they provide high quality spaces and services at reasonable prices.  We help ensure that there are quality amenities for both businesses and employees in our business parks."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_w._william_whiteside","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["In preparation for the Navy Base redevelopment we need major road improvements.  Serving on the MIRIA board helps put some of the funding in place to implement that development."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_w._william_whiteside","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["This issue is addressed at the state level."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_w._william_whiteside","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In Horsham, people are free to be whoever they want to be without discrimination."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_w._william_whiteside","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I'm sad to see that there is such a battle over mask wearing. I see it as a public safety issue rather than a rights issue. And even though most will survive COVID if infected some will not. I believe it is everyone's responsibility to protect those who might not and mask wearing has proved effective.  However, I do not believe the Federal or State Constitution gives a township the authority to institute a mask mandate other than on Township property."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_theresa_harmon","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been a resident of Horsham Township for over 21 years and have been an active member throughout most of my time here.  In addition to years of volunteering in the community, I have also served 14 years as a Committee Person serving District 2-3, two terms on The Hatboro Horsham School Board serving as The Policy Committee Chair and a member of the Curriculum Committee.  Currently, as a Senate appointee, I serve as the treasurer to The MIRIA Board, (Military Installation Remediation and Infrastructure Authority), formed to assist in the reimbursement of the cost of remediating PFC contamination associated with military installations.  I am running for Horsham Council so I may continue the great work of Horsham Council while working with the community to progress with the times in remaining competitive with neighboring townships & communities, while keeping taxes low and open space abundant."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_theresa_harmon","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue, as stated above, is to remain competitive, especially with the new climate that Covid has forced us into.  Having the ability to evolve in today’s \"new normal\" with smart infrastructure in and around our residential community and business campus will allow Horsham to remain competitive while continuously supporting our residents.  And furthermore, maintaining a strong community support system during difficult times so as to serve as a safety net for our residents."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_theresa_harmon","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will support business growth by remaining open to new ideas, studying other successful townships, boroughs and communities, all while maintaining open space, community safety and fiscal responsibility."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_theresa_harmon","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["As Horsham grows, so must our infrastructure.  Streets will need to modified, traffic signals added, etc... to accommodate increased traffic patterns for seamless flow and safety while traveling throughout the Horsham township."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_theresa_harmon","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While I have a personal point of view on this issue, a change on this scale would be made on the State and/or Federal level, therefore I will defer to their legislation.  "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_theresa_harmon","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support protections for all, regardless of age, gender, race, religion or sexual orientation."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_theresa_harmon","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support reviewing science based studies & statistics prior to bolstering a broad, one size fits all, mandate for Horsham residents."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_2_years_john_waldenberger","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a life long resident of the area. I am not someone who has been sitting on the council for multiple years and would be coming in as an average citizen who wants to improve  and grow our community. ","","Being a Libertarian, I am neither \"Left nor Right\". I am there for the rights of the individual. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_2_years_john_waldenberger","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Transparency: I do not feel that there is enough of it. Many residents, including myself did not learn of the new Borough hall until AFTER the purchase was approved. ","","Our residents need to have better access and visibility into what our elected officials are doing in our town. ","","Some solutions include Active Social media, with regular updates. Live streaming of Council and committee meetings. ","","Better practices to notify residents of upcoming projects, especially ones that will affect us with road closures. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_2_years_john_waldenberger","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As a business owner I find that support from the local government is key to success. Some ideas that would help include:","","Offering Free/reduced Advertising space on the borough website/social media","","Creating a welcome Packet that is sent to any new residents that includes a guide or fliers from local businesses. ","","Find burdensome regulations/ordinances that might discourage a business to want to make roots in town. Be that zoning, licensing, etc. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_2_years_john_waldenberger","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Sidewalks need a major overhaul. Many, aside from ones affected by recent construction, are severely deteriorated or uneven.  "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_2_years_john_waldenberger","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["ABSOLUTELY 100% without a doubt. ","","This is not just because I am a Libertarian, but because I believe that all individuals have the right to consume what ever they choose. They are the ones who have to accept the natural consequences. ","","If tobacco and alcohol (both of which are derived from plants) which are more likely to cause harm are constitutionally \"legal\", then there is no reason a plant (Marijuana) that has proven health benefits should not be. ","","I would take that a step further and include decriminalization for NON-VIOLENT possession of other drugs. We need to encourage addiction recovery and treatment, over jail. Locking up someone does not solve the problem, and often leads to bigger issues down the road. ","","No Victim, No Crime. Addiction is NOT A CRIME.  ","","Laws written with the purpose of incarcerating or imposing fines for sake of revenue generation are not laws that are truly meant to protect our rights. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_2_years_john_waldenberger","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely. ","","The Civil Rights Act of 1964 should apply to discrimination of LGBT/GSM (Gender-Sexual Minorities) as well. At the time it was written, things were different and still changing. It is disappointing that our elected legislators have not fixed this issue. ","","The constitution of the US and Pennsylvania guarantee us the rights to LIFE, LIBERTY, THE PURSUIT OF HAPPINESS. Discrimination against anyone for something beyond their control, for who they are is just morally wrong. ","","Discrimination against anyone for their age, gender, orientation, etc. does not infringe upon your personal rights and freedom, but it keeps them from exercising their basic rights as humans. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_2_years_john_waldenberger","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID mandates are such a divisive issue that could be settled with common sense. You have scientific facts as to how viruses and vaccines work. You have competing opinions based on emotion or personal experiences. ","","As stated above I support freedom of individuals to do what they feel is best for themselves, however as a Libertarian, we follow something called the Non-Aggression Principle. Putting people at risk or harm is a violation of their rights and a violation of the NAP. ","","PUBLIC schools - I support mask mandates, you do not have the right to put your child in harms way, or other children. You have the right to put your child in a private school/homeschool. ","","Government Buildings- Same. Consider the rights of everyone who enters.","","PRIVATE BUSINESSES/PROPERTY: I DO NOT support the mandates. It is the responsibility of the property owner to do what they feel is best for themselves and their clients/employees. They also subject to natural consequences of their actions. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_bill_gottshall","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Above all else, I've been proud of my ability to get things done. Meetings have a way of perpetuating inaction. Too often action is tabled, as people in leadership \"kick the can down the alley,\" to avoid making a decision or taking a stand. While I believe that both major political parties share some of the blame for the gridlock we're experiencing right now in government, I'm running as a Democrat because I believe our party has the most forward-thinking policies, especially in regard to climate change. People in leadership positions must act now to save our world from catastrophic changes in the environment. The time for talking about our differences is over; it's time to take decisive action.",""]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_bill_gottshall","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Beginning the long process of creating a carbon-neutral community, doing so in a way that won't hurt our local economy. If elected, I will help Telford's homeowners and business owners access the information and make the connections they need to begin transforming our town.  "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_bill_gottshall","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We need to stop thinking only about \"how things were done in the past,\" and begin thinking \"how can local government help our businesses adapt their operations in a technology-driven world?\" I like the example of Akron, Ohio. The local government created an app, \"Akronite,\" which points residents FIRST to local businesses which offer the services or goods they need. If we want local businesses to compete with Amazon and other online behemoths, we need to put the necessary tools in their hands."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_bill_gottshall","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We should continue with the gradual improvements being made to Telford's water & sewer systems. We also need to keep up with street and alley resurfacing, but the borough should do a better job of communicating with residents about these repairs. In the recent past, the process has been too haphazard and little or no notice has been given to local residents about when & where the work will be done. "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_bill_gottshall","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. Marijuana use and alcohol use create very similar chemical reactions in the human brain, therefore their use should be subject to the same regulations and treatment under the law. And the abuse of either should be subject to the same strict penalties. Whenever an individual becomes impaired by drug or alcohol use and endangers the safety of others, it's our duty to protect citizens from harm. With personal freedom comes personal responsibility and government has a duty to enforce that personal responsibility."]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_bill_gottshall","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. All people, regardless of gender orientation, race, or religion deserve equal protection under the law. And they deserve equal respect and courtesy from the entire community. Local government has an obligation to see that these standards are consistently enforced.    "]},{"candidateCode":"telford_council_4_years_bill_gottshall","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. While individual freedoms have always been an essential part of American society, the health and welfare of all citizens must be our primary concern. If that means a particular individual freedom must be temporarily suspended in order to protect the public health, then that's the way it must be. Individual freedoms only mean something when we're alive and healthy to enjoy them.   "]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_sean_wade","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I was born and raised in Horsham. I have seen it grow and the issues that come with it. I enlisted in the Marine Corps at 18 and served for a decade, traveling throughout Asia, learning solutions for a multitude of problems. I am back in Horsham where I am attending Villanova University and hope to empower my community for a better tomorrow."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_sean_wade","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our top issue is safe drinking water and Willow Grove NAS being handed over in a manner that is safe and in the best interests of our community."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_sean_wade","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Horsham has always welcomed businesses as the plethora of campuses show. I plan on continuing to reinforce good building practices for people wanting to call Horsham home and provide accommodating conditions for businesses wanting to move in and those who are already here."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_sean_wade","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Like previously stated, it is crucial for Horsham residents to have safe drinking water and land. Therefore, the federal government has to hand over the base in a manner that is approved by the residents and officials."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_sean_wade","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Horsham does not have the authority to determine state and federal cannabis laws and will defer to the state and federal legislature."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_sean_wade","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["As a Marine, I deployed to various places around the globe to protect those who cannot protect themselves and to provide a voice for the silenced. I support the individual rights guaranteed in the U.S. Constitution and will ensure Horsham protects those rights."]},{"candidateCode":"horsham_council_sean_wade","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID-19 has been an unprecedented event and any hypothetical situation without data analysis would not be fair. I will, however, use the critical thinking and analytical skills I learned as a Marine to formulate the best response for our community."]},{"candidateCode":"mercersburg_borough_council_paul_sipes","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I listen carefully to people and their thoughts and use information from the library to make decisions to try and help people.  I have a great balance of freedom and personal responsibility as well as a clear understanding that we operate as a collective.  I don't sugarcoat much, but think I am generally fair and honest.  I have been places and seen things and know that \"it's the way we have always done it\" and \"we can't do that\" are not really reasons to not consider an undertaking, especially when other places have already accomplished more."]},{"candidateCode":"mercersburg_borough_council_paul_sipes","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["Our tax base is small and our budget is also small.  I have been working with the Mercersburg Vibrancy Steering Committee to expand the viability of our town for business growth and increased property values.  It is important, and difficult given the tax structure in PA, to keep supporting people who want to buy, and fix-up old houses in Mercersburg.  Demolition by neglect can be a dangerous and pervasive issue and persists in areas where it is allowed to continue."]},{"candidateCode":"mercersburg_borough_council_paul_sipes","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["One of our major opportunities is agri-tourism and this requires places to stay and things to do.  I have been working with local business owners to seize on this and to help spread the word about the hometown feeling of Mercersburg to all those people stuck in the nearby cities.  We have a great distillery, fun Pub, a great coffee shop that is expanding, and I am excited to see more options for short term stays in town to support visitors to Mercersburg Academy and to provide convenient, clean and comfortable lodging for the visitors to Whitetail Mountain Resort who we enjoy all year long. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_third_ward_dom_brown","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["What makes me the best candidate is that my background is from US Army, serving and protecting the citizens of the USA. Then I was a DA Civilian working for the government as well as giving my time to the community with multiple events. Next a defense contractor working with many people from all walks of life learning concerns and issues and problem solving them to ensure the mission was complete correctly and in a timely fashion. Then as a Director of Public Works in Maryland learning and improving the process of maintaining a city. And last but not least being a unifier understanding the issues and understanding how to problem solve issues and concerns.  "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_third_ward_dom_brown","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["Southgate Shopping Center is an issue that is important in Ward 3. ","How to address it is first bring in the community to find out the needs of the entire borough not just ward 3. Create a avenue of how to solve the issue, by reaching out to local developers, stakeholders, investors, and all local business of future businesses that may or may not go in there. Meet with town manager at the same time to figure out restrictions, utilities and repairs. Next meet with all levels of government: County Commissioners, State Representative, State Senator, and Congressmen to have on board of what is happing in the county for the future. Once we have met all requirements and everyone is on the same page bring the community back and let them know where you are in the process and keeping them informed through the entire process so they will know who is invested in their community. Finally its ground breaking and time to go to work to rebuild or repair the Southgate shopping center. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_third_ward_dom_brown","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["Transparency is the next issue.","How to be more transparent inform the community on everything that is going on small repairs and issues and large projects. As well as explain where all of your tax dollars and fees are going to. for example if there is lets say an Ambulance Fee of $2.00 a month breakdown what the $2.00 are allocated to: 10% to new equipment, 20% training, 30% salary and 40% fuel cost. Have this ready before fee or tax is even taken from the resident. Also i believe if residents had more knowledge of what's going on in their borough they would be more incline to attending more meetings and to be more involved in the process after all we are elected by the people and work for the people so they should know all decisions are based on their needs and revenue.  "]},{"candidateCode":"waynesboro_borough_council_first_ward_john_d._poniske","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I believe I am highly qualified for this position because of my diverse background. I am a US Marine veteran - Vietnam Era. I have owned and operated several creative businesses. I hold a Bachelor's and a Master's Degree in American history. I am a retired English/History teacher - having taught in an alternative school setting. I am a published author. I have lived in five different states while having traveled to all fifty states and three dozen foreign countries. I believe in listening to and acting on voter concerns to the best of my ability. It has always been my belief that one should always help one's neighbor when at all possible. I believe in growth, diversity and compassion. I have come to love the town I have lived in for almost 20 years - the longest I have lived anywhere in my life - and hope to help it grow."]},{"candidateCode":"waynesboro_borough_council_first_ward_john_d._poniske","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["I have spent the last two months meeting with borough leaders, discussing how the borough is run and what problems it faces. I have come away with three key problems facing our community. 1) Our poverty level, 2) Deteriorating infrastructure and 3) Shrinking volunteerism. Folks are having a hard time finding jobs with liveable wages. New and diverse businesses should be sought to settle in the area, to rejuvenate our economy and our standard of living. I seek to actively promote Waynesboro, not only a destination for art and music, but for food & drink, culture and history. I want improve our outlook for volunteerism. I now volunteer at my church, the homeless shelter, the library and the Institute. I am also officiating at a GOOD NEIGHBOR BLOCK PARTY on October 30th to promote volunteerism and disseminate information on the many wonderful service organizations in our community."]},{"candidateCode":"waynesboro_borough_council_first_ward_john_d._poniske","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["Another serious problem facing the borough is deteriorating infrastucture.  We have a good deal of Covid Relief money coming into the Borough. The business community has specific needs in order to be able to grow and prosper their operations - broadband access, completely reliable cell phone services, attractive and well-maintained roads and public places and municipal services. I want to be on the decision-making end of seeing that money put to use on failing infrastructure: roads, storm drains, etc.,  and to the extent that it can be - used to beautify our little town. Additionally, there is is significant interest in supporting and expanding the use of renewable energy sources, such as solar and wind power, bringing high-tech jobs and cheaper power to the area."]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_fifth_ward_brendan_bittle","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I am the best candidate for this position because I am the most qualified. I have a Bachelor's in Economics and Finance and a Master's in Data Analytics and Management. The fact of the matter is we need people in office with expertise to make our borough run efficiently and cost-friendly for everyone not just for the few. Additionally, I am the only candidate for this position currently working right in the 5th Ward in a position of community service. I know our community, I was raised right here in the 5th Ward, and I have the skillset and proper preparation to fill this position. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_fifth_ward_brendan_bittle","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["The top two issues I see in our borough are a lack of community engagement, as well as a need for more efficient and cost-effective management. The lack of community engagement is self-evident when I speak to so many community members who do not even know who their councilmembers are, the benefits living in the borough brings to all of us, or the resources directly available to them as a resident in the Borough of Chambersburg. My objective is to continue to foster direct community engagement with all in our Borough to promote Chambersburg and be present and representative as an ambassador to our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_fifth_ward_brendan_bittle","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["The second issue facing our Borough is working towards running it more efficiently and cost-effective. My background is in economics, finance, and data analytics and management. This is a new skillset that I do not believe anyone on council has brought to the table before. I want to continue to usher Chambersburg into the 21st century behind logical and sensible changes to the way we spend money. We must have a council prepared to make the financial decisions necessary to help all in our borough thrive, and I hope to be able utilize my skillset to do so. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_first_ward_heidi_frye","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["My family and I have lived in Chambersburg for almost eight years and we love it here! I feel called to serve the First Ward, and the Borough as a whole, by offering a perspective that values history but also brings fresh energy to the task. Chambersburg has so much to offer its residents as well as visitors--a friendly, safe, diverse, and thriving community. But we must also look forward and envision its future. I have many years of professional (and personal) experience listening to, working with, and advocating for people of varied backgrounds, races, ethnicities, socioeconomic, developmental, and gender and sexual identities. I also have extensive experience managing and leading people of all ages. I have had to work in fast-paced, complex environments and know I can bring my many skills to Borough Council to aid in managing today's needs and concerns while helping issue our community into a strong and vibrant future. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_first_ward_heidi_frye","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["Chambersburg has a wonderful downtown district and its location along I-81 attracts businesses interested in developing in our area. This brings jobs and tax dollars and improved infrastructure. I believe Chambersburg's continued vibrancy and a secure future rely on strong and smart economic development. We have opportunities to continue to fill our downtown and surrounding business districts with shops, restaurants, and services that meet the varied needs and interests of our diverse community while also supporting those long-term business owners who have dedicated themselves to Chambersburg. I believe it is a challenge to find the right balance and I am looking forward to helping ask tough questions and listen to our constituents to arrive at decisions that will be good for our community. While I have no specific plan to address this expansive topic, I do believe my strong listening skills and empathy and concern for wise and just spending will be a benefit to our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_first_ward_heidi_frye","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["In Chambersburg, as in our nation, we are faced with a lack of unity. Our community was built on neighborly connections and a love for our town. However, our community has also changed over its history--a fact we cannot ignore. Demographics have and are shifting and we cannot only look to the past, longing for the way things were. Chambersburg's future relies on us supporting and lifting up all voices. I have heard many people say what a friendly community we live in, and I experience that truth every day. This makes us uniquely positioned to be accepting, loving, and supportive of one another. We have a foundation to stand on to come together, even when we disagree, and demonstrate for other communities that we are a force for progress and good. I am a person who lives to connect with people--all people--and I will bring that openness and collaborative spirit to my work on Borough Council. "]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle_borough_council_wade_g._burkholder","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I make decisions after studying an issue, and determining what I feel is best for a long term solution. I am not seeking the office of Borough Council to see how I can financially enhance myself or a business that I have ownership in.  I believe in \"life cycle costing\" when making major purchases.  I have no \"axes to grind\".  No hidden agendas.  And, no petty issues to exploit.  As a professional communicator, I know how to interact with people in a respectful and positive manner. One learns by listening.  I want open communication with everyone.  Whether in a public meeting setting, or talking with a citizen one to one.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle_borough_council_wade_g._burkholder","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["Small town Greencastle has to deal with the same issues, as larger metropolitan areas ..... just on a lesser scale. Let me address police protection, fire protection, and emergency rescue service. For generations, most of fire protection as well as emergency transportation was provided by an all volunteer staff.  With changing life styles, and enhanced family obligations the pool of \"free\" resources continues to dwindle.  Thus, the need for paid, fully trained professionals. Funds must be assured to Rescue Hose Company to adequately provide necessary emergency services.  This guaranteed revenue is generated with monies assessed via municipal taxes earmarked to RHC for every ones protection.  Same for police protection.  A safe community needs an adequately staffed ..... properly trained contingent of police officers. Up to date equipment, and thorough training for proper use is a must.  Again, the need for tax dollars to be assessed and earmarked for the community's safety.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"greencastle_borough_council_wade_g._burkholder","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["Greencastle's infrastructure has not been updated with a planned program over the years. The need to address this has become a major issue, recently. Sewer and water lines are the Borough's responsibility to maintain.  We all want a safe and convenient source of water.  As well as a free flowing sewer system.  Council as a whole needs to put a long term plan in place, and each year do an adequate amount of replacement.  As a council member I'd help with developing such a plan, and give input on how to make it successful.  All major issues need to be a full Council effort.  Everyone needs to have a voice, and give positive input. The above issues cannot be addressed by any one individual. They need to have thoughtful joint insight.  As a person that has rehabbed numerous older properties over the years I feel I can offer a lot of qualified thought into making an improvement plan .... both workable and affordable.  Greencastle is a wonderful community.  We need to keep it that way!"]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_fourth_ward_larry_b._hensley","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I am a conservative that wants to help improve Chambersburg. I have had years of Supervisor positions through my career. I have served on HOA Board as Secretary. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_fourth_ward_larry_b._hensley","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["Traffic is a major issue with speeders. One thing that would help are to have 4 way stops in those problem areas. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_fourth_ward_larry_b._hensley","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["Infrastructure on some of the roads and alley ways. Work with Planning and Development to address these issues. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_first_ward_allen_b._coffman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I am currently on Borough Council and have served my ward and borough for almost 28 years.  I have been a council person, Vice President of Council, Council President, and an Acting Mayor during that time.  My involvement with the committees is far reaching.  I have served on the Recreation Committee, the Planning and Zoning Commision, the Board of Health Committee,  the Parking, Traffic, and Street Light Committee, the Airport Committee, and also, I'm currently the Council's Human Resources representative.  ","Residency in my ward spans over thirty years.  I am now retired from the workforce and devote much of my time to serving the citizens of my ward and the borough.  As an enlisted person I have served my country in the Army Reserve for 35 years, retiring as a Command Sergeant Major.  My civilian career was devoted to mechanical design work, sales, and management.  There is no one else on Borough Council that has as much experience as me!",""]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_first_ward_allen_b._coffman","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["The first issue that is a concern is to maintain our precious Borough utilities that we offer.  We operate all the utilities within the borough with only a few exceptions.  While they are all important, our electric and natural gas are dependent on obtaining the best pricing from a national market.  We are one of thirty-five communities in Pennsylvania to operate our own electric utility.  Chambersburg has the second lowest cost of electric power in our state.  I want to keep us involved and make sure we stay as a low-cost power provider.  Our gas utility is another important area which saves our citizens money.  Our rates are currently about one half of those outside our borough.  In conclusion, all our utilities are valuable to our citizens.  Both gas and electric are supported by large energy providers.  We need to be on the proven cutting edge of these sources to provide the best for our businesses and citizens. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_first_ward_allen_b._coffman","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["The second issue of concern is the future development and redevelopment inside our borough.  We are now involved in developing a new comprehensive plan to guide us for the next ten years.  The final plan will probably be in print early next year.  Our community is nearly built out with the exception of the southwest corner of town.  It would appear that it will remain as farmland for the immediate future.  This could develop into another area of housing.  The future of South Gate Shopping Center has been a topic of many discussions recently.  While I believe this 14 acres of real estate needs revitalization, I do not believe it is the purpose of local government to use COVID funds to buy real estate and hope a developer will want to invest in the project.  Citizens should not have to fund this.  These costs belong to a developer not tax payers.  Also a special zoning district is being considered.  Will it be too restrictive?  Stay tuned to see how this will turn out.  "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_third_ward_barbara_beattie","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?","response":["I am a native of Chambersburg and am familiar with the town's history and evolution. I have nearly four years of experience on Borough Council and can build upon the  good relationships I have established with residents, businesses and Borough staff. "]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_third_ward_barbara_beattie","question":"What are the top two issues facing your borough or your ward, and what are your plans to address them? Please discuss one issue in this space and the other issue in the space below. ","response":["The redevelopment of Southgate Shopping Center will be the biggest challenge and opportunity since the development of the Norland Avenue business center. It is essential that this long-range revitalization project meets the needs of the growing community and reflects positively on Chambersburg and the third ward. I will work to to ensure this project is realistic and fiscally responsible."]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_borough_council_third_ward_barbara_beattie","question":"Question two, continued: What is the second issue facing your borough or ward, and what are your plans to address it?","response":["Living and doing business in the Borough must be affordable. I support forward-looking investments in utilities (including electric, natural gas and solar power) that lower costs for working families, retirees, young adults, businesses and industries. The Borough has made tremendous strides in these areas during my years on Council and I will continue to support them."]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_mayor_james_kinton","question":"Why are your the best choice for this office? ","response":["I am the best choice to be the next mayor of Chambersburg because I am the only candidate that will seek to serve the people of this community first. I am not a politician and will work to serve the residents and businesses of the community. As a Libertarian my priorities are protecting the freedoms of individuals and minimizing the impact of government in your personal life."]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_mayor_james_kinton","question":"What will be your top priority if elected, and what will you do to address it?","response":["The primary job of the mayor is to supervise the police department. My top priority when elected mayor will be to ensure that policing is done to keep our community safe and not as a means for profiting the government. I would seek to support police by developing partnerships with healthcare organizations to provide on-call professionals to help intervene in mental health/ substance abuse crisis situations."]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_mayor_kenneth_hock","question":"Why are your the best choice for this office? ","response":["My love and passion for Chambersburg and the people in this community makes the mayoral role the right fit for me. I think the office demands someone who will give 100% toward the goals and initiatives that will move us forward as a community. I am prepared to dedicate my time to meet those expectations.  ","","I am not only humbled to be on the ballot in November, but if elected I feel the biggest honor will be working with our police chief and everyone in that department to keep Chambersburg safe. ","","Additionally, I have hosted events such as the Chambersburg Peace Project, which united children, families, police and firemen on a summer day to enjoy each other’s company.  As mayor, I look forward to organizing many more events as bringing people together is more important now than ever before. ","","I also feel as if my visibility to the community is a way that I can lend a hand or an ear to anyone that needs support or representation on issues and ideas. You’ll know who your mayor is!",""]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_mayor_kenneth_hock","question":"What will be your top priority if elected, and what will you do to address it?","response":["While serving the people and promoting safety through our police department is always top of mind, I feel that supporting growth in Chambersburg is my top priority. Since I have been a business owner in Chambersburg for 13 years, I am uniquely positioned to not only be an advocate for existing businesses throughout the community, but also bring the level of energy needed to support Downtown Chambersburg and the Greater Chambersburg Chamber of Commerce.","","I have encountered the same challenges that fellow business owners have during the COVID-19 pandemic. The only way to navigate through the tough times is to support each other. In politics I often hear the word constituents, but when it comes to Chambersburg, I consider the people I will be fortunate to serve to be my family, friends and neighbors."]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_mayor_marvin_worthy","question":"Why are your the best choice for this office? ","response":["I am the best choice for Mayor of Chambersburg because I will work to ensure that all residents have a bright future blessed with promise and opportunity. I will continue to build this commUNITY through collaborative partnerships and effective working relationships. ","","Chambersburg is one of the fastest growing towns in Pennsylvania, and I will work with city officials and the private sector to manage our growth and preserve our high quality of life and low cost of living.","","I will work with Chief Camacho and the CPD to keep our community safe and advance mutual respect between police officers and youth. ","","I have spent much of my life helping young people set and achieve their goals, and I will invest in Chambersburg’s youth so they can be ready to serve and lead this community in the future. I am the past board chair of the Boys & Girls Club. I ran the Friday Night Youth Program for 14 years, and I am the co-founder of the Chambersburg YMCA Youth Achievers program that I currently lead."]},{"candidateCode":"chambersburg_mayor_marvin_worthy","question":"What will be your top priority if elected, and what will you do to address it?","response":["My top priority if elected is to provide the leadership Chambersburg needs to build commUNITY--together.","","I will build the Chambersburg community by identifying our strengths and expanding on them.","","I will listen to community members and set priorities based on the greatest needs for the common good.","","I will identify opportunities for increased community pride and engagement.","","I will create connections between groups to build trust and establish relationships based on community support.","","I will continue to lead with transparency and integrity.","","I will bring our community together to make it the best place it can be for all of us. Let’s Build CommUNITY Together!"]},{"candidateCode":"mayor_of_mercersburg_michael_pedersen","question":"Why are your the best choice for this office? ","response":["I believe I possess the executive leadership skills and local municipal leadership experience and understanding of this borough to lead our town and police services. I envision a small community where we not only want to live, but thrive as a person, as a family, and as a business. I envision a community that honors its heritage, welcomes everyone and ultimately leads us to a tighter-knit community which is locally protected with the right efforts, both fiscally and professionally. As a small business owner, I believe in responsible fiscal practices, transparency, efficient and effective governance, and being responsive to our citizens. ","","Responsibilities over the last 4 years as a councilperson have included working on the water authority; MMP&W fire board and the personnel committee. I also sit on the Tuscarora Area Chamber board of directors and Mercersburg Vibrancy Steering Committee. I have also dramatically grown and maintained the beautification efforts in downtown Mercersburg."]},{"candidateCode":"mayor_of_mercersburg_michael_pedersen","question":"What will be your top priority if elected, and what will you do to address it?","response":["The main responsibility of the mayor in PA boroughs is to oversee the police department. Main St, Park Ave, Linden Ave, Seminary St and Oregon St have become unsafe racetracks in the last few years as patrolling has decreased. As one third of our budget pays for our police department, I believe our citizens deserve to be protected through establishing a greater presence. I have lived on Main Street for 6 years and have noticed more speeding on weekends and evening hours while our police are off duty. I will make sure more days and hours are covered through our current officers as was initially practiced instead of overlapping 4 hours a day during the week and not being on duty on weekends. "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a federal contractor for 25 years, I have created multi-year budgets. I've run operations and policy, staff development and recruitment, bid pricing, and a portfolio the size of the District's budget. My job is to conduct performance audits on government programs; I can see when a program isn't meeting goals. My work has covered mental health, substance use, youth violence, homelessness, monitoring of infectious diseases and prevention of injury and chronic disease, all with bearing on District issues. I've won federal contracts and grants, so I understand how the District might seek additional funding.","I've served for two years on the Board. I've been through a complete budget cycle and participated in labor negotiations and leadership evaluations.","I've lived in the District for 15 years and I've had 3 kids go from kindergarten into the high school. I know the leadership, the teachers, and the staff; I've been a member of supportive organizations for school activities and events."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["YSSD has a serious structural budgetary problem. If unaddressed it will exhaust the District's fund balance in the next 5 years. It's possible that other consequences, such as a downgrade in our bond rating, could be felt earlier than that. The imbalance is the result of many factors, including PA's funding formula, the impact of \"costs\" for charter schools, and unfunded mandates from Harrisburg. The solution is equally complex and will require shared sacrifice. Recent projections from our budget office show a depletion of our fund balance even with increases to property tax rates at the legal maximum. We must taper on expenditures, which is hard because York Suburban, while an outstanding academic performer, doesn't feature many \"bells and whistles.\" There are not many obvious frills to cut, and anywhere we make reductions feels dangerously close to adversely impacting quality. But if we don't make adjustments, the dislocations we will experience by 2026 will be wrenching."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["First of all, we are both obligated and empowered to address it. We have a lot of research now that shows that with a few layers of public health interventions like masks and proper ventilation, hand hygiene and contact tracing, schools can have lower levels of transmission than the communities in which they are situated. As I write this in mid-September, York County has \"high\" community transmission and while the national trend for pediatric COVID hospitalizations finally seems to have broken, it continues to climb in our Federal Region (having risen tenfold since early July). I proposed a mask mandate for York Suburban that was partial and temporary, in order to provide a runway for those parents who wanted to vaccinate their children ages 5-11 but couldn't (and as of September, again, still can't). There were other approaches, such as temporary mask requirements tied to \"high\" or \"substantial\" community transmission, that we could have adopted as well."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["My view, from assessing the research involving everything from cohort and quasi-experimental studies to randomized controlled studies, is that they should. We have data from household contact tracing studies and the case study of the USS Theodore Roosevelt that show that self-reported mask wearing can result in reductions in risk of further transmission to close contacts by 70 percent or more. We have the German cities study that shows a daily reduction in new cases following a mask mandate can cumulate to an almost-25-percent reduction in cases in 20 days. That's significant, and it's one of many such findings. I take as completely sincere the concerns of parents about their children's reaction to masks, and I believe there are legitimate health-based exceptions. If there's a symbol of our collective trauma over the last 18 months it's probably a mask. But as a public health intervention it should be uncontroversial."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The YSSD administration went to significant lengths in the spring of 2021 to make vaccines available to educators and staff but didn't require them. My successful motion for a mask mandate at YSSD didn't require knowledge about anyone's vaccination status. We aren't following the CDC K-12 guidance calling for weekly testing of unvaccinated students and staff because we don't know people's vaccination status and generally, we're not asking. As a matter of law, vaccination requirements are in the PA Code, including at Title 28 § 23.83.(b) and (c), requirements for specific diseases, and schools aim to be in compliance with the Code. Whether COVID ends up on that list in the PA Code is anyone's guess at this point, but I think historically that's not been up to school boards. My personal advice to anyone reading this would be to talk to your own health care provider if you have any concerns; but I believe the vaccines to be generally safe and effective."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity presents opportunities to learn from one another in a climate of respect, including respect for differences. I think we need to be listening to families, students, staff, and educators, and I think it's fair to pay particular attention to groups who may have been systematically excluded from such listenings in the past. In every conversation I have with a YS parent or student, I'm seeking to understand something about our schools from their perspective, because I have to recognize that they know things -- true things -- that I don't know. There are elements of the perspective they're trying to impart to me that I know I can't fully grasp, but I'll keep trying. I believe we could have more diverse hiring among educators, staff, building leadership and administration, and we could certainly have a more diverse board. We had a terrific group of people stand up for consideration 2 years ago when I did, and I hope they'll consider running again. "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Some YS students experience the effects of racism (even as echoes of past racism) in the world every day. It would be a disservice to them and their peers not to recognize that. Curriculum development moves slowly, and it's got to be responsive to state standards; those are very real constraints. I've got tremendous confidence in our faculty to find and use developmentally- and content-appropriate materials in their classrooms. There is no shortage of material representing a wide range of opinions on the treatment of racial and ethnic minorities in the US since its founding, and asking for any single source to represent \"balance\" is like asking an author or researcher to argue with herself. The conversation takes place among multiple parties, with their own analyses and ways of privileging evidence. We teach our students to think critically at YS, to engage with the world as it is, to bring their perspectives to the classroom, and to make the world a better place. That should continue."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_steven_t._sullivan","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our schools should be a safe place for LGBTQ+ students to learn and participate in the full range of offerings and opportunities, with their identities respected and their privacy and confidentiality protected. They should be free from harassment, bullying, intimidation, or exclusion based on who they are, and they should not be invisible in our curricula. This should also be the case for our LGBTQ+ staff and educators. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been serving for 7 years and have experience for the job. I am also a graduate of the district and strive to see West York students be the best they can be. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["How to prepare our students to best take on the challenges that face them after they graduate.  In the time I have been on the board, I have worked with my fellow board members and the administration to implement a curriculum that best prepares our graduates to go into the world and be successful after they graduate. Every Student, Every Day.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["We should take those measures needed to secure the health and safety of all the students, faculty and staff. Most importantly, we should be doing what is necessary to educate our students on how to make the best decision for them and their family given the current climate.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I don’t think the right question is should the students and teachers wear masks. What we should be asking is should we take the ability of parents to raise their children in the manner they see fit away from them. By limiting parents choices. To answer the question, I favor the right of all families to have choices. Families should have the choice to wear a mask or to not wear a mask.  Not be dictated what to do.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Absolutely not.  No one should be forced to inject anything into their body they don’t want.  I believe it should be an individual’s choice. It is severe governmental overreach to mandate this vaccine for anyone.  The standard vaccines that children take now are tested and reliable with a history of success.  Also, I would feel differently if COVID vaccines were close to 100% effective or if they could guarantee one would not get COVID again. Again, I think it is an individual’s choice.  We shouldn’t shame anyone for getting or not getting a shot.  It should be a decision one makes after speaking to their physician. Not something that is forced on anyone. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["West York is already taking steps to address this issue.  We are a changing district demographically.  Our mission statement of Every Student, Every Day encompasses this very idea.  We strive to make all our students feel included.  I believe our students do a great job themselves of recognizing this issue.  Working with my fellow board members, administration, faculty and staff, we all strive to create an inclusive West York for everyone. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe West York does a great job of addressing these issues. Our administration,  faculty and staff take this very seriously already.  These are issues where every district should focus on improvement, and West York recognizes and works toward that every day. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_george_h._margetas","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Every school district should be supporting all of their students.  Regardless of race, color,  creed or sexual orientation.  As West York is very diverse, we support all of our students equally.  We shouldn’t be singling out any group as special, as all of our children are special.  We as a district should be doing everything we can to support all of our students all of the time.  As our mission statement reads, Every Student, Every Day. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I bring integrity, competence, insight, dedication and effectiveness to the West York School Board.  As a current school board director, I am actively involved in several committees and understand the time commitment required of the position. I am capable of thinking independently and strive to bring balance to our board. I am the only mom & woman who is running for this position and feel it is important for parents who actively take part in the district to be on the board.  This inside knowledge allows me to be insightful and to make informed decisions. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["West York's top issue at this time is COVID-19, similar to most school districts in our area.  Our goal is to deliver in-person, quality education to all our students 5 days a week. The administration and the school board continue to work diligently to ensure we are meeting the needs of all our students while navigating unchartered territories. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["In addition to the mitigating measures already in place, I feel the school district should continue to improve on the cyber program which launched in 2020.  This program allows our students who are unable to attend school in person to continue to learn without any interruptions to their education due to COVID.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe the parents should have the choice to decide if their child should/needs to wear a mask to school. As a parent of two children, I am a firm believer in allowing the parents to choose the best course of action for their child when it comes to their medical needs. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe the parents should have the choice to make medical decisions for their child. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["West York is a highly diversified school district. As the only minority and the only woman candidate running for this position, I feel it is important to have diversity in the district's leadership. West York should continue to offer a robust curriculum which allows the students to learn of other cultures, religions, backgrounds, and more.  We strive to create \"world-class citizens\" at West York and by exposing them to a broad curriculum, we will be able to accomplish our mission."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The school district should continue to offer books and courses to our students rich in knowledge from all over the world so our students can broaden their horizons.  As a school board director, it is our duty to expand our awareness and understand issues our students are facing, By doing so, we can help the district to create an effective curriculum for all our students."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_area_school_director_vineeta_kushla","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["The school district does a great job with offering support to all our students.  If there are any LGBTQ+ students at West York who feel they need additional support from the school district, they should work closely with their guidance counselor and/or principal so they can ensure every effort is exhausted to offer the necessary tools and resources. "]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am passionate to learn, passionate to serve, passionate to advocate for our children.  The current board is comprised of all male members and I will add diversity in terms of gender.   As a woman, I will bring a different perspective, opinion, and input to the board.  "]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I will strive to be a voice for reason and morality and to protect our children from harmful influences that would discourage them from understanding our history and how our government works, so that they can become responsible citizens who love this country as much as I do.  "]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Frequent handwashing, along with cleaning, sanitizing, disinfecting, and ventilating learning spaces and any other areas used by students (i.e., restrooms, hallways, and transportation)."]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe the school board should respect the Constitutional rights of Parents to have the primary responsibility for the health and welfare of their children.  Wearing a face covering is a personal choice and  as a district we should be accepting and understanding of the personal choice made by each individual.   "]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Senate bill 471, the Medical Freedom Act, would prohibit the state, its political subdivisions or its agents from mandating that persons receive a vaccination.  This is a personal choice for teachers, administration, and staff.  No one should be forced to get the vaccine.  No child should have to give up their education because their parents have made the decision after weighting the known risks of adverse affects to children and young adults.  It is the school's job to educate our students.  It’s the parent’s job to parent their child.",""]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We should focus on educating our students with the basic skills they will need to succeed in life, and ensure that all students have equal opportunity.  Pushing diversity and inclusion can be counter productive in that the  more we focus on what makes us different, the more divided we will become."]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Critical Race Theory divides rather than unites.  It focuses not on a person’s character or actions, but on groups, races, and the color of one’s skin.  We do not choose skin color.  However we do choose whether we study, work, and accept responsibility for our own actions.  Our focus should be on educating our children."]},{"candidateCode":"eastern_york_school_director_cynthia_rohrbaugh","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["H.B. 241, the Parents Bill of Rights, governmental institutions are prohibited from infringing on the rights of the parent in deciding what is best for their child’s health, education, and upbringing without demonstrating that such action is reasonable and necessary to achieve a compelling state interest. Parents should be promptly contacted if their child identifies as LGBTQ+.  Schools, doctors, and counselors do not have the right to strip parents of their rights in how they raise their children and should not keep things from parents."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am passionate about the educational experience York Suburban offers to its students.  It must be relevant to today’s world and meet the basic needs of all the students as they look to their futures. My time on the board has given me insight into the many issues facing the district and possible ways to deal with them. ","•        Active in all the PTOs while my children were YS students.","•        Served as Board President and Vice President.","•        Chaired the Facilities Committee during major renovation projects to all 6 buildings.","•        Represent York Suburban on the York Adams Academy board (board President for 20 years).","•        Represent York Suburban on the Lincoln Intermediate Unit-Joint Operating Authority (board President for 2 years).","•        Participated in numerous PA School Board Association conferences and statewide committees.","•        Attend many student activities including art, music, theater productions, awards programs and athletic events.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The most important issue facing the district is twofold:","•        Maintain the rigorous academic program for our diverse student population.","•        Repair the projected structural fund balance deficit thus bringing financial stability to the district.","These two issues along with the others such as: the district’s aging physical plant that is in need of extensive renovations and updates, charter school funding, basic and special education funding shortfalls and unfunded mandates from the State that are all straining the resources of the district.  The board must carefully look at all expenditures along with all requests for program, staffing and maintenance needs.  Adjustments and compromise will be needed in order to stay within the limits set by the State on tax increases in any given year under Act 1.",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The district has taken numerous steps to address the effects of COVID in our schools.  Along with a masking requirement (currently mandated by the Department of Health) frequent hand washing and social distancing where possible, other mitigation steps have been taken by the District.  According to a report by Barry Girling, Director of Facilities for York Suburban school district, such things as increasing air circulation in classrooms, changing air filters more frequently, bringing in more outside air when possible and installing commercial grade dehumidifiers in some areas of the buildings have been done throughout the District as part of its mitigation efforts. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Masks should be required for everyone in the schools and on school buses. There is more scientific data now that supports that masks are an important part of COVID mitigation strategies. I believe that there are some who have significant health issues that may be exacerbated by wearing a mask. We need to be aware of their issues and work to keep them safe. However, in the midst of the pandemic that we find ourselves every effort needs to be used to stop or slow the spread of the virus. At the very least, we as a school district need to be cognizant of so many others who have been at home for many months fearing any exposure to COVID.  ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Teachers and/or students over the age of 12 probably. Teachers had the opportunity to be vaccinated last spring. At that time it was hoped this would help stop/slow the spread of the virus and keep our schools open. There are many inoculations that all students are required to have prior to and during their school years. Granted most of these have years of data and research behind them now.  They were all very new at one time. (I personally remember the polio vaccine being administered while in high school.) Enough time has passed to see the devastating effects of COVID.  That should convince us all to be vaccinated. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["As a district and as individuals, we need to be aware of the differences that exist in our community. In talking with people, I find we have fewer differences between us than we think. It is good though to understand these differences and to respect them. I tend to find that younger people tend to not find differences but rather similarities in making new friends. While we have a diverse student population, we certainly do not have the diversity we might have in teaching staff, administrators and the board.  We need to encourage others to “come on down and join us”.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Issues surrounding race and racism are community, as well as, school district issues. I don’t believe that the school district can or should be expected to solve issues surrounding race and racism in a vacuum. Curricular changes are often very slow.  Administrators and teachers are often the best leaders in offering suggestions to address specific areas for consideration and presentation and discussion with students.  We want our students to think about topics outside of their comfort zones. We want them to think about all sorts of topics and question each other and the resources they have studied.  Having these conversations can hopefully lead to better understanding for all."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_ellen_c._freireich","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["As a district, we need to be very aware that there are LGBTQ+ students, faculty and other staff who should be given the same respect and privacy as anyone else.  Everyone should feel safe and have no qualms about their choices. Everyone needs to know that they are appreciated and welcome to join any class, club, discussion or organization without fear of discrimination.  ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Having served in the military for a total of 11 years and 2 deployments, one being deployed to Afghanistan and the other to East Timor, I developed leadership skills consisting of integrity, dedication and judgement.  I seek to find the middle ground that our community and country needs right now, to lead by example, while making fair and balanced choices.  As a decorated combat veteran that has also deployed in support of humanitarian aid, I know first hand the meaning of empathy and compassion. This is extremely important as we have seen a rise in adolescent suicide rates in the US due to social disruption in the last year and bullying.  I will ensure our children have the support and assets for both a well rounded education and mental well being while continue to completely eliminate bullying in our schools and community.  What will make me the best candidate is that I will not involve politics in my decisions, I will use critical thinking skills while remaining non partisan. "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The current top issue in the York Suburban School District that needs addressed immediately is our failing infrastructure and our budget shortfall.  Our HVAC system to include the chillers and boilers are in need of replacement at the high school as presented by Mr. Girling the facilities manager during the September 13, 2021 board meeting that can be watched here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GXg6Ojxcufk&t=947s ","The budget will fall short in year 2025 even with maximum tax increases allowed by the state over the next 3 years unless we start making adjustments immediately. There are many ways to adjust the budget so we do not fall short on funding in the middle of the school year 2025, but there is only one right way to make those adjustments.  The right way includes maintaining the high academic standard of excellence that York Suburban prides itself on and not eliminating the art and music departments as they are needed in a well rounded education that every student deserves"]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Currently the Acting Secretary of Health Alison Beam has removed the responsibility of mask decisions from the school boards by issuing a mask mandate for grades K-12.  I understand that not everyone agrees with this decision but it now allows the school board to focus on the issues that will have long term effects on the district like the ones I stated in the previous answered.  Uniformity is the key when addressing COVID in the schools, the entire district should follow the same guidelines to eliminate confusion and we should continue to follow the state recommendations as we currently are doing in the York Suburban School District."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes they should but with exemptions, which are currently included in the state mask mandate for K-12.  It allows for face shields in place of masks and in select cases and situations to not need or have to wear a mask.  As we see the virus continue to mutate and infect more children in our community along with the vaccinated, it is important to take the necessary precautions to ensure a safe environment for everyone.  As I have stated even the vaccinated are not immune to the virus and can continue to spread the virus to others it is just as important for those individuals to wear masks to prevent the spread of COVID.  Science has shown that masking is not 100% effective but it has also shown that when masks are used correctly it results in a decrease of COVID cases and even less flu cases as we have seen in the last year."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["NO.  This should remain a personal choice as of right now because the state has not included it in the list of mandatory vaccines needed to attend public school.  Even with the list of mandatory vaccinations, there are religious and medical exemptions.  If the state in the future would add the COVID vaccine to the list of required vaccinations, it would have the same exemptions available as current required vaccines.  I have personally received the vaccine and have no issue with it but I also understand the concern that other individuals have about their children receiving the vaccine.  While we currently have a mask mandate in place to mitigate the spread of COVID, I do not see a need to make the vaccine a requirement, but as science continues to learn more about the virus and it's mutations it could change the dynamics of the entire COVID situation."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["As Dr. Tim Williams the current superintendent to over in 2018, he penned a letter to the district and community that his immediate item of importance was to continue implementing diversity in the York Suburban School District.  He up to this point along with the current board and faculty are doing exactly what his vision is for the district in terms of diversity and inclusion.  As I am limited on space for my responses the numbers can be easily found on the District website to show that we not only continue to excel in academics at York Suburban but we continue to diversify and include everyone in our family at York Suburban"]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Currently there is no need to make changes to the curriculum in the York Suburban School District. York Suburban has stood by their community and has shouted down racism, after what Central York School board did in banning books, our district responded on September 21st by accepting a donation of books written by Zetta Elliot and they will be distributed to the libraries in the next week. This is why York Suburban has just recently been ranked number one in the county by Niche in their 2022 rankings"]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_quentin_gee","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["York Suburban School District must ensure inclusion and representation of all children in our community.  We have an outstanding group of counselors along with a number of resources to help our students if they need support.  As I have answered the previous question with there currently is no need to take steps, this answer would be the same  Our district is already supporting and making a great educational experience for all of our students."]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My ability to approach any situation with a non biased attitude, combined with my passion and desire to obtain all information on the topic at hand in my best attempt to make an informed decision. History shows that I've always been one who listens intently, hears all sides of an argument and responds with facts backed by citations and not opinion or emotion. The district deserves a school board that not only hears the concerns and needs of its residents, but also a board that speaks for its residents. One who has the back bone to stand up for its residents. Without a doubt, I believe that person is me. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Parents take issue with a lack of communication and transparency from the current school board. The common argument echoed the most is there seems to be a lack of parental control with regard to freedom of choice concerning the mask mandate. There also seems to be a lack of oversight when it comes to managing the budget and allocation of funds to on going projects.  I would like to implement measures where hot topic issues that present themselves to the board are addressed in a total open forum, allowing for Q&A and updates to the parents as often as possible. A 24 hour quick response strategy that requires the board to convene, be it in person or virtual, to assess the situation and gain an understanding of its ramifications of the districts. Seek legal counsel and release a statement to the residents all within the first 24 hours.   This would be done in conjunction with a detailed explanation to the families.    "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I honestly feel that our district is doing the best that can when it comes to how they actively address COVID IN THE SCHOOLS. This pandemic that we find ourselves in, seems to be ever changing. Even the medical experts are learning new things weekly, and what they thought was best practice last month might not be the same this month. What should be done differently, however,  is again the way in which the district handles communication with the families. The decisions made by the board, be it by vote or legal obligation, should be explained to the families of the district, in a respectful and compassionate way that they can understand and leave the conversation with a sense of relief and assurance that the board still has the best interest of the students and staff in mind. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I feel that students and teachers should have the right to choose. Throughout this pandemic the population as a whole has showed an elevated level of concern and care for others. I believe wholeheartedly that without being forced to do so, teachers and a majority of students would wear a mask out of respect for others. It's the notion that the freedom of choice has been taken away that doesn't sit well. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Again, I don't believe so. This decision should be one that's made by the individual based on their personal beliefs and medical history. For many, the effects of getting COVID outweigh the risks associated with receiving the vaccine.  Regardless of what the CDC says today about the vaccine, a majority of people simply want to see what the long term effects of the vaccine are before injecting it into their body. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The district may want to look at areas where diversity is lacking. Areas such as band, orchestra, art programs, dramatics, etc where there may be a gap in diversity, are areas where focus may be directed. Ensuring that there is representation throughout the staff is extremely important. Including demographics of all races, genders and socioeconomics, is important to aid in identifying and addressing the unique needs of all students and families within the district. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["In discussing the curriculum, I'm a firm believer in teaching the students true world history as it occurred. No matter how uncomfortable it might be for some to comprehend or come to terms with. The history of our world is a complicated and tragic story, but nonetheless, one that should be told. The history of all races and cultures should be taught in school and not limited to a brief discussion. Beginning in elementary school and progressing with more in depth material just as we do with math, science and English. The world we are preparing our students for is full of diversity, and with that comes issues that stem from race relations, cultural stigmatization and misunderstood prejudices. It just makes sense that we educate our youth today on these issues, so they are better prepared to face the world tomorrow. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_2_year_term_michael_a._rascoe","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I feel that in addition to any clubs that may already be established to support students who identify as such, creating an atmosphere of inclusion throughout the system is important. Ensuring that staff, counselors, administrators and students, regardless of their personal beliefs, are welcoming and supportive of this student population. This could include a simple pride flag or relevant symbol on a door indicating a safe space or taking a no tolerance stance against hateful speech or exclusion."]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I put children first.In my experience on West Shore School Board I noticed that voters just want to elect someone who will put their children first. They want a school board director that will be caring, will listen, and will ensure their children are given every advantage available."]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I want to see a better education environment. Covid has been a strain on everyone, however there is a specific underrepresented group of children in our Special Education population that have suffered immensely. Resources that were already spread thin, made it difficult to reach these children during shut down. As a result there is a widening risk of falling behind educationally. My top priority is to work directly with our county resources and administration to direct resources to those with disabilities."]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Consistent cleaning of surfaces, wipe down or areas, anti-bacterial products, frequent hand washing/"]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I personally strive to not place my political and personal priorities above the needs of others. I’ll leave you with this quote: “You can still be concerned about the government. You can still be concerned about who gets elected and what policies are put in place. However, we must recognize that those concerns should never outweigh one of our greatest commandments: love thy neighbor.” "]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am not above the law. I will follow the law on whatever it requires. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Equity"]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Enrich language, reasoning, writing, discussion, and literacy skills by creating opportunities for conversations on different perspectives and challenging belief systems. Increase engagement among students by helping them feel connected to a curriculum that honors their story and background, and improve school climate and safety by giving students a sense of belonging and collective responsibility in the classroom"]},{"candidateCode":"west_shore_school_director_2_year_term_clydiene_f._francis_-joray","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["LGBTQ+  Students are students. ALL students deserve a quality education and to be safe, regardless. ALL students, not just mine, not just yours, deserve a quality education and to feel safe. Does not matter, a child is a child. ALL children deserve equitable resources for what they need. ALL "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Amelia has a unique perspective as a younger candidate for Central's School Board.  While times change rapidly, Amelia has experienced many modern day issues firsthand.  Amelia is dedicated to making decisions based on community input, expert data, and not her own personal feelings.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Mental Health always comes to mind first.  While this subject can cover a vast spectrum of issues, they are all equally pressing in 2021.  Suicide is the 2nd leading cause of death in young people.  Working to strengthen CYSD's current mental health systems is integral to educational performance and student wellbeing.  We cannot wait for a student to be failing before introducing 504 plans, and should be evaluating why a student in an IEP is struggling.  Staff mental health is critical in these overarching goals, as well.  Amelia would also use her elevated position as a School Board Director to push for stronger mental health legislation in Pennsylvania.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Looking to the experts and facts for guidance, as well as working with the State Board of Education.  Communication with the faculty and community must also be weighed when making these decisions.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Amelia believes this is a decision made based on current statistics and is ever evolving.  What works today, may not work tomorrow.  Keeping students and staff protected to keep in-person learning accessible for all families is the ultimate goal. Working with the school district solicitor will avoid frivolous lawsuits that would cost taxpayer money. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Vaccination is a personal choice made between someone and their healthcare provider.  As a school board director, it would be important to weigh in with the community and experts rather than make any votes based on personal feelings.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity is what makes America great.  Again, hearing the community and faculty are critical steps to ensure all students have a fair and equal education.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["School Board Directors do not write curriculum.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_amelia_mcmillan","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Coming back to the subject of mental health, support staff should be up to date in training to support LGBTQ+ students.  The board must work with faculty and the district solicitor to maintain compliance of civil rights protections covered in Title IX.  "]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Always having a passion for education and serving my community, I have a Bachelors degree in Education and a Masters in Public Administration. I worked for the PA House of Representatives for 13 years and have remained in government affairs for the past 3 yrs. ","","I have also served on both the Dover Twp and York County Planning Commissions, VP of Weigelstown Elem PTO, and coached for DYB Cheer and Dover Area Soccer Association.","","This combined with being a member of the Dover Area School Board for the past 6 yrs, I have served and advocated for the educational needs of our children for more than 12 years, and hope to continue to work to ensure our students receive a quality education."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Fiscal responsibility while ensuring quality education. We have seen a number of recent events that have had a huge financial impact on our district’s budget, especially with an increasing number of students moving to cyber charter options. As a current member of the Human and Fiscal Resources Committee, working with and supporting teachers and administration to address these issues as we to work to balance the budget responsibly continues to be one of my top priorities."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["My top priority is keeping our students safe and  in the classroom with in-person learning. The district should look to medical experts and CDC for guidance as to how this should be successfully accomplished. "]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Again, my priority is to avoid remote/virtual learning, as most of us saw and experienced the negative impacts that this had on our students’ education, as well as their social and emotional well-being. As mentioned above, the district should seek the advice of medical experts and CDC guidelines."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["As school board members, we are tasked with ensuring our kids receive quality education. Part of this means doing what we can to keep them safe and provide a safe learning environment.  However, I do believe that vaccinations are a personal choice and should not be required. This should not be a decision made by a school board."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Every student is an individual with unique personalities and backgrounds. Our district should be promoting awareness regarding diversity among our students. We should also work to reduce and discourage stigmas against diverse students, while encouraging understanding and acceptance of diversity among our students. ","","The business community recognizes the value of different perspectives from employees with various backgrounds. If we hope to prepare our students to be valuable contributors of our community and the workforce, encouragement  and acceptance of diversity should be part of our everyday fabric."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The district and the school board should rely on educational professionals and those standards set by the State to determine curriculum."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_amy_brinton","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Similar to my answer regarding diversity in our schools, I believe that we should encourage understanding and provide these students with the support they need to ensure they have the same educational opportunities that all students have."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been heavily involved in the school district and community for the past 19 years while living in Southern York County. I love Susquehannock School District and I'm proud to have my daughters graduate from there. I would like to be the voice for the students, parents and community while supporting a safe and successful school district. I have been lucky enough to serve on the board for the past 5 months and I feel that it is a good fit for me and I want to make sure that Susquehannock stays focused on excellent education."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Of course the top issue is masking the students at school during COVID. I don't feel that the board should be making this decision and I feel that parents should be making the choice for their children. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I feel like they are doing everything they can with the information that they are given."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I think it should be up to the parents, but I have to be honest in saying that most of the students that I have talked to are just happy to be there five days a week, with their friends, and playing sports. If they have to wear a mask to do it, they are willing to wear it. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["No they shouldn't be required, it is their body and their choice."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["I think our school is doing everything that is needed."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe in equity versus equality and in bit that I have witnessed while serving on the board, I have seen great strides to support this. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_elizabeth_dauberman","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I feel that all the students are supported and should a situation arise it will be discussed individually as each student is unique, as well as their circumstances. "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I believe the district needs to have more diverse members and also have an inclusion and diversity committee developed and implemented. "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe the top issue is allowing the parents and community to have a voice and a say over their children. "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Provide the children with hand sanitizer and masks, leave it up to the parents to decide what’s best for their children "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The parents should decide what is best for their child. "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["No, medical treatment should be at the discretion of each child’s parent "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Choosing myself, a minority as a candidate to develop and implement an inclusion and diversity committee "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Children should know about Marcis Garvey and many other people of color that are monumental to our history. Juneteenth is also important history that should be in all school curriculum "]},{"candidateCode":"red_lion_area_school_director_jasmine_smallwood","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Love, nurture, and teach all the students as if they were your own children. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Education: BSN - Chamberlain University, RN - Reading Hospital, BS Sociology - PSU. ","I am a CYSD Alumni, RN, IBCLC and Nurse Educator with over 21 yrs. of professional experience in mental health, maternal-child, and pediatric nursing. Being a nurse is an incredible honor to care for women & children from all backgrounds. I believe in parental choice and positive relationships with our teachers.  I oppose Act 1 utilization to increase the millage to the maximum allowed by law to be financially responsible to families, residents on fixed incomes, and local businesses rebuilding after near financial collapse. Every learner’s growth is unique, and students may not choose college after high school, and our promotion of technology and trade education is critical for well-paying jobs and economic growth. We can accomplish these goals when the School Board, families, educators, and community are respectful and committed to core academics, emotional development, and physical health.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We need to rebuild the School Board and Administration relations to take on the upcoming ramifications of inflation.  Many in our community are concerned about their financial situations in relation to COVID and the economy.  Families and senior citizens are living within their means on a budget and the effect of increased property taxes could be devastating.  None of the loudest candidates are discussing what really needs to be addressed now, food shortages, cafeteria workers and bus drivers are desperately needed, operations, maintenance, health and wellness and services to help students with extracurricular activities, and CORE ACADEMICS should be the agenda items. Building relationships and retaining the best teachers and staff is also key to having a top performing district within our county and state.  It is my hope that we will look at the trend of the expenses and review to remain accountable to our taxpayers and yet support our teachers and staff."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The COVID pandemic has changed the way of life as we know it. When I entered the hospital to work in March 2020 at the beginning of it all, as a nurse I knew I would be potentially exposed or become sick. That is the reality within health care. As schools have adapted, I am truly impressed, and am so happy that face-to-face learning is happening, and it must continue. We need to equip our school nurses with adequate supplies and allow them to have input into Board Meetings during health and safety planning.  Unfortunately, there will be COVID cases, yet it is imperative to continue the cleaning of surfaces, air exchange systems in ventilation, and education on correct hand hygiene to decrease incidence of cases.  Guidance counselors could partner with our nursing staff to promote mental health support and monitor well-being during this pandemic.  We have seen the negative effects of isolation and increased rates of anxiety and depression among our teens. We need to do better at this. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Masks should not be required, and this decision should be left to individual circumstances. N95 masks, reserved for health care professionals, are the only masks proven at preventing transmission of COVID.  There are no long-term studies on the risks or benefits of mask wearing among children. Thus, I cannot in ethical conscience enforce a mask mandate.  Across Pennsylvania, NCAA and NFL football has thousands of spectators, and minimal mask wearing is observed, yet school children are mask mandated. Parents have expressed concerns for their children with regards to speech, language, and anxiety when children must wear a mask.  Our PA Secretary of Health has not mandated any other gatherings such as colleges, sports, or other large crowds, so why are we masking the ones who are least at risk?  Sadly, the topic of masking has become politically charged, which is at the expense of our children to whom we do not have viable research to state they are free from risk in the long-term."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["This subject should not be a political topic, as with all healthcare decisions.  Teachers were included in Phase 1B and were provided time to recover.  Now, with the FDA approval age of 12 and older, this must continue to be a decision between parents and their health care provider.  I encourage families to seek valid evidence-based research from reputable sources and consult with their physician.  Personal health histories should be reviewed prior to receiving any medication especially one on the newer front of technology and timeline as the COVID vaccine. Benefits for the vaccine are evident for older Americans with a higher risk, but again this must be a personal choice and not mandated under duress.  As a parent and RN, I want to see long-term studies to determine safety in children, which requires time to elapse and data to be collected without political influences.  The COVID vaccine must be voluntary, a decision left between an individual and his or her health care provider.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["At birth we are granted an unbiased mind, and young children make friends without regard to outward physical characteristics, unless they are pointed out. In the event children outwardly notice a peer’s physical differences it is up to parents and teachers to model kindness and inclusion of every child. Everyone should be made to feel part of the group. Creating an awareness in children & teens on races who are disadvantaged based on historical contexts is not the way to create inclusion, that is identity politics. Instead, cultural diversity awareness with reputable book resources for adults to review and approve for their child’s age-appropriate education is one method to promote inclusion. This isn’t a one-sided conversation or to water down any information, we do not teach calculus to a 6-year-old. We engage and address the known situations by the questions the children ask. Parents should support conversations within the home, so it transfers to relationship building in school.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["As previously stated, children are born with an unbiased mind, and make friends without regard to outward physical characteristics, unless they are pointed out.  Families, parents, and teachers need to each take on their roles individually to help children understand the impact of relationships which are directly related to character and not correlated to skin color or race. In addition, the concept of respect for everyone is taught at the earliest ages. I personally love the Roundtown Proud motto, meaning Polite, Responsible, Outstanding, Understanding, and Dependable is an excellent foundation.  Again, creating an awareness in children & teens on races who are disadvantaged based on historical contexts only continue to focus on the past and singles out children who only want to be friends and enjoy their school years.  I was raised to treat every person as I would like to be treated, to forgive and forget, and as a nurse care for all, regardless of color or ethnicity."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_laura_a._bond","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I’ll attempt to answer a question to which I personally am still learning about from the perspective of that individual(s). I have friends and family within the LGBTQ community and support them no differently than any other person. For those LGBTQ students, they should feel supported at home and in school. However, for families that want this topic discussed or explained at home, those families have the right to not consent that their child(ren) participate in these discussions/lessons in school. Transgender females have an unfair physiological advantage over biological females in individual sports, challenging the right to scholarships and school records once established by biological female athletes. The LGBTQ students need allies and support, while schools must continue respecting morals & values of families who prefer to broach this topic at home."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experiences as a Lutheran pastor, the proud father of two Central York students, and an involved community leader have helped me to understand our school district’s needs. I volunteer for various non-profits, task forces, and other organizations in the York area in addition to coaching youth sports. I’ve also served as a board member of the Manchester Township Athletic Association. As the lead pastor of an active and community-focused Lutheran congregation, I have the experience and skills needed to work with all community stakeholders.","The challenges facing our school district are vast: falling test scores, difficult budgetary decisions, and a serious need for improved transparency. In situations like these, experience and integrity matter. I am not running for Central York School Board because I expect the job to be easy. I am running because I feel called to serve the students, parents, and senior citizens in our district during these challenging times."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Central York School District’s most important issue is whether we will heed the call to serve our students in a way that prepares them for their future instead of serving special interests or political agendas. In recent years, the school board has failed to approve much needed educational programs, banned innocent children’s books, and put public tax dollars at risk by ignoring state policy—all while our district’s ranking continues to fall.","","As a pastor, I understand that decisions a school board makes are part of a moral compact with the local community—and failing our students in these ways is simply immoral. Instead of engaging our administration and educators in finding ways to better serve and prepare our students, board members have ignored curricula and programs while engaging in partisan politics. Electing a school board that will put students and community members first is the most important issue we face because until we solve that problem, we cannot solve any problem.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["My goal as a board member is to ensure a safe place for public education. We must rely on common sense and the experience and knowledge of experts in these fields. Unfortunately, one of the candidates for this position publicly suggested that the COVID-19 vaccine sterilizes its recipients and that coronavirus diagnostic testing causes cancer. This view is unsupported by medical science. In a rational discussion about the health and safety of our children there is no place for this type of disinformation, and on our school board there should be no place for those who peddle dangerous conspiracy theories.","","We also cannot follow the current board's attempt to ignore state medical policy and expose ourselves to needless lawsuits, putting the hard earned tax dollars of our residents at risk for political reasons. As a pastor, I take it seriously when my actions affect others. Part of caring for our neighbors is to do all we can to not only protect ourselves, but to protect others.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["As I mentioned in the previous answer, I believe that we need to do whatever we can to keep our children in school. We know that in-person learning is much better for a child’s mental health and educational outcomes than online instruction. We also know that it can be a struggle for parents and caregivers to have to be home with children who are exposed and quarantined. I know this from experience, as my child was exposed and needed to quarantine before returning to school. One way that we can best make sure our students stay in school is to listen to the professionals and experts in the scientific and medical fields. I believe there should be exceptions for children who are truly affected negatively by masks. Part of providing a free and public education to our students is to make sure it is done in the safest way possible."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe that requirements around vaccinations should be decided upon at the state level just as the others have been done in the past. The Pennsylvania General Assembly already has a list of required vaccines for public school attendance. Using the existing state-level process for vaccine-related decisions is preferable to placing the decision in the hands of individual school boards. We must keep our local community free from school board members’ personal agendas and disinformation. One Central York School Board member has even falsely suggested that the COVID-19 vaccine sterilizes people and that the screening test causes cancer. Neither of these claims is supported by any evidence. Clearly, school board members lack the qualifications to make this decision. The decision should remain with the General Assembly."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["As a pastor, coach, and community leader, I thank God for the beauty of our diversity. Diversity is a gift that gives all of us different insights into the vast complexities of our shared world. This diverse world is our reality and we must prepare our students for entry into a global economy. It is imperative for us to include and enable all our students to discuss the many social issues that they face now and the ability to think on their own for issues they will face in the future; to give them resources and training to do proper research; to expose them to the diversity that surrounds us. We cannot ban books and resources because it goes against our personal narrative or political agenda. We shouldn’t be demanding to break precedent by requiring public speakers of color to submit their remarks ahead of time to be “vetted.” I am proud of our students for standing against the injustices enacted by our current school board members and those who agree with and are running with them. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Our first step is to make sure that we listen to the professional educators and review, edit as needed, and approve the four curricula that have been tabled for over a year by our current board. This includes updated curricula on health, language arts, guidance, and social studies. The current board continues to fail in its job to provide our students the best possible resources for their education. Instead, even though each curriculum meets or exceeds state standards, our current board members have allowed their personal fears to needlessly delay review. I will work with the district diversity coordinators and diversity committee to once again help our district be a leader in promoting unity and inclusion. I will listen to the voices of our students and educators on how we can best support them in their education. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_joel_folkemer","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All students deserve to be treated with full equity and given full inclusion. Not long ago, members of our current board attempted to block a policy that would protect all of our students from discrimination. This is not okay. I recognize there are intense feelings wrapped up in these conversations, but we cannot allow our students to suffer because of them. We also need to realize that as a school board, we do not have the authority to create policies regarding specific LGBTQIA+ rights. This is something that is done by state and federal law. We must follow these statutes or once again, we open ourselves up to litigation and wasted taxpayer dollars. "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a retired Major League Baseball player who is dedicated to giving back to our community. After continuing my professional baseball career as a pitcher with the York Revolution, I started Corey’s Healthy Kids Club and was part of the team’s reading initiative for children. I have also spoken to local high school students through the D.A.R.E Program. I am ready to continue my lifetime of community service—this time as a member of our school board.","","Since retiring from professional baseball, I have remained active in our community by helping to raise money for local veterans’ organizations and volunteering with the York Little League program. My wife and I have two young children, so I am deeply invested in the success of our school system. As someone who has spent his entire personal and professional life learning the value of teamwork, I am committed to collaborating with parents, students, teachers, and district residents to strengthen our school community."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The Central York School Board needs to drastically improve the transparency of its operations. After embarrassing our entire school community with a discriminatory book ban, school board members canceled their in-person meetings and convened virtually instead. With a national audience watching, our school board members abandoned us when we needed them the most. Rather than hiding from accountability, our school board members should be engaging the community and seeking solutions.","","As a school board member, I will be accessible for our community’s questions and responsive to our community’s needs. I support utilizing parent and community survey data to make informed decisions and ensure our school board is communicating with the public effectively. Improving transparency is the most important issue facing the Central York School Board because board members are entrusted to make the best decisions with our community’s most valuable resource: our children."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["As a coach and former professional athlete, I take health care and medical well-being very seriously. I understand firsthand how important it is to adhere to professional medical guidance, and I trust that many candidates will address this question from that perspective. However, as a school board candidate, I want to approach this question from an educational perspective. Research supports the view that most students learn best when they attend school in-person, and I share this view.","","By adhering to state Department of Health and Department of Education guidance on COVID-19 policy, we are able to make it more certain that our students will be able to continue attending school in-person. We are able to ensure that students will be able to play school sports or participate in other extracurricular activities that they enjoy. If we defy this guidance, we risk a shutdown that would undermine student learning and cause students to miss out on what they look forward to about school."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["When I played Major League Baseball, I used to watch players and managers get into arguments with the umpires. The funny thing is, they never won the argument, and they always got a fine afterwards. I see the universal masking policy the same way. Instead of wasting time “arguing with the umpire,” we need to focus on what our students really need. If we violate state policy, our district risks losing funding, and that ultimately hurts our students and our community.","","In the last four years, our school district has slipped from atop the county-wide rankings to ninth place out of 16 schools. Arguing about masks is an unnecessary distraction from the real issues that are affecting our students’ learning. Our school board has tabled one program proposal after another because of politically motivated distractions. Being on the school board should be a platform for helping students succeed, not a platform for advancing personal political views."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a pitcher for the York Revolution, I was proud to start Corey’s Healthy Kids Club, which focused on positive health habits. Exercise, nutrition, and a medically appropriate vaccine schedule are all aspects of staying healthy. However, the state legislature has always been responsible for designating which vaccines are required for public schools in Pennsylvania. It is unclear to me whether local school boards are even authorized to act on this matter. I support keeping this decision in the hands of the state legislature."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Our school board recently made national news when they voted to ban hundreds of innocent children’s books. The board’s ban was so egregious that it even listed certain categories of banned books. One category was \"characters of color.\" It included 27 children's books. Another category was \"authors of color.\" It included an additional 19 books. Apparently those things are enough to get a book banned. The board also voted to ban the biographies of Rosa Parks, MLK, Nelson Mandela, and Maya Angelou. They even banned a Pennsylvania Association of School Administrators’ statement that acknowledges racism is bad. When CNN and Fox News both reported critically the ban, the board responded that it was a coincidence that all of the banned books were either written by or about people of color. Getting CNN and Fox News to agree on something would normally be impressive, but not in this case. Board members have publicly stated they are considering reinstating the ban. I will oppose this ban."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Central York recently dedicated significant resources to developing a first-rate diversity education curriculum. It was approved collaboratively by a wide range of stakeholders and was recommended for board adoption by district administration. Sadly, several board members made inaccurate and disparaging remarks about the curriculum. This was widely reported by local news outlets, which embarrassed our entire school community. These board members forced a vote to table the adoption of the curriculum, citing concerns that the decision was too difficult.","","Our community deserves leaders who will lead from the front, not kick the can down the road if they think a decision is difficult. If there are legitimate concerns about whether a proposal satisfies our community’s needs, board members have a responsibility to address those concerns and be part of the solution. I pledge to carefully study the proposed curriculum, ensure it satisfies applicable state standards, and move for its adoption."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_corey_thurman","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I went to school as a Black child in the South. I know what it is like to be different. I have seen and experienced discrimination as well, but I have also lived what it feels like to receive support and love from those around me in the face of that discrimination. I want to make sure all of our students feel welcome, including those who are members of the LGBTQ+ community. Adolescence and school are hard enough without bullying and the trauma it can cause. As adults, and especially as school board members, we have a responsibility to ensure young people are getting the support they need. Not everyone supports that view, but making an emotionally charged decision based strictly on personal feelings could cause the district a great deal of legal harm and ultimately cost taxpayers millions of dollars. I will always work closely with the district’s legal counsel when making these decisions to avoid wasting taxpayer money and because I understand the importance of supporting students."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My husband and I have lived in the Central York community for 18 years. I have a thorough understanding of the diverse needs of our student population as the result of my years as a substitute teacher at all grade levels in the district, and also as the parent of a son with autism and a daughter who is in the gifted program. I co-founded Breast Cancer Survivors of York and have years of experience as a board member for the Jewish Community Center. I am currently the chairperson of the York Symphony Orchestra’s Education Committee. Serving in these roles has equipped me with the knowledge and skills that are necessary to be a successful school board member and community leader.","After studying molecular biology in graduate school, I worked as a supervisor in a virology biosafety testing laboratory; a job requiring excellent organizational and communication skills, and also very relevant experience during this unprecedented time.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["As many community members are probably already aware, our district’s student performance ranking has dropped precipitously in recent years. We need to course correct by facilitating a student-centered school system that promotes academic and self growth by addressing the individual needs of every learner. That means we need a practical curriculum to ensure students are college and career ready. As the world is constantly changing, school systems need to adjust accordingly.","One way to achieve this outcome is by embracing the underlying goals of the new Future Ready PA Index. This system rewards school districts for metrics related to career readiness. For example, it evaluates how successful districts are at helping students transition to postsecondary schooling, the military, or the workforce. Helping students to make this transition smoothly should be the primary focus of our school district because it moves us one step closer to ensuring each student’s long-term success.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["As a Board member, my focus will always be on the health and well-being of all students. Mental health is often tied to physiological health, and must not be disregarded. I recognize that there are very heated opinions on both sides of this issue, but keeping students safe and in school should be our first priority. If students do not stay healthy, they risk missing in-person school and missing out on all of the mental health supports provided while at school. I also believe it would be reckless and irresponsible to place our district in the position of receiving potential fines or losing governmental funding as the result of our decisions. These decisions affect all students, families, and taxpayers.","As a scientist, I respect and understand the scientific method more than many. For this reason, I will always look to the experts and follow expert guidance instead of internet disinformation. Conspiracy theories regarding the COVID-19 vaccine and testing have no place in leadership.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["As I stated above, mental health is inextricably linked to physical health. School closures due to unencumbered spread of the virus need to be avoided at all costs. Spread of a new disease with an unknown impact on each particular individual is a risk not without potentially severe consequences. Remote learning is not optimal for students’ educational and emotional needs, which is why we must avoid a shutdown of our district’s buildings. Some have advocated for violating state policy in order to score political points, but our children are not pawns in a political game; they are our future.","Moreover, risking the loss of federal or state funding—or making the district vulnerable to litigation—would be an irresponsible use of one’s position as school director. School board members have a responsibility to look out for the best interest of our students, our educators, and our taxpayers when making important decisions.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a potential school board member, I do not believe this type of decision is within my purview. Currently, the state General Assembly presides over such decisions, and I believe it is best left that way. That being said, I think it is important for misinformation regarding the virus, the vaccine, testing, and treatments to be identified and corrected in an expedient and public manner. Accordingly, there is no evidence to support the recent false implications by one current board member that the vaccine causes infertility or the test causes cancer. No one benefits from lies or conspiracies surrounding a global health crisis. Central York families should be able to make the decision about whether to get vaccinated without local elected officials interfering by spreading harmful misinformation. As a member of the School Board, it would be irresponsible for me to allow mistruths and exaggerations to obscure scientifically supported expert recommendations.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["As a School Director in the second most diverse district in York County, I will always be mindful of how our decisions affect ALL children.","Recently, CYSD made national news for banning a long list of diversity resources.  Only a few resources were identified by a few parents (including the current Board Vice President) as having the potential to “indoctrinate” readers. In response, a vote was taken to ban the entire list from use in our schools until it could be vetted. 10 ½ months later, that vetting process has not even begun.","Our district’s lauded Diversity Program and Committee have been under attack since many members of the current Board have held office.  If elected, I will recommend that teachers, staff, and administration attend diversity training; and I will solicit the recommendations of a wide range of diversity experts on how to implement diversity and sensitivity policies district-wide.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe all children should be seen, heard, loved, and respected. Our Diversity Committee has done an excellent job at providing our students and staff with amazing educational programming and training.  That work is now being pushed aside by the current Board and replaced by personal political agendas and divisiveness.  ","In the summer of 2020, a well-researched social studies curriculum was presented to this Board by the administration.  Several of the Board members personally took issue with certain parts of the proposed curriculum and tabled its discussion. The curriculum is still tabled today.  This inaction is unacceptable; leaders cannot delay decisions simply because they are afraid to make them.  If elected, I will do my very best to make informed decisions, even the difficult or controversial ones, in a timely manner.  And I will base my decisions based on a fair assessment of the input I receive, especially when considering difficult subjects, such as race and racism.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_amy_milsten","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["My previous responses can be used here as well.  ALL children deserve to be seen, heard, loved, and understood.  Childhood and adolescence is a time for self-discovery. Mental health can be very tenuous in a child who doesn’t feel seen or accepted for who they are.  I will always support and encourage love and acceptance.","School boards do not have authority to craft policy on specifics related to the rights of LGBTQIA individuals; instead, they are required to follow applicable state and federal laws in this regard.  Not following these statutes, as I stated in the above questions about mask and vaccine mandates, would open up the district to damaging litigation.  Legal costs and potential damages could do irreparable harm to our district.  I pledge to always seek legal counsel before making any decisions that could directly affect our schools or taxpayers.",""]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a parent, I believe that a high-quality education is the best investment we can make in the lives of our children. Our children are growing up in a technological age that requires new skills and disciplines for success. There are unlimited career paths for our children, but only if they receive an education that has prepared them for those opportunities.","As an educator, I understand the challenges teachers and students face. Through the course of those years, I have worked to implement STEM, Business Education and Performing Visual Arts initiatives that have served as role models for other districts throughout Maryland and nationwide. ","I am eager to share my experience, knowledge, and fresh perspective to help facilitate the continued growth and development of our children for success in the 21st century and beyond.",""]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe the biggest priority this district faces is preparing all of our students for the 21st Century in terms of STEAM opportunities, which is why I am glad to see in its Comprehensive Plan an effort to increase programming and student achievement in these areas. I believe that my background, experience, and resources would bring to the board a perspective on STEAM education that many do not have. I am known for my out-of-the box approach to current educational issues and challenges, producing results that are modeled in other school districts. It would be my honor, if elected, to bring this experience to the board and district as it embarks on its ambition three-year Comprehensive Plan."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["See Next Question"]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe each student deserves to be in a healthy and safe environment that promotes learning. With that as our goal, mask policies should be evaluated based on the transmission rate in our district. If the district reaches an acceptable rate of infection and remains below that rate, masking should be optional. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe children’s vaccination should be a parental decision, unless mandated by the State. In order to ensure our children are in a healthy and safe environment, I believe staff should be vaccinated or provide weekly test results while masking is mandated.  If masking is optional, it will remain mandatory for those staff who are unvaccinated, or guidance has changed from local or state health agencies."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity and inclusion today are often overshadowed by race and gender.  This misconception distracts from the true intention of respect and kindness towards others.  Our children must be able to work with others both professionally and socially.  Teaching diversity and inclusion is the foundation for this soft skill.  Diversity and inclusion strategies must be incorporated into our existing curriculum to prepare our children for the 21st century. Utilizing tools such as “The Compassion Project” as an example would assist with implementation.  Elementary students should begin with learning and practicing compassion.  The next progression is for Middle School students to further extend the concepts to include identifying, understanding, and controlling emotions.  Finally High School students continue the concepts learned by practicing mindfulness through evidence-based practices, to encourage dialogue across diverse viewpoints and create an environment that is truly inclusive."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Since I was young, I have always been intrigued and interested in history. I do not believe in critical race theory, but rather a more inclusive American History. Many parents are unaware that there is no standardized textbook for history across K-12 schools in the U.S, unlike math or other subject areas.  Students can travel from one district to another and receive a different textbook and perspective on U.S. history. All students would benefit in the development of their critical thinking skills from an unbiased, inclusive history curriculum."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_charles_fallin","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["School should be a nurturing and safe space for our children to grow academically, socially, and emotionally while being protected from violence, aggression, abuse, and fear of being hurt.  According to the Gay, Lesbian & Straight Education Network’s (GLSEN), more than 87% of LGBTQ+ students experience school bullying and harassment, and their school victimization is strongly associated with mental health issues and substance abuse. As educators and parents, this statistic clearly shows we are failing some of our students and if we are failing one, we are failing all.  We must do better by establishing an environment where all students are safe. We must develop more harassment, bullying, and non-discrimination policies. We also need policies for facilities accessibility for trans, gender non-conforming, and non-binary students. Partnering and working with fellow educators in GLSEN, both students and educators can begin the process of creating the nurturing and safe space we envision.  "]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["The fear of God! When it's all said and done, I'll be held accountable to Him who Created all things for the decisions I made and will make. The Dover community needs people who believe that representing parents, educating children, and choosing how to spend tax dollars are not going to waver with the social issues of the times, but stand firm on truth."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Currently the top issue in Dover is one of overreaching power which is showing parents their voices are not important to the district. School board directors work on behalf of the community, not the school, not personal feelings, or political agendas. My plan is to carry out the duties of a school board director with the community and the students' future in mind. Complete transparency is key!"]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Advertise the benefits of good nutrition and vitamins, keep the schools and buses clean."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["No. We all have been given the ability to make decisions for ourselves by God and in America we have always stood for that opportunity to choose. This issue is no different."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["No. Again, we should always have the right to choose. If we stand for freedom in this country, then we apply that idea to health concerns as well. Viruses are going to come and go. If we start forcing people to mask and vaccinate out of fear (control), then when will it stop?"]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":[" I believe the district should focus their efforts on making sure they're delivering the best education to prepare our students to become great citizens. Quality educators and curriculum can open minds and help students become positive contributors to society."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Curriculum should not be chosen to address social problems. Curriculum should be chosen based on its merit as a non-bias resource. "]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_2_year_term_carmen_witmer","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Schools have a responsibility to educate on history, math, science, and language arts. Families have a responsibility to their children to help them navigate the growing years emotionally and socially. An educational institute does not need to use time and tax dollars highlighting the personal lives of students."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experiences of starting and managing a successful business , serving as a Board of Director of several community non-profit organizations as well as a commercial bank. I am completing my 16th year on the SYCSD board and chairman of the Building and Grounds Committee. Community organizations that I have served as a director are as follows; York Hospital, Wellspan Health, South Central Preferred, York and York County YMCA, York-Adams Council of BSA and New Freedom Heritage. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["One of the biggest issues that I see is the need for the state legislature to address the accountability and funding of charters schools. Basically the state, through local taxpayers, is funding two different school systems. One, the public school system, that is subject to many costly mandates and the other, private for-profit charter schools, that do not have to adhere to the public school mandates yet are funded with public funds. Although public schools continue to outperform the vast majority of charter schools, the state's quarter-of-a- century old charter school legislation continues to pour money into for-profit charter schools. This has put a tremendous financial burden on all public schools that is passed on to the local taxpayers.","I plan on continuing to lobby our legislature to change the legislation and better fund our public schools. PA's approximately 33% funding of public schools is one of the lowest ","funding levels of all 50 states."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Our school district has a health and safety plan that outlines our steps to address COVID","in our schools. If the CDC, FDA and PA Health Department make suggestions that would alter the existing plan then the school would review the existing plan and make changes as warranted."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, it is a proven scientific fact that masks reduce the transmission of the COVID virus."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, it is a proven scientific fact that the vaccines work as predicted."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["I think our policies address diversity and inclusion quite adequately. That is not to say that they will not change but probably will be updated as time moves on."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Our administration and teachers are always looking for ways to update and advance our curriculum to benefit our students. I am not aware of any changes being proposed at this time."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_james_r._holley","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I think our policies address LGBTQ students quite adequately. That in not to say that they will not change but probably will be updated as time moves on. All of our students need to feel safe and valued and not discriminated against."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a long-time resident and parent of students in the district, I am deeply committed to its success. I am confident that because of my experiences, I can help build consensus and ensure we continue to support the mission of our school district. I worked for a global life sciences company for 17 years as a scientific support specialist, advising customers and troubleshooting problems. I am now working as a project manager and scientific advisor for a nonprofit organization that has coordinated over $800 million in charitable contributions to causes such as mental health and education. This has given me valuable experience in working with large budgets and long-term projects. In meeting the challenges in our schools’ future, transparency and communication are critical. I have spent my entire career listening, troubleshooting, and advising. I know how critical it is to work together to untangle an issue and ensure that everyone feels heard in order to reach consensus."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The challenges of the past two years have resulted in division in our community--yet we know what’s possible when we all come together around shared goals. The divisions we’ve been feeling can be overcome with patience and a desire to work together. This can be accomplished with increased communication. A layered approach to getting community feedback works best. I think using surveys for gathering information from a large group followed by smaller focus group discussions and 1:1 conversations ensures full understanding of emotionally charged issues. These are good opportunities for 2-way communication between the board and the community. Concerns can be raised, reflected back to the community to ensure they’ve been accurately understood, and then solutions can be discussed. It is also crucial to ensure that staff and students continue to have the resources and support that they need to overcome continued and residual challenges from months of alternate instruction methods."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["School districts should use a multi-pronged approach to address COVID. They should follow CDC, US Department of Education, and PA Department of Education guidance for maximizing in-person learning for students. This includes wearing masks in times of high and substantial transmission, distancing when feasible, and improving/increasing ventilation."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Both the CDC and AAP currently recommend masking indoors to prevent the spread of COVID-19, especially to those unable to be vaccinated, like children. I think the current SYC district health and safety plan with the mask requirement aims to reduce risk of illness and prioritize in-person learning. I don’t want to see schools close or large groups of students out of school quarantining. Like everyone else, I look forward to transmission rates coming down so the requirement can be lifted. In the meantime, I know we, as parents, teachers, and staff, are working to find solutions where possible to make the requirement as easy as possible for our students."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["In my opinion, the decision to receive a vaccine is between an individual and their doctor. If the Pennsylvania Department of Education adds the COVID-19 vaccine to the list of school vaccination requirements for the state, families would have the same options for an exemption that they currently have for other vaccines required by the state."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Staff should be equipped to promote safe, inclusive, and welcoming learning environments for all students. The proposed comprehensive plan for SYCSD includes a focus on students’ career awareness and preparation and highlights interpersonal skills including problem-solving, critical thinking, civil discussion, and collaboration as tools for success. To that end, encouraging a constructive dialogue focused on understanding and respect is crucial to community unity, and I believe teachers and staff can achieve this without personal bias."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I support the work our excellent teachers are doing in the classroom and believe they should continue to have the academic freedom to explore various perspectives. I am not in favor of any curriculum or instructional methods that would be divisive or make students feel bad about themselves. It’s important to create space for discussion on current events and social justice issues so students can explore ideas in a safe, neutral environment. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_erin_ross","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I believe every student has a right to feel safe all the time and be free from discrimination. School policy should make it clear that discrimination is not tolerated, equity is prioritized, and individual privacy and confidentiality are maintained. Current student organizations that support these principals should be encouraged and maintained. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["There are many great candidates running for school board director;  we have the opportunity to fill 5 seats this November.  As a volunteer in our district since our children were in kindergarten (now in the middle and high school); I remember the joy of serving and the importance of connecting with children in class.  Professionally, I have worked within a career for 25 years with the same company solving problems, working together to achieve a common goal and appreciating the gifts and talents that all bring to the table.  Within my experience of listening, collaborating, asking questions, restoring checks/balances, and resolving difficulty; I will be an asset to the board for our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our district is divided;  unity is what is needed and with transparency, open forums and collaboration within the community we can restore trust that is now broken.  Many parents and community members reach out to the board with many issues and there is no response to their concerns.   They feel their voices are not heard, decisions are made without the tax payers input and not in favor of their majority voice.  Information at board meetings  is more  of advising the community of what is coming rather then giving them an option to have effective input on many current issues creating disunity. This needs to change and I will advocate for education with no bias for our children.  Our world is changing rapidly; engaging with families is more important then ever right now. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Certainly hand washing measures and practical communication with families to  keep their children home if unwell (fever) just as with any virus.  We need to live with this; without hindering our children's ability to learn and disregarding parental rights.  Families  should  have the option to decide if their child should  be masked at school or vaccinated; this is not for the school to enforce or  decide for parents and  guardians."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["No, in my research I understand and believe masking to be a hindrance to learning and not effective in preventing the spread of COVID."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["No, this is not for the  school district to mandate or decide for families.   This is a private decision between a patient and caregiver; not the school  board or administrator."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We are a diverse nation; and the very definition of inclusion is to educate with a model of students with special needs spending their time with non special needs children.  No issue, unless a particular group is pushing for a social agenda that doesn't belong in schools."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["CRT has no place in school.  Teaching children that they are  oppressors or oppressed because of their race is poison for young minds.  All should have equal opportunity to succeed regardless of race; we are all Humans, not separated or defined by color.  "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_marylee_hall","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Same as Heterosexual; the focus of these private choices should be within an individual; and the basics of life (birds and bees) learned at home and in Health Class.  Not to be  promoted among students as to force ideology.  This is a private matter; not a public one."]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["School board has more power than people think. It's not just taxes or hiring a superintendent - look no further than Central York's book ban to see the real, daily impact a board can have. I'm the only candidate in our race with experience teaching at any level (I'm a college adjunct), with analyzing school budgets, with talking with teacher unions, and much more. That matters when big decisions are made, and I can fairly say that I'm not just a father of three Bobcats - I'm an experienced candidate who can navigate conversations about mill rates and standardized testing approaches."]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Northeastern is an incredible district, with a high school among the higher performing in the region, and faculty who I have personally seen go above and beyond. But our area is also exploding in growth - new warehouses and housing developments seem to go up every month. It is crucial that we find ways to limit tax increases while handling more and more students coming in, which will put a big strain on building capacity and teacher workloads. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I was proud at seeing how Northeastern has handled things so far: daily case updates, Bobcat Cyber Academy led by our own Northeastern teachers, and laptops for all (although remembering to charge them is a daily task!). We need to keep protecting our youngest students who aren't eligible for vaccines. And we also can't assume that even post-vaccination/post-pandemic, that the disparity in technology available at home and in access to adequate healthcare will go away. Continuing to be innovative and dedicating the resources needed to make sure students can succeed at home as well as in the classroom matters, COVID or not."]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, because a large population in Northeastern isn't eligible yet for a vaccine; cases are rising of children with COVID. A mask isn't comfortable and it makes teaching difficult - I have to wear one teaching a class myself. But if it is going to help a student not need a hospital visit or their immunocompromised family member become gravely ill, that's what you do. The argument that parents should get to decide about their child makes sense if it didn't impact anyone else. This impacts everyone. A mask isn't foolproof, but a seatbelt isn't either; I still wear one because it can make a difference. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, barring a severe medical issue. Public health means we all take steps that may otherwise seem like a personal decision because it affects the larger population. If schools decided not to require the polio vaccine anymore because it's up to parents, you are asking for an outbreak that could have been prevented. COVID is no different, especially now that the vaccine is FDA-approved and there should be an extra layer of confidence."]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We aren't doing enough, even as I appreciate the individual efforts I've seen administrators and teachers take to have, for example, books written by authors of color and including more diverse holiday celebrations and topics in the classroom. A diverse student body as well as students who identify as LGBTQ+ will be in your district - you can approach this as something to celebrate and create opportunities to learn, or you can, as some do, choose to ignore it. Be known for being a district that truly helps all students succeed. "]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["One way to look at it is that an all white board choosing textbooks written by mostly white authors to be used by mostly white teachers is going to inherently lead to bias. Acknowledge the situation. Acknowledge racism's place in history. Although some may see that as a push for CRT, it's important to note that CRT is not being taught anywhere in Northeastern. It's possible to talk about race and racism's place in the building of our country - and how it impacts us today - and it be a positive learning experience for any student."]},{"candidateCode":"northeastern_school_director_andrew_shaw","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["This is a crucial issue. Suicide rates are highest amongst this population compared to their peers. Being known as a district that welcomes all matters, especially as students are growing and finding their identity. From the board's perspective, this can be about how to approach hiring - asking administrators how they plan on creating an inclusive environment - and having zero tolerance for bigotry and hatred."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have 33 years of experience as a professional educator and am the proud mother of a Central York graduate. I earned a master’s degree in education from Johns Hopkins University and have served as a classroom teacher, special education case manager, and instructional support coach. As a member of the school board, I would draw on my extensive background in education to ensure our district is implementing practical, research-validated instructional practices that meet the needs of each student.","","As a Central York parent, my experiences extend beyond the traditional educational setting and into our broader community as well. I was an active and involved parent during my son’s time as a member of the Central York High School marching band and served as a Scout leader for 10 years. At a time when our school district is confronted with constantly changing instructional models and educational standards, we need experienced leaders who understand our community.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Ensuring growth and learning for ALL students should be our school district’s most important issue. Unfortunately, student learning metrics have plummeted in recent years as a result of the current school board’s misplaced priorities. This trend threatens our students’ college acceptance rates and future earning potential, but it could also jeopardize local property values because school quality is one of the biggest influences on the housing market. ","","Research has consistently found that teacher quality is the number one school-based factor that influences student learning. As Pennsylvania faces a teacher shortage, we need leaders who will network with teacher preparation programs at the college and university level in order to recruit the best teachers for our school district. We need to examine and address  the underlying factors that influence student performance, so that our district’s county-wide ranking does not continue to fall."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["School districts have the responsibility of acting in the best interest of students, families, and the community. The school board should follow the guidelines set forth by the Department of Health because doing so is in the best interest of students and taxpayers. Ideological beliefs and opinions have no place in decision-making regarding health and safety. We are in the midst of a catastrophic pandemic and should listen to the experts. This includes medical experts, but it also includes legal experts. The district has received legal advice that defying state pandemic mitigation policy could expose taxpayers to unnecessary legal risk. Therefore, our district should follow the current guidance in order to keep our children safe and shield our taxpayers from the effects of costly litigation.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["As an educator, I have seen firsthand that children and teenagers learn significantly better in-person than they do remotely. We must keep our students and staff healthy so that our district can more easily satisfy the academic, social, and emotional needs of our students in an in-person school setting. The best way to keep schools open is to follow the guidance of experts and remain in compliance with the Pennsylvania Department of Health and Department of Education. This approach also avoids potential lawsuits at the expense of taxpayers. We must avoid the pressure to put students and taxpayers in harm’s way just to make a political statement. As elected officials, we have a responsibility to act in the best interest of our community and eliminate politics from decision-making."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["In Pennsylvania, this decision has historically been decided by the General Assembly rather than individual school boards. I support keeping it this way. Most school boards do not have the resources and expertise to make a decision of this nature. Families should be able to make their own decisions about the vaccine without interference from the school board.  School board members should focus on helping our educators and our students have a safe and enriching learning experience, not on sharing disinformation or personal beliefs in a matter as important as this. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We live in a beautifully diverse community that should be wholeheartedly embraced. Students need to learn through windows and mirrors. Mirrors allow us to see and examine ourselves, and get a glimpse into our history. Windows allow us to see other experiences and cultures, learn history, examine perspectives, and identify shared experiences. Last year, the current school board had the opportunity to adopt a social studies curriculum, which had been reviewed and recommended by professional educators and administrators, and included diversity education. Unfortunately, the board voted to table the curriculum without taking a vote. Then came a ban on a diversity resource list compiled by the Diversity Committee. We cannot lead in fear, and must address difficult issues without punting on decision making. The Pennsylvania Department of Education’s standards very clearly address diversity, and we have an obligation to prepare our students to be successful global citizens.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The Pennsylvania Department of Education has a resource list addressing this issue which can be accessed here: https://www.education.pa.gov/Schools/safeschools/equityandinclusion/Pages/RacialEthnic.aspx.","The state recognizes the need to address race and racism in classrooms and our district should too. The first step should be an immediate adoption of the proposed social studies curriculum and an immediate review of the diversity resource list. Issues regarding race and racism are very real and very detrimental to individuals and society at large. When we’re silent on the subject, we reinforce the status quo. When we avoid the subject, we’re communicating to students of color that racism doesn’t matter enough to foster honest discussion which in turn invalidates their life experiences and identities. We owe all of our students the opportunity to learn about themselves and others; their past histories and current realities.",""]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_rebecca_l._riek","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["As a teacher, I accept all students as they come to me, without exception, and I think that’s what all parents want for their children: acceptance. A school board has no authority to draft policy, particularly regarding transgender issues. School boards should follow case law as well as state and federal statutes. While there are strong feelings on all sides of this issue, school boards should defer to legal counsel, and schools should create safe environments for all students, as they are."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have no political experience; however, my community service experience is extensive.  I have been a member of York-East Rotary for 15 years, and served as club president in 2008-2009.  York-East Rotary community outreach programs Road Cleanup, scholarships for York County students, and fundraising for York County nonprofits. From 2010-2014, I served on the board of Family-Child Resources, an organization which oversees mental and physical health needs of York County families.  I served as president of York Little League from 2018-2020, representing York County on an international stage of children and families from all over the world."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["It is difficult to imagine any issue more pressing than the global health crisis created by COVID-19 and its variants.  The new school board must navigate the responsibilities of educating our students against the backdrop of of this new reality."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Lacking board members with backgrounds in virology, microbiology, infectious disease, or similar fields of study requiring expertise in fields, puts the decision-makers where they should rely upon those with this knowledge.  I believe the board should heed the guidance of the CDC, FDA, Department of Health, and the American Association of Pediatrics."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The answer here must remain fluid and based on changing conditions.  The decision to mandate masks, if not executed by the state or federal government, should be based upon the expertise of organizations like the PA Dept. of Health, CDC, etc.  I do believe that masks should be required for all unvaccinated persons.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Vaccine mandates have always existed for the greater good.  However, the decision of whether or not to require the COVID vaccine should come from healthcare experts in state and federal governments."]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["At present, diversity only exists in Central York School District at the student level.  Clearly, representation is an issue.  The current version of the school board is uniformly aligned across every demographic except for gender.  Congruent mindset and group-think allowed bad ideas, like banning books written by and about unrepresented peoples, to go unchallenged.  Electing diverse board members, and hiring diverse administrators and faculty members would be a major step in the right direction with regard to addressing diversity and inclusivity issues.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Sharing the truth about history does not constitute indoctrination.  Manipulating historical facts, cherry-picking information,  and limiting which perspectives will be taught are what sets you on the path of indoctrination.   At this point in time, I do not have specific curriculum changes or additions in mind; however, I believe that discussions with educators, counselors, and equality experts should form the foundation for any curriculum changes.  "]},{"candidateCode":"central_york_school_director_2_year_term_lydell_d._nunn","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our schools should be a welcoming, safe haven for all of the students in our district. I recognize that gaps likely exist between this ideal and where we are in actual practice pertaining to LGBTQ+ students.  The district should have open discussions to determine how our LGBTQ+ students can be better supported in the district."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I possess the skills, experience and collective reasoning to help move our district forward, as it embarks on its three-year comprehensive plan and long-term construction projects. My goal is to help keep our school board focused on academic excellence and student achievement for all, expansion of life preparedness social programs, and financial accountability and transparency to our community. I have a passion for doing the right things for the right reasons. I have a work ethic and dedication to make a positive impact on the decisions promoting the future success of our students and I have the passion and experience needed to effectively work with all of the school board members, regardless of whether we agree on every issue. and have real-life experiences which will allow me to be effective as a school board director."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["After witnessing (and personally experiencing) a turbulent 2020 school year with lots of distractions from learning, my passion for excellence and equity in education has led me to run for a position on the school board, so that I can help make a difference to the children in our community, because everyone deserves a high-quality education without distractions"]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is a decision made the state level. "]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is a decision made the state level"]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["In order for the SYCSD to continue to pave the way for success of our students, we need to also continue to focus on creating an inclusive environment. I am a strong proponent of implementation of  measures to facilitate inclusion  for ALL students in our school district, including our LGBTQ+ community."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["When students feel safe and affirmed, they can thrive both academically and socially. We need to foster understanding and respect for all people  I do know that it is important for us all to always consider various perspectives, as a means to further inclusion in our own community. We need to have discussions so we all understand the nuances of each others cultures and how to respect those and respect each other as individuals and human beings."]},{"candidateCode":"southern_york_county_school_director_2_year_term_laura_crawmer","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["In order for the SYCSD to continue to pave the way for success of our students, we need to also continue to focus on creating an inclusive environment. I am a strong proponent of implementation of  measures to facilitate inclusion  for ALL students in our school district, including our LGBTQ+ community. Again, when students feel safe and affirmed, they can thrive both academically and socially."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been a Dover resident for 24 years and have three children that attended Dover schools. I believe I have a good idea of what our community of parents are looking for in a partnership with their public school system that, basically, co-parents their children. Our children are our community’s greatest asset and I am passionate about making sure each child graduates with the skills and abilities to take on the next chapter in their lives and be productive members of our society. Parent input and communication is key to ensuring a successful public education experience and I will work hard to keep those lines of communication open."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our top issue is the mask mandate and the transfer of some families to another district. I will fight against the mask mandate and for masking to be the choice of the parent and student. K fear the mask mandate will lead to a vaccine mandate and I also fear it inhibits the educational experience for teachers and students. The forced move of some families to another district may be a mute point because that had been decided in a hard fought court case but I’d be willing to hear out the concerned and impacted parents."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I believe COVID policy needs to be decided at the school board level and then followed and implemented by the superintendent. I would fight to place an emphasis on personal hygiene and daily disinfectant of high touch areas. Common sense goes a long way fighting COVID, keeping your child home if they show signs of illness, washing hands and keeping classrooms clean would be the policies I support."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["No one should be required to wear masks in schools. I fear mask wearing is creating division and fear and is creating more problems than it is solving. Our children need to be able to communicate, interact and learn with as little distractions as possible. From what I understand, masks are a huge distraction and most student don’t take mask wearing seriously. Masks are dropped, shared, shoved in backpacks and reused making them unhealthy and germ infested."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Vaccine mandates are an infringement on our civil liberties and open the door to continued governmental rule that moves us closer and closer to a socialist society. I will fight against any and all government overreach that impacts our ability to make individual choices for ourselves and our families. "]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The more we focus on diversity, the more division we create. This question poses quite the dichotomy doesn’t it? How can one create inclusion by addressing diversity? With all due respect, this question does not make sense. But, I understand the point. Instead of focusing on diversity or inclusion, I would prefer we focus on math, reading, writing, science, sports, band, drama, etc. Let each student decide what interests them and let them determine where they fit in and excel."]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Our curriculum needs to teach math, reading , writing, science, etc. We don’t need to teach or address racism. We don’t need to point out differences. Pointing out differences will create division. We need to be one, unified, school district. We are Dover Eagles teaching our children to be productive members of society who treat each other with respect, who are loyal, honest and accountable to each other and our community. We  need to ensure our K-12 public education equips our children to enter the next stage of their life, support themselves, be able to write a coherent email, balance a checkbook, save money and be humble enough to be an employee and learn new skills and trades. We won’t get that from students if we continue to impress upon them a victim mentality. We want strong, confident young adults ready to take on the world with grace and humility! "]},{"candidateCode":"dover_area_school_director_heidi_mease","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our district needs to have a strong anti bullying campaign with clear behavioral expectations and consistent disciplinary actions. We also need to ensure every student has a school faculty member that they feel comfortable going to to discuss an emotional issue. Every student should be supported equally regardless of race, ethnicity or sexual orientation. LGBTQ+ students shouldn’t get any more or any less support from the district than any other student."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a YS alumni, the educational experience I received established a foundation for me to succeed both personally and professionally. When my family and I moved back to York in 2010, our decision of where to raise a family was simple because York Suburban is a wonderful community and the same level of academic excellence was still being provided.  As a parent, resident and business owner, I want nothing more than to see our District continue the tradition of excellence and give that academic foundation to all students. My experience as a first term board member, community resident, and business owner gives me a well-rounded perspective on how to best approach the challenges of the near future.  My most important qualification, that of a father with children currently attending York Suburban schools, means I’m personally invested in our district’s future and helps me understand the needs of children in the areas of academics, emotional support and extracurricular activities. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We face an annual structural budgetary deficit.  Continued implementation of state mandated spending programs, additional Covid related costs and inflationary pressures are making matters even worse.  As a school board, we must carefully assess each spending request and make decisions which are in the best interests of our students, our staff and our constituents.  The same thought process applies when considering our decisions on increasing the tax rate.  For me, it comes down to two things:  (1) Does this maximize the academic experience for students?; and (2) Is it in the best interests of our district and constituents?   "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Our district has made and will continue to make decisions related to Covid which maximize the number of in-person instructional days for the kids.  That includes following PA Department of Health guidance related to Covid while keeping in mind what is in the best interests of our local constituents.  "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Our district is currently following the mandated mask policy put forth by the PA Department of Health.  When that mandate is lifted, I will take into account our local conditions, the needs of our students, teachers and staff and the recommendations from our administration when the board is making decisions.  My two key questions when considering this are:  (1) Does this maximize the academic experience; and (2) Is it in the best interests of our district?   "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is not a decision within the power of the School Board.  If the legislature votes for this requirement and it is signed into law, then PA schools will implement the law.  Our number one job is maximize the educational experience for our students in the most fiscally responsible manner.  The members of the board are not elected to set healthcare policy.  "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The makeup of our district is diverse and changing, and our district’s continued focus on academic excellence for all students has been consistent.  A hallmark of that excellence is the way our teachers, administrators and staff adapt to shifting demographics to support all students.  My goal as a school board member is to make decisions that allow for all students to have equal access to the tools that will maximize their educational experience.  Our schools should work in tandem with parents to be welcoming to everyone, always keeping in mind our common goal of academic excellence.  Through my years of volunteer work with the YMCA, the Children’s Home of York, York Suburban Education Foundation, Rotary Club of York, Junior Achievement, SCORE and other community organizations, I’ve seen first-hand the importance of supporting diversity across our community to become stronger."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["As our school district’s demographic continues to evolve and change, we must continue to hire and train administrators, teachers and staff who are engaged and able to adapt to change, while maintaining focus on academic excellence.  Again, my role as a school board member is to make decisions that allow for all students to have equal access to the tools that will maximize their educational experience.  "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_james_r._sanders","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our district should be welcoming and respectful to all, creating a positive environment in the community that lifts us to achieve our goal and mission of academic excellence.  All children in the York Suburban community deserve every opportunity to succeed in life, and excellent education is a critically important part of that success.  "]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a concerned citizen and mother of a York Suburban student, I began paying close attention to the School Board in the last few years. Like many parents, I felt as though the Board did not consider the opinion of the community in many key areas. While I never imagined I would run for office, I felt compelled to step forward on behalf of the community. Before moving home 8 years ago to raise my family, I worked in the US Congress where I researched and analyzed public policy issues, including education. I believe that my passion as a concerned citizen and mom combined with my experience will make me a strong advocate for restoring community voices on the School Board."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The school district faces a budget deficit every year of more than $2 million. Unfunded state mandates and flawed funding formulas make the problem worse. Our nonpartisan Business Office projects maximum tax increases every year – and it still won’t fix the problem. We can’t tax (or cut) our way out of the financial crisis that the controlling members of this Board have allowed to get worse every year. It will require the cooperation and creativity of the School Board, Administration, parents, taxpayers, and state and local officials to fix the problem without taxing residents out of their homes or hurting the quality of education. It starts on Election Day by voting for new leadership committed to fiscal responsibility."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["We must give fair weight to both guidance from parents and the community as well as the PA Department of Health. I support making decisions related to Covid that maximize in-person instruction for students. The pandemic and student isolation has led to our students falling behind in their academic skills and learning. And York Suburban’s school social worker has warned about our students’ pandemic-induced significant mental health issues. We are seeing severe issues in kids of all ages. There is much work to be done in service to the kids in our community."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support parental choice with respect to masks. Our district is currently following the mandated mask policy put forth by the PA Department of Health. If elected, I will continue to evaluate our local conditions and the data regarding student health at our schools. While people can respectfully disagree on this issue, we know that no one wants to keep children in masks any longer than is necessary. Experts agree that their learning and mental health will be positively impacted with a return to normalcy."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["This authority belongs to the state and not School Boards. That being said, I am opposed to forced vaccinations of children against the wishes of parents."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["One of York Suburban’s greatest strengths is the diversity of our students and community. We must ensure equal access to a great education for all students at York Suburban. However, the diversity on the School Board is sorely lacking. If elected, I will be the only mother of a current student in York Suburban schools. Currently, only two of the nine Board Members are women. We need more parents and community members of all backgrounds and races to ensure a more representative Board."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Children are born without prejudice. They value and respect their friends and classmates regardless of their differences. We must foster that precious instinct in kids by supporting diversity and opposing efforts to divide children. To do so, School Boards must work to ensure transparency between the School Administration and the community and parents about what is being taught to students."]},{"candidateCode":"york_suburban_school_director_nicole_mccleary","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our common goal is to ensure that all York Suburban students have equal access to the tools they need to achieve a high-quality education, free of discrimination. LGBTQ+ students included."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_loren_frasco","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been an active member of the community serving on the Steering Committee for the University Village,  Chairperson of the Community and Business Committee and Vice Chairperson on the Planning Commission. I have lived in the borough for over 30 years and have worked to organize our neighborhood to address issues of safety and oversee the growth in our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_loren_frasco","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Change. Our community is in the midst of change. Development is in our future and we need to control how that is brought about. Changes to zoning to encourage the type of development that will enhance our Borough and not make it unrecognizable. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_loren_frasco","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We in New Britain Borough encourage and support our businesses. As Chairperson of the Community and Business Committee we look to enhance the relationship between the community and businesses by encouraging local events bringing people into our community to enjoy all we have to offer and encouraging businesses to be a part of our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_loren_frasco","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["As the borough revitalizes we need to look at ways for people to travel safely through our borough. Lighting, underground utility poles, traffic flow, bike lanes are all important to our community. Water is another major issue. We need to ensure that public water is available to the businesses and community who want or need it. Continuing to apply for grants to allow us to address these issues in a cost effective way is key."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_loren_frasco","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Marijuana has been decriminalized in many of the communities around us. It seems the tide has turned and we need to update our laws to reflect changes in the mindset of the community. Allowing our police and court system to deal with criminals of much higher degree of seriousness. I do believe marijuana needs to be regulated to ensure it is used in a safe way, similar to alcohol."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_loren_frasco","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Definitely. There is no place in society for intolerance. We all are entitled to live our lives in safety and equal opportunity. A person’s sexuality is their own business and should not prevent them from enjoying all the benefits our Borough can offer. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_loren_frasco","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support keeping people healthy and safe. I wear my seat belt in my car, I shovel my driveway and walkway to ensure my family and delivery people are safe to walk on my property in winter. I see wearing a mask as my small part I can do to keep my community safe. If our community spread gets to such a high level that it is necessary to save lives, yes, I would support a mask mandate. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_scott_bomboy","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My love of Perkasie is well-documented. I will always put Perkasie first. I have actively served residents since 2016 by chairing council’s Public Safety committee, leading our historic preservation efforts, and making sure all residents and visitors are treated with respect and have a voice. There is no substitute for experience!"]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_scott_bomboy","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our top challenge is balancing land development with quality-of-life issues. We can address this by 1) revising our Comprehensive Plan to improve our Parks and Rec system, 2) investing more in road repairs and public parking to meet growth issues, and 3) adding more open space in the borough. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_scott_bomboy","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I have strongly supported economic development in my five years on borough council. Our plan includes bringing more food and retail business options to town; granting permit relief for business start-ups; keeping taxes low; and providing business support from our economic development team. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_scott_bomboy","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our biggest need is a better response from PennDOT about fixing its roads in Perkasie. I worked with state officials to get Main Street repaved in 2019. I also support a more aggressive local road repair policy. Parking and open space are two other priorities for the next borough council"]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_scott_bomboy","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As an elected official, I took an oath to support our state constitution. I believe legalization must be settled in the state legislature or by state constitutional amendment. For Perkasie, the question could be presented as a voter referendum. But I have doubts about local decriminalization’s legality. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_scott_bomboy","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I would invite debate about a local non-discrimination ordinance establishing a commission to hear disputes about discrimination based on race, color, age, religion, sex, veteran status, disability, sexual orientation and gender identity. These ordinances already exist in 69 Pa. towns. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_scott_bomboy","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["The borough legally can’t force residents to wear masks. It can require masks for entry to public buildings in some situations. Residents should respect the wishes of local institutions requiring masks to enter a building. And people should follow county and state health department mask guidelines. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_john_brady","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I lived here since 1998 and want to take part in the function of our borough.  I am welcoming to new ideas, opinions and meeting people to collaborate solutions for additional benefits of our community. What is important to me is for people to be easily heard and addressed without prejudgments; timelines of projects and solutions move efficiently to completion; and the Boroughs operations are financially responsible, effective, safe, and secure.  ","I do like to seek challenges both physically and mentally.  My careers have relied on business relationships developed by good listening skills, follow up, and successful execution to earn a paycheck. I ask the borough to vote for John Brady, and if elected I will be easy to reach and work smart for the betterment of New Britain Borough.",""]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_john_brady","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Financial Reserves need to be built up.  We need to find ways to reduce spending, possibly by incorporating additional boroughs into the central bucks police dept and other ventures to reduce our overall cost."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_john_brady","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Entertain ideas for more events in the borough, suggest a link via https://www.newbritainboro.com ie: Discover New Britain local business"]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_john_brady","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Infrastructure looks ok, Many dead trees are a concern  as well as very slow moving projects with vacant lots empty building on business 202. These locations need to be approached and addressed."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_john_brady","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes as long if it is in line the PA state law."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_john_brady","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["All people in New Britain borough regardless of who they are, are to feel safe and protected."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_john_brady","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Businesses and individuals can have the  choice to require or wear the mask, mandates can be left up to the state. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_chuck_brooks","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Having been on the council for the past eight years and having held numerous chairmanship positions, I have a vast variety of experience and clear understanding of local government and Perkasie related requirements.  In conjunction with fellow council members, my efforts have been instrumental in reshaping the direction of Perkasie while continuing to preserve the hometown charm and feel of our special community."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_chuck_brooks","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The continuation of building business growth within the Town Center.  I will continue to work closely with future business owners and developers to assure constant growth.  Therefore, assuring the members of our community the opportunity to “Buy Local” and to enjoy all that Perkasie has to offer."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_chuck_brooks","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I believe that working closely with Planning Commission and using the Comprehensive Plan as our road map will ensure the best path for economic vitality in Perkasie.  Continued patronage of local establishments will only enhance the cause and the creation of enthusiasm within the community for up and coming establishments will ensure success.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_chuck_brooks","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["I have for years stressed the need to front-load our roads programs within the Borough.  As funding runs scarce from the state level and gas tax funding is diverted to other state requirements, boroughs and municipalities are left “holding the bag”.  The council must allocate more funding to make up the difference and assure that the roads program remains timely and progressive."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_chuck_brooks","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would not support measures to decriminalize marijuana.  The Borough is not in a position to counter state and federal law.  Therefore, until the law regarding marijuana has been changed, I do not think that the boroughs governing body needs to review and/or take any action regarding this matter.  "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_chuck_brooks","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["The Perkasie community is dedicated to supporting ALL forms of diversity as protected by law.  Municipal governing bodies are meant to govern within the framework of both state and federal laws.  Establishing certain protections for one group or another is not within the per view of the boroughs governing body.  Therefore, I do not support protections at a local level.  However, I do believe it is vitally important to recognize ALL groups and organizations within our community."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_chuck_brooks","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID and associated mask mandates should be directed through CDC guidelines.  If the State adopts a policy/statute or law regarding the use of masks the Borough should comply as necessary.  "]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_john_r._engel","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been a Borough Councillor since November, 2007 and honored to be the President of Council since January of 2012.  I never forget that my duty is to the citizens of Chalfont and totally support participation of the public.  It is my belief that all should serve their community and participate in their government.","","I have been a Troop 24 Boy Scout Leader, a member of the board of directors of the local ambulance service, and serve on the Central Bucks Regional Police Department Commission  while I have lived in Chalfont since 1982.  Chalfont is a wonderful place to live and I wish to help continue that by being a part of the local government.  ","","It is my firm belief that there should be no politics at the local government level and that the duty of a Chalfont Borough Councillor is to serve all citizens of Chalfont equally and fairly."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_john_r._engel","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["","","The biggest current challenges are stormwater management, traffic and roads as well as planning of development and its impact on the borough.  The Borough Council has a long term plan to address the storm water issues on a priority basis.  I support the Bristol Road Extension by PennDoT to help reduce congestion through the center of the Borough as well as providing necessary alternate routes for emergency vehicles such as Police, Fire and Ambulance services."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_john_r._engel","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We are working on a shared parking plan for the commercial corridor on Main Street.  Making the businesses in this corridor easier to access and providing more parking will bring more people and business into this area.  The results of a commissioned research study has highlighted the necessity of central parking and business accessibility as a real need to support business growth.","","In 2017 Chalfont Borough Council adopted an ordinance enacting the state’s Local Economic Revitalization Tax Assistance Act (LERTA). This is designation is focused on fostering development in the mostly industrial, commercial and mixed-use zoning districts along Butler Avenue and Main Street.","","Chalfont Borough property owners in the LERTA districts can apply for a five-year tax exemption on new construction. The exemption affects the tax assessed value of the improvements and is not a total exemption."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_john_r._engel","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The Borough has a long term plan to repair roads and constantly works with the Pennsylvania Department of Transportation to have them maintain the state roads and bridges under their exclusive control.  The Borough cannot do the work on these state roads but we continuously monitor these issues and bring them to the attention of Penn DoT.","","The other major issue is storm water management.  A priority list of needs is being addressed in a planned manner as this is a very high price tag Federal and State mandated issue.  The competition between need and cost is intense and we try to find every possible funding opportunity through grants and coordinated planning to do this in a responsible and effective financial manner."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_john_r._engel","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do support marijuana law review but strongly feel this should be done at the state level to avoid piecemeal and confusing enforcement.  I will not support total decriminalization until there is enough study of the long term health effects as well as a way to determine if a person is too impaired to drive a vehicle safely."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_john_r._engel","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I do support LGBTQ+ protection but feel this is another issue that needs to be coordinated at the State and County levels to give comprehensive protection to the all regardless of orientation.  "]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_john_r._engel","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do support measures to protect people from COVID.  I believe that every citizen has a right to their own opinion but must absolutely not endanger others through their behavior.  I support instituting protection based on science with guidance from the Center for Disease Control.  As a Borough Councillor I feel protection of our employees is a part of my duties and will support a mask mandate in our Borough offices should it be necessary for protection of all."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_amy_lustig","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a 24-year resident of Newtown Borough, I know and celebrate my town and its residents. I'm invested in community building and in bolstering an infrastructure that safely supports all those using our roads, sidewalks, and green spaces, particularly those enjoying the borough on foot and on bike. Having served on the borough's Beautification and Revitalization Committee and the Traffic and Parking Committee, I believe that balancing an appreciation for historic tradition with the awareness that change is essential for present and future prosperity is pivotal to the borough’s vitality."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_amy_lustig","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe the top issue facing Newtown Borough at present is well-symbolized by our physical infrastructure. Our roadways are defined by structures that have stood the test of time for centuries while vehicular traffic has burgeoned. We must find ways to preserve that history while finding innovative ways to improve, change, grow, and maintain safe spaces and passage for all.  "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_amy_lustig","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["In order to support Newtown Borough's businesses, I will work to Increase the borough's visibility and broaden its reach beyond the neighboring communities. I believe this can be achieved by using advertising and social media to invite residents and neighboring towns to Newtown Borough, a destination with incredible restaurants, unique shops, and beneficial services. It is also imperative to emphasize the value small businesses add to a community and to draw attention to supporting those places and owners."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_amy_lustig","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Newtown Borough's roads were not designed to accommodate a steady flow of vehicular traffic alongside pedestrians and cyclists, and therefore, dangerous conditions -- not to mention congestion -- are often present when navigating on foot and on bike. I believe that addressing these issues will require creative ways to adapt limited space, balance street spaces, develop pedestrian zones, and make crosswalks more visible. As some borough roads are owned by the state, we will need to work closely with agencies outside our perimeter to counter problems that have affected key roadways for years. With the development of greenways in adjoining areas, connecting the borough to spaces like rails-to trails is a priority."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_amy_lustig","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["This issue is unlikely to be decided at the municipal level."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_amy_lustig","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, I am in favor of anti-discriminatory protections as well as inclusive policy and practices facing the LGBTQ+ community and other marginalized groups."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_amy_lustig","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I  would follow the guidelines provided by medical and public health experts."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_marilyn_jacobson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I would like to continue working with our harmonious and competent members of Council to continue making Chalfont a wonderful “Hometown”.  Our residents enjoy the natural beauty of Chalfont’s Parks and Trails system year round.  I want to continue to make Chalfont a walkable and pedestrian-safe community:","•        by connecting parks with trails through grant acquisition; ","•        by updating our storm water and street infrastructure through grant acquisition; ","•        by encouraging resident participation in volunteer organizations and our local government; and ","•        by restoring our annual events including the Chalfont 5k Challenge, Fun Run and Chalfont Night.",""]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_marilyn_jacobson","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["•        Safety:  Completion of the new Central Bucks Regional Police Headquarters in 2021 will make us eligible for the completion of the Accreditation process in early 2022.  ","•        Traffic:  Recently the completion date of the Bristol Road Extension was delayed from 2025 to 2032 due to funding.  We need to find a way to restore the earlier completion date by working with our county, state, and federal representatives.","•        Increased walkability through Trail Connections:  Grant funding & Chalfont 5K Challenge profits will help in construction of the North Branch Neshaminy Trail.","•        Implementing the “Shared Parking” plan to provide increased parking and traffic mobility for our Borough core for the business community.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_marilyn_jacobson","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Chalfont is a participant in LERTA (Local Economic Revitalization Tax Assistance Program) that provides tax incentives to businesses.  Implementing the \"Shared Parking\" plan to provide increased parking and traffic.  Provide professional staff that will provide the required permits in a timely manner.   "]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_marilyn_jacobson","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["•        Maintenance of our infrastructure:  Replacement of ageing storm water infrastructure is a costly item.  Grant funding has helped in funding storm water replacement and street resurfacing in the Lindenfield area in 2022."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_marilyn_jacobson","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a municipality of 1.6 square miles, those decisions are best made of higher levels of government. "]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_marilyn_jacobson","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Our laws provide equal protection and service to all."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_marilyn_jacobson","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["The Borough has followed the guidelines provided by the C.D.C and the State and Bucks County Boards of Health."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_lauren_pareti","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Building kind, compassionate, safe and affordable communities has always been my passion. Having worked for more than 20 years directly with individuals and families in crisis and with the organizations that serve them, I’ll bring a unique perspective and skill set to the Council. I have helped communities to secure more than $160 million annually for housing and services. I also lead effortss to evaluate project outcomes to ensure that those funds are invested wisely and result in meaningful and measurable improvements in peoples’ lives. As we recover from the pandemic, I want to leverage my experience developing, evaluating, and funding projects that rebuild lives devastated by economic instability, addiction, homelessness, and mental health challenges. Currently, women comprise fifty-three percent of the Borough’s population, and the Borough Council is comprised of nine men. New voices, like mine, will make our government stronger and more responsive to our needs. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_lauren_pareti","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["My top priority will be ensuring that Perkasie has a bold vision and practical plan to succeed into the future, while maintaining our small town feel and historic charm. This means leveraging our strengths - small businesses, beautiful parks, well-established community events, and eligibility for three National Historic Districts. It also means finding creative solutions to challenges, including a decentralized business district, aging infrastructure, flooding, housing affordability, and growing division and lack of civility in public discourse. I will be a Councilwoman who understands that serving is about much more than attending meetings, taking votes, and showing up at ceremonies. I will contribute new ideas and energy to help our downtown thrive, preserve our history, protect our parks, plan for resiliency as the climate changes, and make certain that Perkasie remains a place where you know your neighbors and you don't have to be wealthy to provide your family with a nice home. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_lauren_pareti","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We need to create more reasons for people to visit Perkasie by expanding and diversifying our dining, shopping and recreational options. We also need to market our strengths and incubate new businesses. As a Councilwoman, I will support a range of strategies to accomplish this. With the pandemic, we have seen a trend towards professionals fleeing cities. Our lower cost of living and proximity to large urban markets is an asset to freelancers, consultants, and creative professionals who can base their businesses here and still compete for big-city clients and contracts.  For artisans and entrepreneurs, pop-ups, tiny business villages, and business-within-a-business models can create lower risk opportunities to operate from a more affordable space, make the leap from e-commerce to bricks and mortar, and use vacant store fronts.  Finally, by promoting and expanding our community events we can bring more people downtown and introduce entrepreneurs to all that Perkasie has to offer. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_lauren_pareti","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our infrastructure is aging, and leaders haven’t always been transparent about the size, scope and urgency of the challenge. We are a small town with our own electric utility and a problem with flooding. More frequent and intense heat waves and storms are coming our way, and cybersecurity and housing affordability are growing concerns. To be ready for the future and ensure that economic development doesn’t exacerbate problems for existing residents and businesses we need to: improve flood control and drainage; develop affordable housing and better transportation options; and ensure that our electric, water, sewer and broadband systems are resilient to cyber threats and climate change. Infrastructure investments will drive our ability to attract private investment and young families. Yet, small towns simply don’t have the financial capacity to fund infrastructure improvements. We’ll need to leverage state and federal resources, invest them wisely, and eliminate waste in our budget."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_lauren_pareti","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The hard-working officers of Perkasie’s Police Department want to connect anyone struggling with substance use to help. They don’t want to arrest people who are not a threat to public safety and don’t belong in jail. Doing so is a poor use of their time and a waste of tax-payer money. Our police want to focus on keeping our streets and our residents safe. Assisting people who use substances and need help is best done by drug and alcohol professionals. Our Police Department is already connecting people to that help through programs like Bucks County Police Assisting in Recovery. Despite equal usage rates, black people are nearly four times as likely to get arrested for marijuana than whites. Decriminalization is an important step towards righting race inequities. It’s a policy that has majority support among all age groups and political affiliations. For these reasons, I would support measures to decriminalize and loosen penalties for personal use of marijuana."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_lauren_pareti","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["When every person is free to live life openly, with equal rights ensured, we all benefit. Everyone deserves a fair chance to provide a safe and loving home for their family and access to services without fear of discrimination or harassment. Despite many advances, nearly two-thirds of LGBTQ+ Americans report personally experiencing discrimination. Recently, we have seen our School Board oppose diversity, equity and inclusion efforts, without transparency about their objectives. Working for 20+ years in human services, I have witnessed the devastating effects of bullying in the lives of LGBTQ+ young people who represent as much as 40% of youth experiencing homelessness. More than 40 Pennsylvania localities have ordinances prohibiting discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity in employment, housing, and public accommodations. As a Councilwoman, I would support these protections locally and work hard to make Perkasie a kind and welcoming place for all families. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_lauren_pareti","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID poses a vast public health and economic threat. Our most vulnerable neighbors face the greatest risks. I come from a working-class family that taught me to take care of each other even when it’s uncomfortable or inconvenient. I have spent my career in human services working to implement evidence-based strategies to improve well-being among at-risk populations.  The science is clear that masks work to prevent coronavirus spread and reduce the intensity of infection and sickness. The C.D.C recommends that even vaccinated people in our area wear a mask in public indoor settings. We know that mask mandates dramatically increase mask use. Examples of similar, effective safety requirements (e.g., seatbelt laws) are plentiful. We are all weary, and, though vaccines offer a way out, we have not convinced enough people to get vaccinated. For these reasons, I would support a local mask mandate tied to a data-driven approach to establish metrics for when masks will no longer be necessary. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_emily_heinz","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As someone who grew up in Newtown Borough and graduated from Council Rock (class of 2003), I genuinely want to give back to the community that I grew up in. I'm particularly excited to bring a fresh and different perspective to council, and would like to see the borough modernize while retaining its historic relevance and charm. I also have extensive project coordinator experience, which is sure to be an asset to this project-oriented position."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_emily_heinz","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Newtown Borough is facing unprecedented traffic congestion, and the current infrastructure is not conducive to vehicles, cyclists, and pedestrians safely sharing the roadway. We will need to get creative within the limited space we have by making crosswalks more visible, working with the police to curb speeding, and looking for ways to incentivize non-local traffic to use the bypass. ","","As new people continue to move into the borough, we need to proactively engage borough residents to get more involved in creating a purposeful community. To do so, we will need to modernize our digital communication efforts and increase the frequency at which they come. We should also look for ways to designate community spaces that serve each demographic of our community equally."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_emily_heinz","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Supporting the growth of our local borough businesses means making sure they're visible to a breadth of people outside of Newtown borough, township, and neighboring towns. In order to do this, the borough website needs to be modernized, and we need to start presenting ourselves via social media and adverting as a destination with great restaurants, unique shops, and welcoming people. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_emily_heinz","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The borough's major infrastructure needs are closely tied to what, I believe, is our biggest issue at this moment: traffic and pedestrian/cyclist safety. Some of that is already in the works (the current council has secured a grant to upgrade some traffic signals), but I would like to see more visible crosswalks, particularly on the busiest borough streets where speeding and running red lights is an issue. In the right places, I also think speed tables could be very beneficial. In terms of digital infrastructure, I'd like to see us modernize a bit and perhaps put an emergency text-alert program into use. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_emily_heinz","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["This issue is unlikely to be decided at the municipal level."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_emily_heinz","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, of course. How are we to build a better community if we don't openly welcome and support everyone in our community? I wish it weren't necessary to have protections against any discriminatory practice, but until that day comes, I wholeheartedly support them."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_emily_heinz","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I will follow the advice of medical and public health experts."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_derek_macmillan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been a very active in the community for the past 20 years, especially with Covered Bridge Park and the New Britain Civic Association, as a long-time board member and past Vice President.  I was also  one of the original members of the New Britain Borough Parks and Rec committee where I served as Chair for four years, and continue to serve as a committee member.  ","","One popular event I helped to bring to the Borough is the annual “Duck Derby and Picnic at the Park” at Covered Bridge Park -- raising thousands of dollars for community organizations over the past 11 years."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_derek_macmillan","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["With the Borough's slim resources, we need to focus on making every dollar count WITHOUT raising taxes.  This is possible with frugal capital management and making New Britain Borough a destination, rather than a pass-through community.  I have always believed that a strong community is built through volunteerism, and I will encourage the public to share in our journey towards 'Building a Better Borough'."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_derek_macmillan","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I would like to offer tax incentives for businesses to make their home in New Britain Borough.  I also believe the community should have a voice in public decisions that directly affect them, while also maintaining fiscal and financial security."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_derek_macmillan","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["One area of concern is our frequent power outages and the time it takes for power restoration."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_derek_macmillan","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As long as it complies with state laws, yes."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_derek_macmillan","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support protections for every resident.  "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_derek_macmillan","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would base my decision on the recommendations and guidelines of the CDC and the PA State Department of Health.  "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_courtney_loo","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have the time, energy, and passion to serve Morrisville. I've enjoyed leading clean-up efforts along the Morrisville River Walk (levee) and volunteering for community projects. I’m delighted to say that I have support from both Republicans and Democrats.  I am not a single-issue candidate. I will work hard on all the matters that affect our residents.  "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_courtney_loo","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["An Earned Income Tax (EIT) on top of already high property taxes. To make an informed decision, I will ascertain first and foremost the impact on our residents. I need to know how the monies will be used and will our property taxes be reduced. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_courtney_loo","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will emphasize the positives of Morrisville which there are many. I will advocate and encourage businesses to establish themselves in Morrisville and showcase the businesses that are already here. I will work closely with the Morrisville Economic Development Corporation, Morrisville Business Association and Lower Bucks Chamber of Commerce, and I will have a commonsense approach to any community growth. It must benefit our residents and have community support. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_courtney_loo","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Morrisville needs consistent code enforcement that addresses violations. Along with that, I will work closely with our Borough Manager to address road repairs and repaving as well as street markings to help make it a safer town. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_courtney_loo","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would not support any measure that made marijuana more accessible. My concern is the accessibility to children inhibiting their mental and physical growth. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_courtney_loo","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. I am a proponent of LGBTQ+ having equal protections as any other citizen."]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_courtney_loo","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_kimberly_a._bedillion","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a long-time resident of Perkasie Borough, I believe I have a responsibility to contribute to the ongoing well-being of this vibrant and historical community. I have served as Judge of Elections in Perkasie Ward 2, where I have helped ensured the integrity of several elections within the Borough. I would like to expand my community service efforts by serving on Borough Council. In that role I would use my analytical skills to take a fresh look at what is currently being done and dig deeper to locate more efficient and economic avenues. I would use my teamwork skills to develop partnerships with community members and local businesses to improve the quality of life for Perkasie residents. Finally, I would use my leadership experience to promote Perkasie's historical appeal and growing business district."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_kimberly_a._bedillion","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["As we emerge from the pandemic, Borough Council needs to enable local businesses to re-open to full capacity safely but quickly. Relaxing and/or rethinking local ordinances and zoning requirements is essential to providing local businesses with the tools they need to re-open fully. In addition, Borough Council must develop a short and long-term fiscal roadmap to ensure the ongoing financial health of Perkasie Borough. If the pandemic has taught us anything, it is that we need to ensure we have sufficient financial resources from which to draw during an extended emergency period. We need to make tough decision concerning what businesses and services in which the Borough should and should not be engaged. We need to aggressively pursue greater efficiency and quality by investigating alternative methods and eliminating duplicative or unnecessary work. Additionally, I would like to investigate unique opportunities to reduce costs, such as outside sponsorship or partnerships."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_kimberly_a._bedillion","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will listen to and actively work with small business owners to remove unnecessary regulations and red tape that make it difficult for small business owners to operate and grow. I will support local initiatives to create events that drive business to the Borough.  "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_kimberly_a._bedillion","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["It is important that we strike a balance between development and retaining the historical, small-town charm of Perkasie Borough. Residents enjoy having additional dining, shopping, and entertainment venues, but we must ensure that we add these new options in such a way that we do not lose the character of our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_kimberly_a._bedillion","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_kimberly_a._bedillion","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_council_kimberly_a._bedillion","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_tracey_a._bowen","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am able to apply my professional banking and finance experience to the Chalfont Borough Council position to assist with planning, budgeting, and financing.  With a keen focus on expense management and revenue generation, our Council has been able to navigate these turbulent economic times with cost containment while still providing key quality of life enhancements (playground equipment upgrades, park and trail improvements, the renovation of the old fire house into an ice cream store - just to name a few of our accomplishments). With 15+ years of volunteer service for Chalfont Borough, I would like to continue to advance our mission to keep Chalfont a wonderful place to live, conduct business, visit, raise a family, and retire.  Our sense of community pride is evident not just in our everyday interactions with our neighbors, but at specialty events like the Chalfont 5k, the Tri-Municipal 4th of July Parade, and Chalfont Day. I want to continue those traditions. "]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_tracey_a._bowen","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I don't think there is a single \"top issue\" - I think there are a few of them.  We must be able to attract and retain businesses in our downtown commercial corridor.  The Local Economic Revitalization Tax Assistance (LERTA) program  was developed and implemented to bring businesses to our area.  We're also pursuing shared parking solutions in our Borough Core to assist those businesses as they grow and prosper.  A second big issue is traffic.  As we and the municipalities around us (particularly those north of us) continue to grow and develop, we must continue to implement the latest \"smart signal\" technology to keep traffic flowing as efficiently as possible during peak times.  We also need to address public safety with our CB Regional Police Force.  The completion of the new police headquarters is scheduled for October 2021 and will assist our officers in the performance of their duties, which benefits our entire community."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_tracey_a._bowen","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As mentioned above, we've approved a LERTA to attract businesses to our area.  Our next job is getting the word out about its availability.  Pandemic restrictions have put an enormous strain on all businesses, but small businesses have been especially hard hit.  The tax abatement we offer would assist any business already in Chalfont or any new business relocating to our Borough.  Prior to the pandemic, we had an active Business Revitalization Committee, and I anticipate more activity from that Committee as we move past our current restrictions."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_tracey_a._bowen","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Storm water management is an issue for all of our local municipalities.  We've had great success securing grant money to assist us with storm water management, and we'd look to replicate that success in the coming years as well."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_tracey_a._bowen","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["We are a small borough of less than 2.0 square miles.  I don't believe we have the resources or staffing to create separate criminal penalties outside of state and federal codes.  Should this issue be brought to Borough Council, I would seek the input of our Attorney and Police Chief to provide guidance in this area.  "]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_tracey_a._bowen","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, I support LGBTQ+ protections at the local level.  In a borough our size, that means abiding by the state and federal criminal codes, as well as the protections offered by the Fair Housing Act and Equal Credit Opportunity Act.  As mentioned in the previous question, we are limited by our resources and staffing."]},{"candidateCode":"chalfont_borough_council_tracey_a._bowen","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would support following the guidance of those tasked with Public Health.  I have no health care experience or expertise, so I would rely on those who have that skill set to guide us.  "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_jesse_sloane","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["In 2017 I was elected to represent over 60,000 Bensalem residents as a member of the Bensalem Township Council.  I take this job very seriously, and have been a constant advocate for all residents these past 4 years, whether it be trekking through a flooded backyard or helping a troubled resident get assistance from our police department.  I also bring a skill set that no one else possesses, through my work as a mechanical and nuclear engineer in the construction industry.  I am the only Council member who can fully understand the technical pros and cons of potential development projects to ensure they are truly in the best interest of the township and our residents."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_jesse_sloane","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We must prioritize repairs and improvements to our existing infrastructure, especially our public storm water management facilities.  This area has been mercilessly hit by multiple severe storms, including tornados, in just a few months’ time.  We need to focus on how the township can provide relief to residents suffering from constant flooding problems so that no one has to worry when another rainstorm hits our community."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_jesse_sloane","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Bensalem had not done enough long term planning.  We should be looking 3, 5, and even 10 years into the future to set goals for where we want to be as a township.  Once those goals are set, we will need to develop a roadmap for how to get there.  This must address filling empty storefronts and promoting local businesses.  These are community partners that bring strong jobs and tax revenues to our community."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_jesse_sloane","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our storm water management infrastructure has been stressed beyond its capabilities due to the excessive storm events this year.  As a result, Bensalem Township was required by the Pennsylvania Emergency Management Agency to complete an assessment of these storm water management facilities.  As of the date of this survey, I have not yet received a copy of this completed assessment, despite multiple requests to the mayor’s administration.  This assessment allegedly includes recommendations to repair or replace impacted facilities.  The township needs to start implementing long term budgeting to address these repairs and ensure that we can timely provide real relief to our struggling residents that have been continuously impacted by these storms and the associated flooding. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_jesse_sloane","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Medical cannabis has is legal in Pennsylvania, and a dispensary already exists in Bensalem.  I fully support the use of medical marijuana, because I know that it provides real relief to people suffering from diseases ranging from cancer to pain management.  At this point, any further action regarding the potential decriminalization or legalization of marijuana would be up to the PA state legislature, who I believe is considering such possible actions."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_jesse_sloane","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely.  I have already proposed a nondiscrimination ordinance that adds protections to the LGBTQ+ community to my colleagues on Bensalem Council.  However, only one council member supported the idea; it was only the three Republican councilmen who did not.  One did not believe such protections were needed, one did not thing the resolution “had any teeth,” and the other refused to return my calls on the subject.  I would like to see Bensalem adopt that nondiscrimination ordinance, or at least be willing to discuss it in a public forum. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_jesse_sloane","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["A state-wide mask mandate has already been issued for Pennsylvania’s schools to prevent the types of serious outbreaks that are occurring across the nation.  The CDC is recommending people wear masks when indoors due to the surge of the Delta variant.  I believe in following the science.  We can all do our part to wear a mask and prevent further spread of COVID-19.  I hope that the residents of Bensalem value each other’s lives enough to do the right thing, so that a mandate from local government doesn’t even have to be considered."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_ed_tokmajian","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Four years ago, I was elected to serve on Bensalem Township Council by the voters of Bensalem. My extensive experience and education helped to provide the skillset needed to serve Bensalem residents.  I hold an MBA in business management. I have over 20 years of finance experience and worked for some of the largest corporations in the world, providing the knowledge and ability to manage Bensalem’s $60 million budget. I have been a Bensalem resident for 35+ years. I am a proud member of the Lions Club, serve on the Bucks County Planning Commission, and was previously elected as Bensalem Township Auditor. Along with Councilman Sloane, we have worked hard encouraging development that provides value through open space preservation, increased transparency and diversity across our government, prominently supported our police dept, increased the casino rebate, and addressed infrastructure, including traffic signaling, State Road flooding, and fought for resources and funding for our roads.   "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_ed_tokmajian","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Over-development continues to present challenges across Bensalem, resulting in increased traffic, decreased open space, and storm water crises. I will continue to support land development projects that provide value to the Bensalem community with low impact to residents. Over the last 4 years, I helped to acquire close to 25 acres of open space in Bensalem. I would like to create an advisory board to review open space availability within the township for potential preservation, as well as identify and address commercial open space across Bensalem. We also need to do a thorough review of our township building code to ensure we have the safeguards in place that addresses increased impervious space now and for future land development. In addition, being on the Bucks County Planning Commission, I also recommended reviewing Municipal Planning Code to ensure building code considers the increase in tornados and the need for improved building materials. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_ed_tokmajian","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Business growth is extremely important, particularly to increase our commercial tax base and provide job growth for residents. Over my last 4 years, I supported significant business growth including an Amazon grocery and distribution site, the continued growth of our Delaware waterfront, as well as many small new businesses.  However, Bensalem has too much open commercial space, with some strip malls reflecting a very dated look. We need to find ways to incentivize commercial landlords for updating and modernizing shopping centers, particularly along Street Road. I would create a program to advertise and promote the many benefits of doing business in Bensalem; Some of those benefits include hosting a world-class casino, being in close-proximity and having direct access to major roads such as I-95, Route 1, and the PA Turnpike. In addition, continuing to address our road infrastructure will also help to provide more benefit for doing business in Bensalem.      "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_ed_tokmajian","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Bensalem’s needs for major infrastructure lies primarily with storm water management. With the recent storms experienced here in Bensalem and across the county, we have seen continued erosion on our storm water management infrastructure. Bensalem also lies at the most southern point of most county watersheds, which only increases our water management issues. First and foremost, I would like to continue addressing our storm water management to ensure we allocate resources towards improving our storm water infrastructure. We need to prioritize areas where we are largely seeing issues, particularly on State Road and areas along the Poquessing Creek and Delaware River. I believe the township budget should allocate emergency funds to be able to better address resident needs when and where needed. As the largest township in the county, we also need to continue to ensure we are prepared with emergency management tools and equipment to provide assistance to residents at any time.       "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_ed_tokmajian","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I have previously supported medical marijuana with the application of a site that is now located right here in Bensalem. Many people have found that cannabis used for medicinal purposes helps to alleviate many ailments. The decriminalization of marijuana is still being considered at the state level. State legislatures should closely look at any impact to other areas around the country that have already approved legalizing marijuana or loosened penalties. Ultimately, this decision would not fall under a municipal level.    "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_ed_tokmajian","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, I would certainly support LGBTQ+ protections. Councilman Sloane and I had previously proposed a non-discrimination ordinance to be adopted by Bensalem. Unfortunately, the other three Council members rejected the idea for various reasons. I have continued to encourage ways to diversify our government across all levels. With Bensalem being a very diverse community, I would also support a resource that would help to increasingly promote diversity within our neighborhoods. I also continue to support programs such as our Unity Week that celebrates the diversity within Bensalem each year. I believe we need to increasingly support community programs that helps to build relationships and respect amongst many of our neighborhoods.    "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_ed_tokmajian","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Since the start of the Covid-19 pandemic, I have supported the measures that we had previously taken to ensure Bensalem residents remain safe and healthy. We followed state and CDC guidelines, closing our municipal building for a limited period of time, closing public parks, managing public meetings over zoom, and requiring masks at times in governmental buildings. I will continue to follow guidelines set forth by our health officials, primarily based on hospitalization rates. As a government official, I was elected to ensure Bensalem residents remain safe by supporting public safety from criminal activity, weather-related events, and even pandemics. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_borough_council_jenna_demirjian","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am passionate about giving back to the community that’s been my home for 14 years. My neighbors have become family to me and the relationships I have built allow me to understand their various viewpoints and needs. I aim to continue with council’s efforts to make Langhorne Manor a more sustainable and inclusive place to live.",""]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_borough_council_jenna_demirjian","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["My goal is to build on advancements the council has made in recent years toward increased openness and accountability with our community.  Establishing closer collaboration between our council, mayor, police force and residents, through dialogue and relationship-building, will result in increased support and success of our efforts. It is the job of borough council to reach out to the community to encourage and welcome their involvement and ideas."]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_borough_council_jenna_demirjian","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Given the size of Langhorne Manor, I feel my efforts will be best suited to supporting residents who own their own businesses when opportunities present to bid for work within the community. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_borough_council_jenna_demirjian","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The primary infrastructure need currently facing Langhorne Manor is stormwater management. It is a vital concern that directly affects our residents.  As a member of council I would strongly advocate and approve initiatives that come from the Stormwater Commission to ensure our residents aren’t adversely affected by stormwater. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_borough_council_jenna_demirjian","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Not applicable because we are in a small municipality that does not make those decisions. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_borough_council_jenna_demirjian","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support the LGBTQ+ community and would work to ensure such protections on the local level. I strive to create an inclusive and diverse Langhorne Manor, where all residents are treated equitably and are afforded the same rights and liberties. I plan to review LGBTQ protections passed by neighboring municipalities before determining which we might implement in ours. I see a need for more outreach, education and communication on this topic with residents, decision-makers and our police chief and officers. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_borough_council_jenna_demirjian","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support safety measures including wearing masks and social distancing, but mandates would have little impact in our mostly residential borough. The only two institutions here are Langhorne Gardens and Cairn University. Both follow their own safety protocols, which I support. Last year, the council began holding its meetings virtually to prevent spread of the coronavirus. This enabled borough business to be conducted efficiently, with the added benefit that more residents began “attending” and participating in the meetings."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_earl_markey","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I stand on conviction and values, not partisan blatherskite. For example, I stood up for the Constitution in the United States Supreme Court during the pandemic and stood against extremists infiltrating the local Republican party in recent months. On Council, I will be a check on one-party domination and hold my colleagues accountable. I am also not afraid to upset the special interests by blocking sweetheart deals and no bid contracts.  If you want a Councilman who is more concerned about standing on principal than where he stands in a photo op, I may be worthy of your vote. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_earl_markey","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Yardley’s spending and debt has increased in the last few years. Council needs to be more fiscally responsible. If elected, my first motion will be to repeal the Occupation Assessment as well as Per Capita Taxes and offset these taxes with spending cuts. The maximum combined Occupation Assessment and Per Capita Taxes levied upon any resident is $35. The revenue generated by these taxes is simply not worth the burden on both taxpayers and the borough."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_earl_markey","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Much of the focus on business growth has been to make Yardley an evening or weekend destination. Unfortunately, numerous issues have arisen for residents because of this ambition. What more, the pandemic demonstrated just how vulnerable the hospitality industry can be. Like any good investor, Yardley needs a diversified business portfolio. Innovators such as Zico, Red Nucleus, GR8 People, and ICON have grown in Yardley without changing the character of the community. For this reason, I propose focusing business development initiatives on Yardley’s innovation sector. Growth in this section encourages people to live, work, and be a part of the community; not just visit for dinner."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_earl_markey","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The sewer system is of particular concern. If approved, the sale of the Lower Makefield Township portion of system to Aqua would put Yardley in a predicament. All involved municipalities must work together, and I will take a hardline against actions by other municipalities or sewer operators that disadvantage Yardley residents and rate payers."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_earl_markey","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Changes to controlled substance laws should be left to the state and federal governments. That said, I view decriminalization by municipalities as a ploy to collect more revenue with civil penalties in lieu of fines by removing the civil rights protections afforded criminal defendants."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_earl_markey","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["At the outset, I regard acts of discrimination as vile transgressions of the moral norms. In 2018, Council enacted an Anti-Discrimination Ordinance. While very well-intentioned, any violation of the ordinance could subject Yardley taxpayers to significant investigative, administrative, and litigation costs. Fortunately, enforcement actions by the borough have not been necessary. I favor updating the ordinance, so to eliminate the potential for investigative, litigation, and administrative costs to Yardley taxpayers. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_earl_markey","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I oppose adopting local COVID restrictions as such measures would be costly to Yardley taxpayers if challenged in court. Further, an ordinance requiring proof of vaccination or a negative COVID test to access public accommodations (so-called vaccine passports), as has been enacted in New Orleans, would certainly garner a legal challenge if adopted by Council."]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_anthony_marfia","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I will work to preserve the residential and business character of the Boro.","Promote transparency.","Work with state and county officials to improve traffic and safety concerns of the Boro "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_anthony_marfia","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_anthony_marfia","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_anthony_marfia","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_anthony_marfia","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_anthony_marfia","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_anthony_marfia","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_mark_moffa","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am on the ballot twice. Here, for re-election to my Borough Council seat. And also for Mayor. ","","For council, I am running with fellow incumbents Beverly Wolfe, Laura Germain and John Stratz, because I believe council is doing great work for Penndel's residents. I'm proud to be part of this team, and encourage voters to vote for all four of us so that we can continue to be as productive as possible. ","","I ran for mayor, challenging the incumbent mayor from my own party in the primary election, because I felt a change was needed in that position. I'm honored that the voters emphatically nominated me.","","So now you will find me twice. I ask that you please vote for me for BOTH (yes, you can do this, just like we did for Tina Davis two years ago when she ran for state house and senate on the same ballot). If I win mayor, I will accept that position, and we will appoint someone to temporarily fill my council seat until a special election is held for it.",""]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_mark_moffa","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The revitalization of our business corridors is the top issue facing Penndel. As an elected official, I will provide the strategic, practical and representative leadership needed to aid revitalization efforts. ","","For example, we've just had a significant sale of 24 and 50 Hulmeville Avenue, the old Perma-Bilt Furniture Mart by the bridge that is being reconstructed. I invited the new co-owner to a meeting of the borough's Revitalization Task Force, so that he, our task force, our new manager, and the county planning commission could meet for the first time and begin to form a working relationship that will be key to the success of the development. (But instead of embracing the possibilities and working together, our political opponents decided to rudely confront the developer with false conspiracy theories. This is why we don't have nice things.)","","A vote for me is a vote for progress, and against the negativity that has prevailed for too long. I will fight for positive change. "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_mark_moffa","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Our floundering Business Route 1 corridor is an example of the failure of \"the way things have always been done.” Through strategic connections and partnerships, and collaboration between our Borough Manager, elected officials, and business community, we will help bring new life to Penndel.","","Already, we have accomplished a lot. Just last year, amidst a paralyzing pandemic, I spearheaded efforts at Borough Council to pass three major pieces of legislation: ","1. Massive zoning relief and incentives to encourage revitalization. ","2. An earned income tax to recoup our dollars that were going to other towns.","3. The hiring of a manager to run the borough more effectively and help lead revitalization efforts.","","​So we're already moving forward. We're already working smarter. And now, the borough is in the process of reaching out to each of our existing businesses with information on how to expand and improve, and an offer to help them do so. We've even just reduced certain permit fees."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_mark_moffa","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The Borough Council spends a lot of time, money and effort focusing on our infrastructure needs. This council has received grant funding to help with significant and badly needed improvements to our sewer system, has accomplished a lot recently, and has a plan for future upgrades. ","","Council is also always planning for future road pavings, and currently is trying to revise the borough's procedures for how curbs and sidewalks are dealt with when roads are repaved.","","For Business Route 1, council has been working with PennDot on plans for major improvements at two of our intersections that will improve safety along that corridor. ","","I would continue to support these ongoing initiatives in any way possible. "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_mark_moffa","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. Decriminalizing drug possession, and instead investing in treatment and harm-reduction services has many benefits for public safety and health, including fewer arrests and incarcerations; increased uptake into treatment and recovery services; the ability to redirect law enforcement resources to prevent serious and violent crimes; and lower criminal justice costs."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_mark_moffa","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. I support full protections against discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity. This includes prohibiting discrimination in private employment, housing, and public accommodations. I would support seeing Penndel join the list of Pennsylvania municipalities on this page: https://www.lgbtmap.org/equality_maps/profile_state/PA"]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_mark_moffa","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, because I believe in science and saving lives. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_julia_w._woldorf","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am seeking re-election to Newtown Borough Council to continue my efforts to improve the efficiency of Borough government and the quality of life for the residents.  Having served two terms on Council including 2 years as council president and 4 years as vice president, I bring important experience, skills, and knowledge to this position.  I am particularly knowledgeable in zoning, subdivision and land development, storm water management requirements, writing ordinances, and applying for grant funding. To date, I have obtained over $500,000 in grants and donations for Borough projects.  I recently managed the update of all the Borough’s ordinances and publication of the entire code on the Borough website.  I oversaw the planning, funding, design and construction of the restoration of the Newtown Common which received the 2019 Governor’s Award for Environmental Excellence; and I am currently overseeing the planning, funding, and design of the new Patriots Park on Court Street. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_julia_w._woldorf","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing Newtown is how to retain its highly-valued walkable small historic town atmosphere, while maintaining good fiscal health.  As the Borough updates its Comprehensive Plan, Open Space Plan, ordinances, and plans for infrastructure improvements, I intend to be focused on goals that support a thriving business district, maintain the integrity of historic resources, encourage the availability of a variety of housing stock, provide services for residents of all ages, preserve parks and open space, and ensure public safety. "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_julia_w._woldorf","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Newtown Borough's business district is small, but it has great potential.  In the old days, the Borough was surrounded by farms and it was the commercial core providing all the necessary retail and business services for the area.  Now Newtown businesses have to compete with multiple nearby shopping centers and online retail.   For the business district to thrive, there should be a variety of businesses and an inviting streetscape, so that shopping in Newtown is a pleasant experience in and of itself.  I recommend that the Borough establish a new Main Streets Program.  This program could support the business community by overseeing improvement of the streetscape, attracting a variety of businesses, helping with advertising and creating a media presence to attract customers, advising, and helping to secure grants and other funding."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_julia_w._woldorf","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Newtown Borough needs more sidewalks and improved street lighting.  There are streets, some of which support significant through-traffic, that have a sidewalk only on one side, or have no sidewalk at all.  This is hazardous for pedestrians, particularly children.  There are many stretches of streets and sidewalks that have no lighting, making it hazardous to walk at night.  The Borough should complete its sidewalk plan.  I would seek grants to help pay for installation of public sidewalks where none exist, a cost currently borne by the property owner.  I would also apply for grants to support a Borough-wide lighting survey and installation of additional lighting as recommended by that report."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_julia_w._woldorf","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a member of Borough Council in 2018, I supported adoption of an ordinance regulating the location in the Borough of the manufacture and sale of medical marijuana, which had been recently legalized in Pennsylvania.  However, as a member of Borough Council, I would have no control over the decriminalization of recreational marijuana."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_julia_w._woldorf","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["As Council president in 2011, I led the successful effort to adopt Newtown Borough's antidiscrimination ordinance which bans discrimination in housing, employment, and education based on sexual orientation or gender identification, in addition to the other protected classes already identified by state and federal law.  It also established the Human Relations Commission to hear and facilitate resolution of complaints of discrimination of all types.  As the Borough Council liaison to the HRC, I am currently assisting the commission with its activities.   If re-elected, I will continue to support enforcement of this ordinance and anti-discrimination efforts by the HRC."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_council_julia_w._woldorf","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a healthcare professional, I am an ardent supporter of preventative public health measures.  The spread of COVID can be reduced by social distancing, wearing masks, and increasing the percentage of vaccinated people.  All of these measures have demonstrated effectiveness.  We are fortunate that we have the technological resources to meet and conduct business remotely.  Holding Council meetings remotely or live-streaming has actually increased public attendance at meetings, prompting me to support continuation of hybrid meetings after the pandemic.  Social distancing, in particular, can impact some businesses, such as restaurants, more than others.   As a member of Council, I have supported relaxing zoning restrictions to permit outdoor dining during the pandemic and am sympathetic and willing to work with other businesses to minimize the impact of shutdowns and other restrictions as they are ordered by the state or county.  The pandemic will only end when we stop the virus's spread."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_chris_campellone","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My primary goal is to do right by the citizens of Yardley Borough. To look out for their financial and emotional well being and to champion initiatives that help the residents first. I’m open to ideas and readily available and accessible to everyone. I have experience leading huge projects and working with all sorts of people and I’m ready to put that experience to work for Yardley Borough. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_chris_campellone","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Flooding is clearly the number one issue. We just saw it with the results of Hurricane Ida. As a homeowner in the flood zone I will work to ensure residents are safe, their homes are protected and that we do everything we can to apply for grants to allow homeowners to raise their homes. In addition I’d like to see more flexibility in the flood zone building ordinances to allow homeowners to improve their homes. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_chris_campellone","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["By working with local business owners to help promote their businesses at community sponsored events. I will be a tireless advocate for Yardley Borough businesses. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_chris_campellone","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We need more crosswalks. Specifically at Yardley Commons and the train station. I’d also like to apply for grants that will allow us to put electric car charging stations in the Borough. This is in addition to finishing what we started with the North Main sidewalk project and Mary Yardley Bridge improvement. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_chris_campellone","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am open to a discussion on this issue, but would need to better understand the ramifications to local businesses and residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_chris_campellone","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely and unequivocally. As the chair of the Human Relations Commission I want to be clear that Yardley accepts everyone without exception. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_chris_campellone","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I will listen to health experts and state leaders and follow the guidance. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_caroline_thompson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have a proven track record on council of active participation, I am an elected official who shows up and does work. I have a proven track record on council of effective governance, overhauling the borough's budget to increase transparency and redirecting funds to establish and grow savings accounts. I have a proven track record of creative solutions, helping the borough to secure millions in grant funding for projects that would otherwise be financially out-of-reach for our small town. I have a proven track-record of advocacy, focusing on floodplain resident's quality of life through CRS discount improvement, reforming the floodplain ordinance and an educational webinar series on life in the flood plain which has been viewed on YouTube by hundreds of residents. What makes me the best candidate for this office? My prove track record. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_caroline_thompson","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Planning and strategy. My time on council, and the previous few decades for the town, have been speckled by environmental disasters (floods), leadership changes (police, management, high turnover on council), and council to council / council to resident wheel spinning due to disagreement and project management failures. Planning and strategy must be the top priority in the next term of council so that disasters and turnover do not derail progress. What is the critical path and how do we stay on it? "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_caroline_thompson","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I don't envision our business district growing (i.e. number of businesses) significantly in the future due to spatial constraints and parking considerations. However, current businesses can be supported by local government during and post-pandemic by offering loosened restrictions on outdoor dining [we have done this], delayed payment of business taxes [we have done this], increased opportunities for foot traffic through town [we have done this], and one-on-one listening sessions with borough business owners to respond to concerns and collect ideas for growth [we have done this, too]."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_caroline_thompson","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Yardley Borough is an aging historic river town. Our existing infrastructure needs more than just patch-work repairs and the growth of our town has led to increased need for sidewalks, pedestrian safety measures, and parking strategy. Revamping the budget in 2018 has redirected borough assets into our savings accounts which has allowed us to save for and plan for future infrastructure projects. It has also allowed us to apply for grant opportunities that require a monetary match. Current major projects include the Mary Yardley Footbridge and North Main Sidewalk. Future projects include rehabilitating historic and deteriorating borough hall. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_caroline_thompson","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["27 states and the District of Columbia have decriminalized possession of small amounts of marijuana. 10 cities/municipalities in PA have done the same. I support decriminalizing possession of small amounts of marijuana as no major reported issues have occurred in the jurisdictions listed above which have already implemented. Further, these policies will help channel tax monies allocated to jails to more serious crimes and, hopefully, a more comprehensive approach to caring for inmates with mental illness. "]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_caroline_thompson","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I fully support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level. Did you know Yardley Borough is one of only 12 municipalities in PA that has an ordinance prohibiting conversion therapy for minors? Did you know Yardley Borough is one of only 67 municipalities that has an ordinance prohibiting discrimination based on sexual orientation in private employment, housing, and public accommodations (full protections)? Yardley Borough, under the leadership of the current council administration, has moved the needle towards equal protections under the law for LGBTQ+ residents. However, the county and state need to do more. Specifically by refining broad RFRAs, negative LGBTQ+ Youth Laws and Policies, and Criminal Justice Laws (HIV-related)."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_caroline_thompson","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Wearing a mask is easy. Getting vaccinated is easy. My child is unable to be vaccinated at this time due to his age and others are unable to be vaccinated due to valid medical concerns or religious exemptions. I'm happy to mask-up if it means other people can fully participate in education, in the workplace, and in social gatherings. Two in three parents nation-wide agree on this. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_nancy_m._culleton","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I’ve lived in Bucks County since 1977 and the Borough since 2016. I care about the future of Langhorne, and I believe in strengthening the foundations of democracy at the local level. If elected, I’ll work to give constituents more access to Borough information and more opportunities for dialogue with local officials. I’ll connect with people to learn what’s on their minds. I’ll keep fairness, fiscal prudence, and a concern for the environment at the forefront when making decisions.","","I like to ask questions. I know how to listen carefully to a range of voices, weigh all sides of an issue, communicate clearly, and work with a budget. I’ve seasoned these abilities during my career as a high school English teacher and counselor, my service as treasurer of several local groups, and my work on Quaker-affiliated nonprofit boards. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_nancy_m._culleton","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Climate change is the number one issue facing our borough and planet.  We must put significant resources into making our infrastructure more climate resilient (see below).  Ideally, we’ll be able to use our share of money from the infrastructure bill now in Congress to help accomplish this. For years, the Borough itself has primarily used energy from renewable sources. The next step is to think creatively about incentives for residents and businesses to reduce their use of fossil fuels as well. ","","Community engagement is also a key issue. I’ve been so inspired by a generation of volunteers who have helped make the borough a great place to live. I want to reach out to many more people in our diverse community, especially younger residents, to help raise up their ideas and bring their skills, wisdom, and leadership to Council and its committees."]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_nancy_m._culleton","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I support keeping Langhorne a town of small businesses. We can help them thrive by keeping taxes as low as possible and by cooperating with the Business Association on initiatives that benefit both businesses and residents. This is especially important as we recover from the economic impact of the COVID-19 crisis. Looking ahead, we should consider ways of enhancing our town center to draw in more customers – for instance, by encouraging more retail stores among our primarily service-oriented businesses, creating more intentional, linked parking areas and walkways, and further highlighting the borough’s historic character. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_nancy_m._culleton","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["As this summer’s violent storms have shown, climate change already affects our community. We must assess what improvements are necessary to prepare our roads, electrical grid, water and sewage systems, and communication networks for increased stress; monitor our new storm water management plan; and ensure that our first responders are well equipped to deal with more frequent extreme weather events. "," ","I’ll support incentives to reduce traffic congestion, promote safety, and reduce carbon emissions. These could include walkways connecting our business areas, bike paths connecting to nearby recreational areas, and charging stations for electric vehicles. Ongoing communication with PennDOT is needed, as its planned changes to the intersection of Routes 1 and 413 will affect Borough traffic. I’ll always be in favor of more robust regional public transportation options. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_nancy_m._culleton","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Like most Pennsylvania voters, I support the decriminalization of marijuana. Ideally, this issue should be decided at the state level.  Before agreeing to support any proposed municipal measure, I would need to understand its rationale, its potential consequences, its level of support in our community, and any limits to our authority to enforce it."]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_nancy_m._culleton","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely. Discrimination against LGBTQ+ people has no place in Langhorne Borough or anywhere else. Currently, their civil rights are not fully protected under federal or Pennsylvania law. More than 50 municipalities in our state have passed ordinances prohibiting harassment of LGBTQ+ people and banning discrimination against them in areas of employment, housing, education, and public accommodation. I would be proud for Langhorne Borough to pass such an ordinance as well. ","","I'll continue to support educational programs that build respect for people of all gender identities, sexual orientations, races, ethnicities, abilities, religions, and nationalities.",""]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_borough_council_nancy_m._culleton","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["With the statewide school mask mandate now in place, our best defense against a rise in COVID cases and further mandates is voluntary compliance with the CDC’s recommended mitigation measures, including vaccinations. If asked to decide on further local restrictions, I would consider data from state and county public health authorities, the current level of compliance with their recommendations, and constituent input."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_beverly_wolfe","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["For the past 8 years, I have served the Borough of Penndel's residents and business owners keeping my focus on their needs, the most critical need being filling empty commercial areas.  Penndel Borough has made the necessary internal changes to set the stage for the redevelopment and revitalization of our business areas.  We  have made great strides in this area but there is still much to do.  When I spearheaded this initiative back in 2016 by partnering with the county, I knew it would take years to see results and we are finally on the verge of seeing those results.  During my tenure on council, we have changed the way Penndel Borough conducts the business of the people, with an unprecedented level of transparency and accountability.  I feel I still have a lot to offer the town I grew up in."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_beverly_wolfe","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I think what I talked about in the first question is the top issue here.  Empty, abandoned commercial properties don't bring in the revenue to assist our residents with the cost of running a town.  Our residents want and deserve the kinds of services that we have been providing and we have been maintaining those even with our limited tax base.  We implemented an EIT last year to fund the hiring of a Borough Manager who has brought a new level of expertise to the table and will allow us to fund marketing strategies to appeal to developers and let them know Penndel is open for business.  We also decreased our millage last year to try to assist our most vulnerable citizens with a tax break, something I would love to see us try to continue to do.  "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_beverly_wolfe","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Once again, if you refer to my answers to the last questions, I think they answer this one as well.  We have an entire committee, the Revitalization Task Force, dedicated to this issue.  Last year, we passed one of the largest pieces of legislation that Penndel Borough has ever passed, our new Transit Oriented District (TOD) and Zoning changes to go along with this new TOD.  This action was recommended by the Bucks County Planning Commission as a necessary change to attract development.  We are also preparing a marketing strategy to promote our town.  We have it all here in Penndel,  a diamond in the rough you might say.  We have the Langhorne Train Station, Septa stops, we are just a couple of miles from I-295, US 1, the PA Turnpike, and now with our new TOD and the changes that came with it, we have opportunities for new and exciting businesses, mixed use, and more to fill up the empty properties.  I totally believe in this vision, as does the current council."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_beverly_wolfe","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We have already addressed some very long standing issues that we decided should no longer be ignored.  We have obtained substantial amounts of grant funding to do projects in the borough, such as a major update to the sewer system, new LED lighting and electric connections at the Memorial Park, among many other things.  We installed new LED street lighting, made other improvements to our stormwater management system.  We have other projects in the works to continue updating and upgrading our infrastructure.  "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_beverly_wolfe","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is a subject that I do need to devote a bit more time and research before I decide my position on the matter.  "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_beverly_wolfe","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Unfortunately, I don't think LGBTQ+ protections on the local level will hold that much weight unless they are adopted at higher levels of government first.  That being said, I believe in human rights, I believe in American ideals.  Every single American citizen deserves to have equal rights, period.  Putting labels on people always leads down the wrong road and denying certain groups of Americans the same rights as others just because they are perceived as \"different\" in some way is just plain silly.  We become more divided every day as more groups are formed or identified. "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_beverly_wolfe","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I already do.  The variants that are already known plus the inevitability of new variants coupled with those who choose to not be vaccinated, makes indoor masking an absolute must right now.  I would go so far as to say even large outdoor events where people are crammed together is problematic also.  "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_laura_germain","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I wouldn’t say I am the best, but I would say that I have made many positive changes during my tenure. I have really focused on community events and spirit by running many successful events, most recently the reopening party."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_laura_germain","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["COVID affects almost everything, so I will continue to be diligent I getting out information to our residents."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_laura_germain","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Hopefully our EIT and TOD will help! Also, the community events make Penndel a more attractive place to live."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_laura_germain","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_laura_germain","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. It is time to reserve serious penalty for serious crimes."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_laura_germain","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely. They need to be included in all anti-discrimination bills and we need to offer support with mental health."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_laura_germain","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. It’s a small inconvenience for a very serious health issue. We don’t know much about long COVID or how it affects survivors."]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_kathryn_price_engelhard","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I come to the Borough with fresh new eyes and new ideas.  I have lead some of the largest non profits in the country, and worked and learned from CEO’s of some of the top businesses in our nation. I will use these experiences to tackle the big issues facing Morrisville Borough.  ","We have an amazing community here, one that needs to be preserve but also grow.  Striving to keeping our property taxes form rising not only helps local residents but helps the Borough grow with houses being sold and new families moving in.  ","Supporting both home based and local businesses to grow should be a high priority.  ","Empty store fronts and buildings need to be filled with a variety of inventory."]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_kathryn_price_engelhard","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our budget is tight and we face difficult decisions on how to bring new revenue into the Borough.  It will be up to the elected officials to provide ways for the Borough to grow revenue.  Recognizing that we have many families who are struggling to make ends meet and people on fixed incomes.  "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_kathryn_price_engelhard","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We need to invest in our infrastructure, some of our walk ways and side walks are deteriorating and are difficult for  handicap people to get around with ease.  ","Many communities I have lived in have downtown festivals, annual celebrations that bring in new revenue for our local businesses.  We have excellent restaurants in our Borough, we need to do more to get people inside.  ","I have lived in small towns all over the country, I have seen their successes and yes some of their failures. I want the opportunity to share these experiences with my Borough"]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_kathryn_price_engelhard","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Many people ask me about “the roads” unfortunately the biggest issue we have are with the State Highways.  I know,  I live off one of them.  We also have a bridge that has caution tape around it for years now.  Which is also on a State road.    Locally we have streets that have pot holes that damage our cars, and sidewalks that are crumbling.  I will work with other council members to help prioritize our infrastructure needs. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_kathryn_price_engelhard","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe it is time to legalize marijuana for personal use and decriminalize it for those using it for their own personal pleasure or for medical reasons.  "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_kathryn_price_engelhard","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I would support protection for the LGBTQ community.  No one should ever live in fear because of who they love, or don’t love, because it is none of our business.  I want this Borough to be one of acceptance.  We do that through our own example and we should expect our elected and other town leaders to be the example of such behavior.  "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_kathryn_price_engelhard","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes I would support mandates if Covid cases continue to rise.  If we want our economy to grow in this Borough then we need to keep our businesses open.  We need to protect ourselves and others by keeping us healthy. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_james_schwartz","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I'M A LONG TIME RESIDENT. WELL KNOWN AND RESPECTED IN THE COMMUNITY."]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_james_schwartz","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["IT'S ALWAYS REVENUE AND KEEPING TAXES LOW. I WILL WORK WITH THE BORO MANAGER IN SUPPORTING BUDGET SAVINGS AND INCREASING REVENUE IDEAS.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_james_schwartz","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["BY MAKING MORRISVILLE AN ATTRACTIVE PLACE FOR BUSINESSES TO WANT TO LOCATE HERE."]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_james_schwartz","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["STORMWATER DRAINAGE AND STREET PAVING AND REPAIRS. REGULAR MAINTENANCE AND PRIORITIZING STREET REPAIRS. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_james_schwartz","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["THIS IS A STATE ISSUE. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_james_schwartz","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["EVERYONE HAS THE RIGHT TO LIFE, LIBERTY AND THE PURSUIT OF HAPPINESS UNDER THE CONSTITUTION. HOWEVER, NO ONE NEEDS MORE PROTECTION. NO ONE SHOULD BE DISCRIMINATED AGAINST, PERIOD!"]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_council_james_schwartz","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I SUPPORT ANYONE'S RIGHT TO WEAR A MASK OR NOT WEAR A MASK. I'M NOT BIG ON GOV'T MANDATES. I AM A COVID SURVIVOR. I KNOW HOW BAD THIS IS. PEOPLE NEED TO TAKE THIS SERIOUS AND MAKE THE IMPORTANT DECISION FOR THEMSELVES AND THERE FAMILY."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_david_bria","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My record on Yardley Council speaks for itself. In the last four years, I've secured grant funding to break ground on the next phase of the North Main Sidewalk project, successfully earned floodplain residents a 10% discount on their federal flood insurance premiums, and expanded Yardley's police force to match the needs of our growing downtown business district. Given four more years, I will upgrade Borough Hall's technology infrastructure to broadcast all public meetings in a format accessible to every resident, complete the full North Main sidewalk project, and solve the parking problem in Yardley's business district through private-public partnerships. I have the experience to lead Yardley Borough as it continues to emerge as one of Bucks County's best communities to live, work and visit."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_david_bria","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Floodplain management continues to be a challenge to river communities like Yardley Borough. During my first term, I helped pass an overhaul to the floodplain ordinance which gave homeowners more freedom to conduct renovations while remaining within FEMA guidelines. These updates earned homeowners a 10% discount on federal flood insurance premiums. I am a strong advocate for residents seeking to participate in federal home elevation grants, and will continue the Borough's role in administering these programs throughout my next term."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_david_bria","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Small business is the driving force behind Yardley’s local economy. As an elected official, I can’t take credit for the innovation and grit my community’s business owners demonstrate every day. Instead, I promise to keep an open channel for business owners to communicate their needs. I’ll approach each situation with a get-to-yes attitude that provides opportunity for continued growth. Local government should be a partner to local business—not a bureaucratic barrier. At the same time, it’s the government’s job to ensure an equal playing field for every small business owner who wants to open up shop on Main Street."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_david_bria","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Parking availability has emerged as a major concern for both residents and visitors as Yardley's business district continues to grow. I will launch a partnership between local businesses and the Borough to make use of empty office lots on weeknights and weekends. Tech-based solutions such as ParkMobile allow visitors to pay for hourly parking via smartphone. This creates a revenue opportunity for businesses whose parking lots are empty after hours and solves concerns regarding liability as parked cars are registered by license plate. The Borough's role enforcing and facilitating this program would be substantially more affordable than the capital investment to purchase and construct a new municipal parking lot."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_david_bria","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Black Americans are nearly four times as likely to be arrested on marijuana-related charges than white Americans. Decriminalization is a racial justice issue we must prioritize. I support not only decriminalization, but the full legalization of cannabis for recreational use."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_david_bria","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In 2018, I introduced and passed an ordinance that prohibits discrimination in housing, employment and public accommodation on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity. Both the US Congress and the state legislature have failed to enact civil rights legislation that fully protects the LGBTQ community. It is the duty of local officials to enact these protections until action is taken at higher levels of government."]},{"candidateCode":"yardley_borough_council_4_years_david_bria","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support the public health guidance issued by the CDC and state health department. Additionally, I support private businesses and employers who require proof of vaccination for their patrons and employees. We can end this pandemic through vaccination. The misinformation and conspiracy theories surrounding the COVID vaccine can no longer go unanswered. Vaccines work—period. Everyone should get one unless they have a valid medical reason not to do so."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_robyne_j._kelemen","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["It has been my pleasure to represent the residents of New Britain Borough on borough council for the past 8 years.  I bring my experience in addressing the needs of our community and ask for your vote to continue to do so.  I was the founding chairperson of our borough's Public Safety Committee, and represent the borough on the Central Bucks Regional Police Commission, working to assure the ongoing high quality-of-life in our community.  My professional background is in engineering and business, which gives me capability to work with colleagues and residents to address important financial and technical issues in the borough. My approach is open-minded:  I am available to the community to discuss matters of concern, encouraging discussion and collaboration to find the best solutions for our community."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_robyne_j._kelemen","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The borough needs to continue to maintain a strong tax base in order to keep our current level of services to the community.  We need to support appropriate business and residential investment in the borough by promoting our community as a great place to life and do business, and a destination, not a pass-through to other communities in our area.  I will make sure that steps continue to be taken to assure appropriate development in our University Village area and elsewhere, to continue to enhance our community character, availability of services, and quality-of-life."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_robyne_j._kelemen","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I want to maintain the reputation of New Britain Borough as a welcoming municipality for businesses to work with as they consider their growth and development needs.  The borough is encouraging to new businesses yet protective of aspects that could raise residential concerns. New Britain Borough has been quite successful the past few years in acheiving new business growth, and appropriate growth will continue to be supported."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_robyne_j._kelemen","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["New Britain Borough is in the process of making municipal water service available to more of Butler Avenue, which will remove one impediment to appropriate business development.  The borough will continue to work hand-in-hand with the state and county to maintain roads and bridges in top shape.  More trails are in development, and these continue to offer great opportunities for connection in our community for both commuting and recreation."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_robyne_j._kelemen","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As more and more states are moving towards controlled legalization of marijuana, changes are likely to occur in Pennsylvania as well over time.  I want to assure that the youth of our community are protected and continue to be protected from the detrimental effects of drug availability and use.  We have taken the approach to maintain current penalties at this time."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_robyne_j._kelemen","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Our municipality does support LGBTQ+ protections through equal rights ordinances put in place in the past few years. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_council_robyne_j._kelemen","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["We should follow state and federal recommendations and mandates to assure appropriate protection of health and safety.  The best expertise for this is beyond the local level."]},{"candidateCode":"bristol_borough_council_betty_rodriguez","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been on council 17 years and a Bristol resident all my life and I know the needs of  my constituents ."]},{"candidateCode":"bristol_borough_council_betty_rodriguez","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Parking is an issue and landlords that refuse to keep their properties taken care of for their residents is another.  We are working on ways to take empty spaces and make them parking areas, and we still have an inspections department that deals with the problems of rentals."]},{"candidateCode":"bristol_borough_council_betty_rodriguez","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Always working with the business district which is in my ward to keep it thriving!"]},{"candidateCode":"bristol_borough_council_betty_rodriguez","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Working with others to secure grants to upgrade our Mill street parking lot which has issues due to flooding! Has always been an issue but more so due to climate change."]},{"candidateCode":"bristol_borough_council_betty_rodriguez","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes I feel that you can keep it legal and it would benefit people better."]},{"candidateCode":"bristol_borough_council_betty_rodriguez","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, I feel our town is already very diverse and all rights should be equal regardless of anyone’s beliefs, "]},{"candidateCode":"bristol_borough_council_betty_rodriguez","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, to protect our citizens !!!"]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_louis_joseph_adams","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I've lived in Penndel for several years now. Since living here there has been no republican or libertarian representation on council. I think it's time I gave back to my community by being that representation. I want to make sure that individual liberty and maintaining a peaceful and stable community are the goals my elected leaders focus on. I know that by standing up and answering the call to serve in this way I can be that influence. We have a diverse community of both democrats and republicans, I'd like to be the voice on council for the group not currently represented."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_louis_joseph_adams","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Hate and dogma seem to be the new cultural norm. Us vs. them feels like the tear that's ripping this country apart. Even here in Penndel lines are drawn and issues are viewed through the lens of the parties we belong to.","","Wouldn't it be nice to not have to operate that way? Wouldn't it be nice to be able to reach across the aisle and make decisions that bring our community closer together? We can't combat hate with hateful words, more division, and more separation. We need to find ways live at peace with our neighbors, and I think it's time Penndel focuses on ways to serve our community, not our parties.","","Local government should be focusing on maintaining a community that's attractive to residents because it's safe, welcoming, and friendly. Too much has distracted us from that goal, I hope to help be the influence that helps council rise above and lead the way."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_louis_joseph_adams","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I am a Republican fiscally, and a libertarian socially. That means in regards to business growth, the more local government can get out of the way of small business owners and make running a business in Penndel more attractive, then more business opportunities will present themselves.","","I've run small businesses. I've hired employees and fought up-hill against government red-tape making profits difficult to achieve. I know first-hand the difficulties of working with local and county officials to make my dreams become a reality. I also know that governments do not create businesses, but people with dreams and willing to take risks do.","","I want to be the person on the council with the knowledge and experience to relate to those risk-takers and help make their dreams come true."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_louis_joseph_adams","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Too many potholes are starting to make driving in Penndel unpleasant. Most of Penndel borough is small back-streets that take people home. We need to focus on getting there safely, making sure those roads are properly treated for the snow and plowing events that take place during the winter, and those roads and infrastructure they deliver to our homes are maintained."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_louis_joseph_adams","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am a Republican fiscally, and a libertarian socially. I don't see a need to keep it illegal. I have worked at non-profits and volunteered with homeless organizations in Bucks County and have seen first-hand how pain killers and opium has done more damage to America than marijuana ever could. ","","The sooner we legalize marijuana, the sooner we can grow it in the United States and stop fueling national and international drug crime. People won't risk importing and fueling illegal drug trades with safe access to it at a local dispensary. "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_louis_joseph_adams","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I am a libertarian socially. The government has no right, and never should have a right, to tell people how to live their personal lives. Every person should be allowed fair access to work, go to school, buy or rent property, engage in commerce, assemble and protest peacefully, marry anyone, and pursue the American dream. We need freedom to think and choose for ourselves, be that in our politics, religion, sexuality, or lifestyle. I would never vote for anything that infringes upon those for any group of people. Not just the LGBTQ+, but every group and every individual. "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_council_louis_joseph_adams","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID 19 is a complicated issue that has been impacting all of us. I lost my grandfather to COVID, I lost a business to COVID and had to lay off my staff, I lost a lot. ","","We are close to 70% vaccinated and that number is growing. Life is finally starting to get back to normal for so many of us. I'm not going to support making life harder as we are finally starting to see real victory over this virus. ","","If you're a business owner and you wish to restrict access without a mask, that's your right. I think we can let common sense govern what actions people take without the need for the government to mandate it."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_stacey_champion","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been an active community member. Bensalem has been my hometown for over 50 years having been born and raised here. My parents were great role models in terms of being active members of Bensalem also. My husband and I chose to make Bensalem our home and to raise our children here. I have a strong knowledge base  in understanding budgets and finances having been a controller for 4 of the top banks in the world. I believe the impact of decisions made by council on our safety, financial stability and security for the future of Bensalem are what have made Bensalem a great place to live and raise a family . I am the best for Bensalem because I am committed to it being a great community that all residents, workers and visitors know they are safe through great policing and other first responder efforts plus maintaining a township that we can be proud of from our parks and roads to all the things that makes Bensalem one of the top 100 places to live."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_stacey_champion","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["There are 3 issues I believe face our municipality. The first being the safety of our residents and our first responders serving our community. Bensalem, due to its proximity to Philadelphia has always had more crimes as compared to other Bucks County areas. Roughly 80% of our criminals are from outside Bensalem. Keeping our police force fully funded and operating at the best level with the equipment needed so they can keep our residents, visitors and themselves safe. Our other first responders also should be able to know that the council fully supports them and we will do what we can to continue to provide the needed equipment in order to keep the residents, visitors and themselves safe also. By addressing a safe community we can ensure that Bensalem remains a stable and secure town to live and raise your family. So ensuring stability and security are the other 2 issues."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_stacey_champion","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Bensalem has always supported business growth. It is a balance between residents needs and the businesses. Having a strong business presence helps our residential taxes but also provides jobs and services for our residents to be employed close to home and to use in terms of services. I will continue to support businesses that help our community flourish."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_stacey_champion","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Bensalem has been addressing the storm-water issue over the last few years. I believe we need to continue to do since our borders are compromised of creeks running into the Delaware. I will lobby the Mayor to continue to look at state or federal funding to help this issue as he has done over the course of the last 10 years and work with him on his budget needs that do not raise taxes."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_stacey_champion","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe this is a state issue and should be address at the state level. Bensalem has 3 major cross roads that have been epicenters for drug and sex trafficking. I would not want any laws that would assist in these trades gaining anymore ground."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_stacey_champion","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes I support all protection for everyone no matter who they believe in or who they love. Discrimination should always be addressed and not permitted. I will continue to uphold the laws. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_council_stacey_champion","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["This issue has divided our country and actually our community more than I ever thought something could. I believe that we as it is being stated need to begin to address this virus as something that will always be around and that mandates will not make it go away. I believe people are capable of making their own decisions on what is best for them or their family. Our government is for the people by the people not by the few."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_court_judge_38-1-28_edward_levine","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Experience, qualifications, and an independent and unbiased opinion are essential qualities for a Judge. I am a graduate of Temple School of Law and I have 15 years of legal experience.  Our court has the highest Civil and Landlord Tenant caseload in the county.  Having a Judge with a thorough knowledge of torts, contracts and landlord tenant law is essential.  ","My Qualifications are not just an extensive legal background but also administrative and managerial experience.  A Judge must manage staff and maintain the books.  Since I was elected my court has had perfect audits, and we were just were named an \"Exemplary Court\" by the Pennsylvania Supreme Court.","Finally, I am an independent judge with no conflicts of interest, unlike my opponent who spent 30 years working with the police who will be bringing cases before him.  After spending 30 years believing everyone in the courtroom opposite him is guilty, it is hard to believe that mindset can be changed overnight.  Why even risk it?  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_court_judge_38-1-28_edward_levine","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Mental health and drug addiction are serious problems right now in our county.  As 2nd Vice President of the County Judges Association I have been working with the DA's Office, Public Defenders Office and County officials to work on better measures to treat mental health and drug addiction.   We need early intervention, and I have worked extensively with local agencies to help defendants who have these issues.  I have also worked with the newly established Pre-Trial Services unit to help with bail issues for defendants.  I will continue to be an outspoken voice and leader in the court system for intervention and assistance for those with mental health and drug addiction issues.   The goal is to get treatment and help to minimize recidivism which will also help with tangential matters like domestic and civil issues."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_court_judge_38-1-28_edward_levine","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["Judges are subject to scrutiny at all times.  All of our criminal decisions have checks and balances.  For example, if I dismiss charges the Commonwealth can always refile.  If I set an unreasonable bail parties can file for a bail modification.   All of my civil and landlord tenant matters can be appealed, as can my judgements for traffic and non-traffic matters.  Outside of my decision making, my demeanor and character are always subject to the Judicial Conduct Board.   Fortunately, I have had very few matters appealed (other than traffic tickets where a party appeals because they failed to appear).   I have never had any ethical violations and I run one of the most respected courts in the county, which is why I am the only candidate endorsed by the Fraternal Order of Police and the only candidate with strong support from attorneys throughout the Commonwealth. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_court_of_common_pleas_stephen_corr","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience makes me the best candidate for judicial office.  A judge in the Court of Common Pleas must be prepared to manage and decide a wide variety of cases in different areas of the law.  I am the only candidate to have practiced in all areas of the Court of Common Pleas (Civil Court, Criminal Court, Family Court, and Orphans’ Court).  My broad experience makes me the most qualified for the job.  I have represented individuals, small businesses, and large corporations as both Plaintiffs (those filing a lawsuit) and Defendants (those who have been sued) in both state and federal courts.  Representing the families of those killed on September 11, 2001, I am the co-author of the first lawsuit filed against the terrorists who funded, planned, and carried out that attack.  Because of my vast experience, the lawyers in the Bucks County Bar Association rated me the most highly qualified candidate by a margin of more than 2 to 1.  "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_court_of_common_pleas_stephen_corr","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing the court is access to the courts.  Due to the recent pandemic, the Court of Common Pleas could not hold jury trials for more than one year.  As a result, civil litigants and criminal defendants have not had speedy access to the courts.  I am the only candidate who has experience in a jury trial.  In fact, I have been lead counsel in more than 70 jury trials.  As a result, I will be ready, on day one, to help the court relieve the backlog of jury trials.  With the ongoing uncertainty caused by the pandemic, we also have to make sure that all citizens have easy access to the courts.  As the former chairman of the Bucks County Bar Association’s Technology Committee, I was instrumental in bringing electronic filing to the Bucks County Court of Common Pleas.  Electronic filing and docketing insures that everyone has equal, and convenient, access to the court, and I will continue to improve upon that system to make sure that our court remains open and transparent."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_court_of_common_pleas_stephen_corr","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["In the United States, no person is above the law, and judges are no exception.  I believe judges should be held to the highest standard for ethical conduct both inside and outside the courtroom.  In Pennsylvania, the Judicial Conduct Board is entrusted with the responsibility of investigating complaints of misconduct against judges and, where appropriate, filing formal charges against those judges found to have engaged in unethical behavior.  The Board is made up of judges, lawyers and non-lawyers.  I believe the Board does an excellent job of completing its mission by holding all judges accountable for their actions."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-2-07_michael_\"mick\"_petrucci","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["UNMATCHED EXPERIENCE & COMMITMENT TO COMMUNITY.  As District Judge. As a former law enforcement official. As a deeply committed and longtime community volunteer. And as a local resident, husband and father. I bring to this election a positive record that voters can view for themselves – of handling thousands of trials and tens of thousands of cases fairly and honestly; of bringing compassion and understanding to the bench to help kids who make a mistake get back on the right track; of stepping down from the bench to be active in our community; and, of delivering equal justice for all. My service is based first, of course, in following the law and applying it fairly. But my service is also based on my understanding of our community gained from decades of giving my time to charities, civic organizations, and community groups; from listening to and helping local residents; and, from raising my own family here and dealing with the same challenges as all of us."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-2-07_michael_\"mick\"_petrucci","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The fact is that our local District Court works well and has been recognized by the state for its operations. Local residents have also given our court high marks for fairness, compassion and objectivity – three factors that I believe are vital in what is truly our community’s “People’s Court.” I am very proud of these positive reviews because, as your District Judge, they are the things for which I am responsible. This does not mean we cannot provide even better service. That is why, if I earn your vote for re-election, I will work to expand our “Youth Aid” program that helps put kids who make a mistake back on the right path. I will build upon my active work in our schools and community to help foster a stronger, more trusting bond between residents – especially our children – and our District Court. I will also continue to work with local law enforcement on programs and initiatives that ensure public safety while preserving people’s rights."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-2-07_michael_\"mick\"_petrucci","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":[" To start, I am happy to report that my District Court has received clean audits from the state based on its superlative handling of financial matters. These audits are part of the accountability standards all District Judges face. I believe strongly in accountability for all public officials – judges included.  Pennsylvania has processes in place to ensure the oversight of its judges as well as the public’s ability to lodge official complaints regarding judicial conduct. However, I believe that public knowledge of these processes and procedures is limited at best and confusing at worst; greater public education of these things is something we should do. Of course, the legal system also has built in “accountability” though the ability of citizens to appeal any decisions made by lower courts."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_supreme_court_kevin_brobson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["With over 11 years of service, I am a veteran appellate and trial court judge who understands that all Pennsylvanians deserve to have faith in a fair and impartial judiciary. If elected, I would be the only justice that has served as a Commonwealth Court judge. In this respect, I will add a new voice and a new perspective to the Supreme Court—a justice who has dedicated a career to ensuring that government follows the law and protects the constitutional rights of our citizens. In addition to receiving the Pa. Bar Association’s highest rating in this election, the Supreme Court appointed me to serve as the sole appellate judge member of the Pa. Judicial Conduct Board, the body charged with investigating judicial misconduct. There, the members elected me to serve as chair. Most recently, my colleagues on the Commonwealth Court elected me to serve as court’s President Judge. I thus have the judicial, administrative, and leadership experience to be a Pennsylvania Supreme Court justice."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_supreme_court_kevin_brobson","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing the Pennsylvania Supreme Court, as the leader of Pennsylvania’s unified judiciary, is the preservation of judicial independence and the threat of politicization of our courts. All Pennsylvanians deserve equal access to the courts and to have confidence that the facts and the law, not politics or bias, drive decisions. Judges wear black, not red or blue. While the court cannot entirely shield itself from those quick to criticize its decisions as political, how the justices approach high-profile cases can blunt such criticism.  As I have done as a Commonwealth Court judge who has handled high-profile matters, as a justice, I will endeavor to write clear and thorough opinions grounded in the law.  I will respect the separation of powers and exercise appropriate judicial restraint when asked to tread into areas committed to the other branches of government. This approach, I believe, has contributed to my reputation as a fair and nonpartisan jurist."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_supreme_court_kevin_brobson","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["My term as the sole appellate judge member and Chair of the Judicial Conduct Board of Pennsylvania reaffirmed my commitment to the highest ethical standards as a judge. While most judges approach their duties with professionalism and humility, we must hold accountable any who fail to adhere to the Code of Judicial Conduct (Code) or otherwise engage in unlawful or improper conduct. Our system of judicial discipline under the Pennsylvania Constitution, combined with our criminal justice system, is adequate to the task. Nonetheless, attorneys, other judges, and the public must be diligent in reporting any alleged misconduct to the appropriate authorities. I want to work to educate the public more on the existing system of disciplining judges. We should also examine the current Code to determine whether improvements can be made to the provisions relating to disqualification. I believe judges at all levels, and the public, may benefit from clearer guidance on this subject."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_court_of_common_pleas_tiffany_michelle_thomas-smith","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have the experience, integrity and commitment to community to best serve Bucks County. With over twenty years experience, I am the most qualified candidate.  As a family lawyer, I am uniquely qualified to protect our most vulnerable population, our children and their families. Practicing in Dependency Court, I see first hand the impact of mental health issues and addiction in the county. My background in interest based negotiations provides the expertise to expand alternative dispute resolutions in civil matters and as a Public Defender, I stood up for the rights of the indigent. My commitment to community is evidenced through my work with the Bucks County Bar Association and United Way of Bucks County. As a judge I will utilize these combined skills to provide for fair and just results. Integrity is the lynchpin for our judiciary. The success of the community relies on equal justice, fair and impartial law enforcement and open dialogue. I will bring those qualities to the Bench. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_court_of_common_pleas_tiffany_michelle_thomas-smith","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The most pressing issues in Bucks County Court of Common Pleas include scheduling and filing backlogs, the need for advanced technology,  accessibility to the Court for all members of the community and environmental and safety concerns. The increased backlog and need for increased technology was brought on in large part by the COVID-19 shutdowns. During the COVID crisis my office never shut down. We used technology and paperless options to ensure that our client's needs were met and cases proceeded without interruption. The increase use of technology and virtual platform also provides for greater accessibility for members of the community. The using electronic filing provides for efficiency and reduction of environmental waste. As a Judge, I would continue to use the most efficient and effective means of technology to improve the Courtroom environment for litigants and practitioners. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_court_of_common_pleas_tiffany_michelle_thomas-smith","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["Judges have an ethical responsibility to the community  and should be accountable for their work. However, judges also have a responsibility to make fair and impartial decisions without inappropriate or undue influence of any sort. Judges must strike an balance between independence and accountability. Judges must also invoke fair and non biased decisions and renounce injustice and inequity. What is missing all to often, particularly in family court cases, is the element of compassion. People in the community deserve to be treated with \"compassionate justice,\"  which is the intersection of understanding and empathy for others, coupled with the fair and well-reasoned application of the law. As a Judge, I would apply the concept of compassionate justice as a consideration in cases where that additional element would provide for the most fair, efficient and just result. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_stacy_seaman-wertman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the best candidate because of my hands-on experience, integrity and values.  I am the ONLY candidate trained and tested for this position, just as our last three judges were, as are 65% of all MDJ's in Pennsylvania.  For 18+ years, I have been a Constable, the law enforcement arm of the District Court (DC), therefore I have been involved in every aspect of the DC.  My hands-on experience is vast, from explaining rights to a prisoner, serving civil orders, to attending thousands of hearings.  I teach legal and civil classes for Temple University.  As for integrity, I feel the DC deserves my complete attention.  I will be your full-time judge.  It will be my first priority, not developing a law practice. Having grown up in Warwick, I understand the area. Serving the people of Warrington and Warwick for 18+ years has shaped my values.  Believing in safety and security, I am proud of having the FOP endorsement.  With my retired Navy husband, I work our organic farm and raise our son."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_stacy_seaman-wertman","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Mental healthcare is the biggest issue facing the justice system today and only getting worse with the recent isolation from COVID.  I have dealt with this issue for most of my career as a Constable.  The limited mental healthcare options available when I started almost 20 years ago was truly sad.  However, in recent years, it has been improving.  Alternative programs at the County level are slowly working down to the District Court level.  The District Court is the first step in the criminal justice system and catching the issues early, can get them the help they need to stay out of the system, reduce recidivism and stops the revolving door.  When I catch issues at the District Court level and get a person services, many issues can be addressed.  Intervention and alternative programs need to be used more often.  With my knowledge and experience, I am the best person to get them the help they need.   "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_stacy_seaman-wertman","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["I do feel judges are held accountable for their actions.  Magisterial District Judges have many levels of oversight, starting with the Bucks County Court Administrator, who deals with day to day issues.  Next is the President Judge of the County, who is their direct boss and who sets local rules for MDJs.  They can remove a MDJ from the bench.  Next is the Administrative Office of Pennsylvania Courts (AOPC), the office that investigates all complaints against Judges in Pennsylvania.  They can remove, sanction and even charge Judges.  Most of all, MDJs are answerable to the voters every six years.  Being a Judge does not shelter a person from having to follow the rules.  They should hold themselves to a higher standard.  Judges need to avoid any issues by following their Canons.  These are specific rules for Judges to live by before and during their time on the bench, such as devoting sufficient time to be at court, making ethical decisions and more stringent campaign finance rules."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_drew_crompton","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["  ","Since January of 2020, I have served as an appointed Judge on the Commonwealth Court. I was confirmed by a bipartisan Senate vote and was recently recommended by the Pa. Bar Association. I am seeking a full ten-year elected term on November 2nd.  ","","I have issued approximately 125 well-reasoned and thoughtful opinions to date. I have been endorsed by the FOP, the Pa. Chamber of Commerce, trade organizations, and a broad array of others. I interpret the law as written and do not legislate from the bench. ","","Prior to becoming a judge, I served as an attorney for the Legislative and Executive branches of state government. I have also appeared as a lawyer numerous times before the Pa. Commonwealth and Supreme Courts. ","","The Commonwealth Court decides issues dealing with almost every aspect of state government. I built a career on ensuring that the government follows the law and this is what I will continue to do if elected. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_drew_crompton","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["","Too many people in Pennsylvania have lost some faith in our judicial system. As I talk to voters all across the state, they tell me that they believe judges have become too political and often decide cases on their own philosophy rather than based on our Constitution or laws.  ","","I know what judges are supposed to do and what they are not to do. Over the past two years as a sitting Commonwealth Court Judge, I have “stayed in my lane” and have ensured that the other two branches of government do the same. I have tried to always keep a level temperament even when lawyers or witnesses do not.  ","","Moreover, I have tried to author opinions that are balanced and straightforward. I do not editorialize in my opinions. I believe that in order to do restore some faith in our judicial system, judges must be independent and interpret the law as it is written. Further, all people must receive the same justice regardless of race, political affiliation or economic means. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_drew_crompton","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["A crucial part of accountability is ensuring that information about each case is publicly available. For the past year, I have chaired a committee that is working to put all critical legal information online and available to lawyers and the public at large. Currently, every opinion of the Commonwealth Court is online, as it should be. However, the project that I am involved with would also post additional information which is crucial to ensure fairness. ","","During the early part of the COVID pandemic, the Commonwealth Court streamed all of its proceedings on YouTube. This should continue even as we return to live arguments. The public should have the ability to watch all judicial arguments online. ","","Lastly, we must also ensure that there is a strong Judicial Conduct Board where individuals can file complaints against judges for misconduct. Judges must be held to high ethical standards if we are to expect the general public to have faith in our Judicial system."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-2-07_mark_b._zinman","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["A good judge seeks out experience. A great judge is humbled by the community depending on you to get it right. In my 40 years of professional practice, as an accountant and small business owner, I face the pressure to get it right every day. My clients are often faced with decisions that lead to their success or failure. They rely on me to navigate the unknown, make sense of the complexity, and to get it right. As a result, none of my clients lost their businesses during the pandemic. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-2-07_mark_b._zinman","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["From losing local businesses to changing the way we live day to day; our community is not immune to the global pandemic. The local court makes many rulings over many civil matters, but the pandemic has brought landlord tenant disputes to the forefront. There are going to be many of our fellow residents who are going to need relief. Unit owners certainly have the right to be paid their agreed rent, but renters may have legitimate economic concerns and need a place to live. I want to be certain that our community has faith in the system and that the system is going to be fair to them. You have the right of society versus the rights of the individual that need to be weighed, and I would keep those scales in balance as best I can. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-2-07_mark_b._zinman","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["Our state judicial system has many layers, with the magisterial courts at the bottom, and elections are held where citizens can hold judges accountable. However, what is missing is transparency throughout the system. Once a judge is elected, they a have a high degree of authority. For example, to set fines and decide when cases are heard. This can lead to judges inserting their bias, leading to different punishments for the same crime. The social unrest that rises in our society is based, partially, on the appearance of different rules for different people. Judges need to be held accountable to the public and make sure that their work is transparent. The goal is show our community that everyone in our local court is treated fairly under the law, as it should be."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_patrice_tisdale","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the best candidate for the Magisterial District Judge (MDJ) because I have the experience sitting in a judicial role, the compassion for those that appear before me, and I am involved in various organizations that work for the betterment of our community. The MDJ is responsible for making decisions that affects both the lives of the individual that appear before them, which ripples to the community at large. The MDJ should be a person that is involved in the community, beyond just having lived here, as they will have a better understanding of how one action/decision affects the wider community. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_patrice_tisdale","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issues that constituents have expressed to me regarding the MDJ is impartiality and having an individual that understands the law. Although I am engaged in the community on a personal level, I am not entwined within the Bucks County legal/law enforcement community, as such, any matter that comes before me will be met with an impartial eye regardless of who the prosecutor, defense attorney, defendant, plaintiff, or law enforcement officer involved may be. As a former federal attorney, I have prided myself with consistently being the neutral party tasked with figuring out what justice requires in each situation. I will continue to bring that neutrality to this role. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_patrice_tisdale","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["For the most part  yes, judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions because the individuals that appear before them have recourse if the judge's action does not comport with either case law, judicial canons, or legal ethics imposed on attorneys. In some instances, judges are not held accountable when there is insufficient transparency regarding the decisions they make from the bench. I plan on providing a higher level of transparency by providing explanations for the decisions that I make, either written or orally from the bench, to the parties involved in each matter.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_david_lee_spurgeon","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the only candidate that received the top rating of \"Highly Recommended\" for Commonwealth Court by the Pennsylvania Bar Association - a non-partisan group that is comprised of lawyers and community members from across the state.  I have a proven record as a trial judge and have been a public servant leader on the bench.  Recognized for my judicial leadership, I was named a National Judicial Fellow by the National Council of Juvenile and Family Court Judges.  As national expert in the area of domestic violence,  I have numerous appearances as a legal expert on COURT TV as well serve as a local and national panelist in many forums.  As the former lead prosecutor in Allegheny County for these crime types and improved the court system to be more responsive to this issue.  As Deputy District Attorney, I was an integral part in the creation and/or supervision of our problem solving courts including Veterans' Court, Mental Health Court and a Repeat Batterers docket.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_david_lee_spurgeon","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["A fresh perspective is needed on the court.  I was raised in a blue collar steel town, as the steel industry collapsed.  My father worked for the railroad and was a 42 member of the union.  I also was a union member for 11 years with the United Steelworkers.  This Court hears all labor related cases yet lacks people serving that have experience in this area.  I am the first person in my family to graduate from college or law school and understand that this court makes decisions each day that impact all Pennsylvanians.  I plan to bring impartiality to the Commonwealth Court.  The Commonwealth Court ensures that the government follows the law and the voice of the people is not silenced.  I spent nearly 19 years ensuring accountability as a prosecutor and the government should be held to the same standard.  The Commonwealth Court also sits a trial judge in specific cases and I have already served with distinction in that capacity while others have no experience in this area.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_david_lee_spurgeon","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["Judges should always be held accountable for actions that do not meet the level of decorum judicial offers must hold.  People need to believe that the judicial system is fair, open and accessible to all our community members.  Anyone that does not promote these concepts should be addressed by the many forums that already exist.  The Courts must be open to evolve and further dialogue in this area would foster new ways to ensure all members of the judiciary are accountable to the people they serve.  I, personally, continue to be very active in my communities to ensure that my role is deemed to be accessible and to give people the opportunity to interact with a member of the court on a personal level to foster that dialogue."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_supreme_court_maria_c._mclaughlin","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["The breadth of experience I have gained over the course of my 29-year legal career makes me the standout candidate in this race. I am the only candidate who has served as a prosecutor and litigator for 19 years and with experience as a trial judge who has never had a decision overturned. I’ve presided over cases involving election law and labor law and currently sit on the busiest appellate court in the nation.","","Having invested time in all 67 counties, I am a commonsense judge who has always garnered bipartisan support throughout Pennsylvania. I will carry my values formed as the daughter of a working class family and a single mom of two boys for many years with me to our Supreme Court.",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_supreme_court_maria_c._mclaughlin","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The Supreme Court recently initiated the Autism and the Courts: A Regional Discussion initiative, with the goal of improving the court system for people with autism. Sharing with my husband an adult child with special needs and grandchildren with autism, this initiative is personal to me and I would love to use my experience to help shape the success of this program. ","","The courts throughout the Commonwealth could use similar initiatives to create more treatment courts. There are large populations that are in need of mental health treatment and drug treatment; many of them veterans. Pennsylvania has one of the largest populations of veterans, but there is not a sufficient number of Veterans Treatment Courts. I come from a family of veterans, so this issue is also personal to me.","","I have a lot to offer because of both my personal and professional experiences and I have never been one to sit aside when I know changes can be made for the greater good.",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_supreme_court_maria_c._mclaughlin","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["As an elected official and public servant, I go to work every day knowing it is a privilege to serve and that I am accountable to the people of Pennsylvania. I never forget I represent everyone in the Commonwealth and my decisions have always and will always reflect that. ","","I am proud to be on an appellate court where my decisions are transparent and easily accessible for the general public. I hope voters take advantage of this because it is within their power to hold us accountable with their vote. That is why judicial elections matter. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_stacy_wallace","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["One of my primary considerations in choosing to run for Commonwealth Court was where my diverse legal background could best serve our judicial system. The Commonwealth Court’s unique role in our judiciary and its focus on matters involving state government agencies, as well as elections, means its decisions can potentially impact both the state and the nation. With this critical role in mind, Pennsylvania residents should expect Commonwealth Court judges with the relevant legal experience necessary to offer informed and just opinions on such matters. Given my legal career’s substantive and procedural overlap with the Commonwealth Court’s legal jurisdictions – such as election law, municipal law, and regulatory law including banking and unemployment compensation  – and my experience drafting opinions at the appellate level, I believe I am well prepared and uniquely qualified to serve on the Commonwealth Court."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_stacy_wallace","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe the top concern facing not just this office, but Pennsylvania’s court system as a whole, is that our state courts and judges are not reflective of the broad spectrum of backgrounds, values, and opinions held by the residents of the Commonwealth whose laws they are elected to uphold. Overall, Pennsylvania’s state court judges tend to be residents of our Commonwealth’s major cities, and might not necessarily have the depth and breadth of legal experience possessed by attorneys from more rural areas of Pennsylvania. As a result, many Pennsylvanians may feel left behind by or alienated from our court system. If elected to the Commonwealth Court, I will address this issue by relying on my unique background to offer these often unheard and underrepresented Pennsylvanians a voice on all matters that come before the court. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsylvania_commonwealth_court_stacy_wallace","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["There is room for improvement when it comes to current measures meant to hold Pennsylvania’s judges accountable. Current tools allow attorneys and judges to report their colleagues if they violate judicial canons, and empower the legislative branch to impeach judges who violate the state and federal constitutions. While these mechanisms should promote accountability, a judge’s actions are often not reported for fear of repercussions. At the same time, these practices can be abused to attack judges because of a personal opinion or disagreement with a judicial decision. To remedy these issues, I suggest mandatory education for both attorneys and judges on the importance of accountability. I also encourage voters to take a more active role in ensuring their elected officials hold unethical judges accountable. Voters need to actively engage with legislators and candidates to evaluate their capability to enforce the checks and balances that exist for our protection. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_patrice_tisdale","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the best candidate because I am the only candidate certified by the Supreme Court of 3 States, and I am the only candidate that has the community involvement to fully understand the impact that the District Court has community. ","","This is a community court and the person serving as the MDJ should be one that respects the community enough to do more than the basic requirement of a 4-week course. The MDJ should be involved in the betterment of the community. I am that person. I serve on a variety of Local & County wide boards that seek to only better the lives of residents. I do not simply exist within the community.  I have over 20 years of involvement in the criminal justice system, and have seen all aspects of the effects of good and bad judicial decisions. This experience along with being a trained attorney has given me insight, creative perspective, and a solid knowledge base to ensure justice is served for everyone involved. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_patrice_tisdale","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue for this court is providing clarity & neutrality to each individual to ensure justice is properly served; whether it is the prosecutor, defendant, plaintiff, or law enforcement officer. As a trained investigator and prosecutor, I have always exercised clarity & neutrality while seeking to understand the “why.” This experience, training, and lack of entanglement with local law enforcement will appropriately guide my decisions to truly address the reason a person appears before me and equip me with the information needed to render the decision justice requires: whether it is a drug treatment program, creative ways to address truancy, or making the court more accessible for individuals. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_07-3-02_patrice_tisdale","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["Overall yes. There are several layers of accountability for judges from which individuals can avail themselves if they believe a judge’s actions do not comport with judicial canons, or ethics. However, at the MDJ level, there is one additional layer of accountability that is not in play for the non-attorneys that occupy this role. In addition to the being subjected to the judicial oversight pathways, licensed attorneys are also subjected to the Disciplinary Board of the Supreme Court of PA. This added layer of oversight not just threatens the removal from the bench should a judge’s actions call for it, but it also threatens the loss of the license to practice law. This additional layer of accountability should be imposed on MDJs by requiring that the judge that sits at this important level of court be a licensed attorney - as it is for every other level of court within the Commonwealth. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_ricardo_cancel","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["This is opportunity for West York to bring new insights to council that will work for the future with New Visions for the better of the community with diversity in growth I will make sure every decision made by the borough in the best interest of the residents and business owners  I going to bring good changes for sure"]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_ricardo_cancel","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Finances for sure and borough is  fiscally Responsible for the use of tax payers money to be able to continue providing quality services to the community as police ambulance etc etc "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_ricardo_cancel","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I want to help with council to Find new ways to help actual business and new business to open in west York "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_ricardo_cancel","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Fix the streets and make utilities companies pave road as they work this will help motorists with smother and safer ride around the borough "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_ricardo_cancel","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["My decision It’s has to be the best interest of the residents and children’s living in my area ",""]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_ricardo_cancel","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes everyone has Rights we all have to respect for sure because there’s a lot of great people part of the lesbian and gay community doing a great job for our country and our neighborhood there’s no reason to discriminate against them or anyone Base on their sex orientation or either race or color of their skin "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_ricardo_cancel","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Keep our neighborhood safe is very important we shall follow CDC guidelines and common sense too. "]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_dave_bush","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Many months ago, I decided to give something back to the community by running for Township Supervisor.  I stand for open government, honesty, integrity, and will follow the Constitution word for word.  My only agenda is serving the residents to the best of my ability."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_dave_bush","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Fair and honest government, lower property taxes, and a safer Route 15 through our community.  I will fight to improve these issues on a local and state level!"]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_dave_bush","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As a former business owner I know regulations are a big deterrent to growth.  We need to work with the business community to streamline as many rules and regulations as possible.      We also need to reduce taxes which will stimulate growth."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_dave_bush","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Route 15 in the Dillsburg-Carroll township area needs a major upgrade for safety, business growth, and convenience of the residents.  Over the years the increased traffic flow on Route 15 has caused many traffic accidents and loss of life. The original design of Route 15 was very inadequate for the increased traffic flow of today.  A limited access highway would have been a better design. Now Penn-D.O.T. may need to totally reroute Route 15 to solve the problem."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_dave_bush","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":[" No.   I will support honest medical use only.  I am old school!"]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_dave_bush","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":[" When Supervisors are elected they take an oath of office which includes a pledge to uphold all local state and federal laws.  I take the oath of office very seriously and will strive to uphold my oath of office."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_dave_bush","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":[" I am a science guy and the masks do not qualify for use as intended. The negative issues with masks far out weighs the positive. You must obey the laws even if you are sure the government is wrong, but then, you must use common sense and work hard to change them!  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_alan_vandersloot","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been a community and Labor leader for over 45 years. York College of PA Class of 1969; Leadership York (first class) graduate 1979; 48 year union member and delegate to York Adams Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO; Board President of White Rose Senior Center ; Service on several other local community boards and committees.   Current Borough Council member , since 2017- Finance Committee chair; Received 2021 Certified Borough Official certification from PA State Association of Boroughs; Serve on York County Boroughs Association executive committee.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_alan_vandersloot","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Boroughs have unique issues mainlining their relevance to residents and businesses.   West York is very unique in that we are a \"full service\" Borough-  Our public safety budget is about two thirds of our revenue expenditures. We provide police; fire and public works through our dedicated unionized professional employees.  Trying to provide these needed services and not increasing our property tax rates steeply is a major challenge.  As Finance Committee chair, the committee and I work closely with our Borough Manager to monitor annual budgets. We look for innovative grant proposals, maintaining  a close mutually beneficial  relationship with our unions is very important.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_alan_vandersloot","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Being a landlocked municipality has prevented West York from attracting major business growth.  We try to keep mercantile tax rates reasonable and provide full time police , fire and public works departments to provide stability,  We will always work closely with federal. state, county and other municipalities to seek ways to support our budget by inter-governmental cooperation. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_alan_vandersloot","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Incorporated as a Borough in 1903, we experience instances of property neglect; parking shortages, need of street and utility upgrades, and blight.   West York has the highest population density rate in York County  ( approx. 10,000 persons per square mile) We are updating our ordinances and codes  to address neglected properties.   We need to govern smartly going forward. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_alan_vandersloot","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes.  We did try to support decriminalization of small amounts of marijuana  a few years ago, but the proposed ordinance failed to be passed. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_alan_vandersloot","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes.  This nation has always been diverse, and is growing more so as the years pass. West York is certainly very diverse! I support the implementation of a county-wide human relations commissions and I supported West York being a satellite resource office of the York City Human Relations Commission. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_alan_vandersloot","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes.   I  follow the science.   As an  elected official, I can offer opinions how to deal with a pandemic, but we will not conquer this problem by ignoring the advice of those who understand the gravity of the situation.   We just passed the death rate of the pandemic Spanish Flu of 1918. We have developed vaccines and understand the modes of transmission of COVID. We need to support the recommendations of the experts.  Let's start feeling safer to get back to normal life activities.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have always listened to the residents.  If they contact me I answer to the best of my knowledge.  If I don’t know the answer I will tell them I will find out and get back to them.  I will fight for them all the way."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Tax increases and refuse increases.  We have a lot of residents who cannot afford it.  The refuse was raised twice in one year.  They have to decide if they will buy groceries or the medicines they need.  No one should be in this position."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will welcome and support them.  We must try our best to support the local businesses."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Everyone needs to work together.  Complaints should be dealt with at the office and not on Facebook, Twitter etc.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["That depends on the situation people know the consequences before they use it."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["No answer to this one"]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_mary_wagner","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is tough.  People who got the vaccine still get it, people who support mask mandates still get it.  People with certain health issues don’t have to wear it.  There is no happy ending and I believe it should be the people’s choice."]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_tara_wenzel","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["After spending 37 years of proudly serving and defending my country overseas and at home as an intelligence officer, I now want to take those skills to serve and defend my community. I have been working for over the last year and a half trying to hold our elected leaders accountable. In addition, I started the first Municipal Website and Municipal Facebook page the Township ever had. I now manage the Heidelberg Township Community Facebook page for keeping our residents informed. My goal with winning this seat is to create an atmosphere for our residents where they feel that they can attend the Public Meetings and  if they have an issue to present, feel that they will be heard, treated with respect, and that research will be done to try to work through those issues. I also want more residents to know WHERE the taxpayer money they work so hard for is going AND that they feel the Supervisors are representing them. Many residents have shared with me that either they don't know when the Public Meetings are (something I have changed with the Heidelberg Township Community Facebook page and NextDoor) or that they used to go, but felt that nothing ever changed or got done. "]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_tara_wenzel","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["More transparency for financial spending. Our residents need to know where their taxpayer money is going and I plan on making that a top priority if I am elected. I'd also welcome more resident participation in earmarking where these funds should go."]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_tara_wenzel","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Our Township is rural and we like it that way, but I also see a real need to reach out to those small businesses that are already here to let them know that they are appreciated. "]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_tara_wenzel","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Many of our residents have brought up problems with flooding issues they have. I would research what grants would be available and look at the possibility of using some of the Federal Infrastructure money to help resolve some of those issues. "]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_tara_wenzel","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I feel our local Police Force handles this issue appropriately at this time."]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_tara_wenzel","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I feel that ALL people should be treated equally and with respect."]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_tara_wenzel","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe that answer depends on the situation. There has been a lot mixed messaging that has made this a very difficult situation. I work part time in a special needs classroom and wear my mask every day as I want to protect these beautiful young children as much as I can. I do feel there are certain situations where masking could be optional, such as eating in restaurants. I keep our residents updated once a week on our Heidelberg Township Community page with the latest PA Dept of Health statistics for the two towns that our Township encompasses, not to make a political statement one way or the other, but to provide information so our residents can make appropriate decisions for protecting themselves and their families."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_deana_weaver","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["    Community involvement over the past 25 years has taught me how to coordinate activities with politicians and governmental agencies. I have volunteered for Dillsburg Youth Baseball, Northern York Community Foundation, Dillsburg Library, Northern York School District. As co-founder of Carroll Citizens for Sensible Growth, I was recognized at local, state, and federal levels for environmental cleanups of roadways, watersheds, and private properties under. ","     I am currently in my fourth 3-year term on Carroll Township's Zoning Hearing Board, having Chaired the Board in my third term.  ","     I worked closely with Representative Scott Perry to end the PA Beneficial Use Program for municipal waste ash that was toxic to our community. While then-Colonel Perry was stationed in Iraq, I aided him in establishing two libraries, one in the Green Zone and one on base camp."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_deana_weaver","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Building community support for our newly-merged fire company, Station 15.  When Dillsburg  and Franklintown stations merged, a void was left in community outreach.  This is not only critical for financial support, but it is the only way to build on the future of a volunteer force.  It is critical to work with local businesses to gain their acceptance and participation in allowing volunteer firefighters to leave their place of employment in order to respond to fire calls. It is also critical to discern what level calls will generate that response."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_deana_weaver","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Business growth in the area is predominately dependent upon traffic access. This has been a slow process over the past 25 years, and we are currently entering a revitalization phase with improvements to Route 15.  Carroll Township's identity is intertwined with that of Dillsburg Borough, and building a local economic base will take cooperation between them and the five other municipalities making up our school district."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_deana_weaver","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Improving the flow of traffic on Route 15 is critical and already in the works. Municipalities must work with the school district to lessen fiscal impacts of new development, with the goal of stabilizing property taxes. This should be a priority.  "]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_deana_weaver","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The benefits of medical marijuana have now challenged the automatic assessment that its use should constitute a crime.  This change in attitude and law alone will decrease the costs of incarceration on our communities and the subsequent forgiveness will allow for more productive lives."]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_deana_weaver","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["It should never be legal to persecute or otherwise cause harm, either financial or emotional, based solely on a personal inability to accept social or cultural differences.  "]},{"candidateCode":"carroll_township_supervisor_deana_weaver","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["   I would support an effort to educate individuals on why they should wear masks under certain conditions.   It is every adult's individual choice to protect themselves from harm. For children, I believe it is reasonable to place stricter conditions in order to protect them from circumstances where they have no voice."]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_melody_stine","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I was raised as a very community-oriented person and was taught that you should be involved to help make your community a prosperous and welcoming one."]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_melody_stine","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["As a borough we are land-locked and therefore taxes are always an issue.  The rising costs of waste collection and recycling, as well as emergency services will continue to take a toll on a community like ours with no changes in the tax revenue due to limited space. "]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_melody_stine","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["The problem with a small borough such as ours is the again, space.  When previous business storefronts are being converted into housing/rental space it makes it nearly impossible to encourage businesses to come into our community.  Once a space becomes a housing opportunity it rarely returns back to a business/retail space.  I would encourage our community to utilize the businesses we have in Hallam, so they can continue to thrive. "]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_melody_stine","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Bridges!  We have had quite a few issues due to to the heavy storms that have come through Hallam in the last few years.  Having the Kreutz Creek flow through our borough always presents challenges, but right now it's the bridges that need the most attention. We have a plan in place to replace the Cherry St bridge by mid-2022 and the walking bridge at Emig Park will be replaced once we secure grant money to cover the cost. "]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_melody_stine","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I don't believe that marijuana is a \"gateway\" drug and have always supported the legalization of marijuana for medicinal as well as recreational use.  "]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_melody_stine","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["100% I stand behind Hallam being a welcoming community for ALL peoples.  During Pride month, for the last four years, we have had a mayoral proclamation in support of the LGBTQ+ community and recognizing that their struggles are human struggles.  We all do better when we all do better. "]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_melody_stine","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Of course.  I believe in science and want a community that does our part to help alleviate the burden on our healthcare system and it's burnt-out employees.  "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_donald_b._wright","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Focus on accomplishing the mission of Municipal Government without letting National politics interfere.  Drive to notice our Boroughs roads and storm water system. Concern for private property rights and  lowering property taxes. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_donald_b._wright","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Rising cost for services, that will outpace revenues is then largest issue facility by all local Governments.  I have been trying to push the repair and restoration of our streets today in order to avoid future cost overruns. ","Policing cost will become a larger issue as this cost takes a larger percentage of the Budget. We should not lock ourselves into a one provider mindset but stay open to finding other resources to accomplish the public safety mission. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_donald_b._wright","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Keep property tax fixed or lowering. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_donald_b._wright","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Repairing aging streets and Storm water. ","Providing a long term plan to stay ahead of maintenance and replacement of infrastructure has been my concern for several years.  "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_donald_b._wright","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is not a local issue.  These are State laws Jacobus as a municipality should not get involved in the political distractions and cost of these policies. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_donald_b._wright","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_donald_b._wright","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["No.  Mask or no mask should be up to the property owner and individual. "]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_michael_a._albert","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have four years, nine months of successful experience in the position! "]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_michael_a._albert","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["All of the issues facing us at the moment are handled by and reside in the jurisdiction of the Borough Council! I am not involved in any of them! "]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_michael_a._albert","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We are a very small Borough with little to no rum to grow. For the time being promoting our existing business will be the priority! "]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_michael_a._albert","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Once again, these infrastructure issues are competently handled by our Borough Council with only my voiced input, either for or against their actions."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_michael_a._albert","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would not! "]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_michael_a._albert","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["They are covered under the existing laws and would continue to do so with out providing extra protection for targeted groups because of who they are! "]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_michael_a._albert","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["NO! Absolutely not! People want to wear a mask, it is up to them to decide, not me or anyone else! ","COVID cases may rise and they may fall in accordance with the virus type. There is NO difference between the COVID Virus and the normal flu virus! Both are Coronaviruses! No one EVER worried or stressed over the Flu cases in past years, nor were they EVER politicized as COVID has been done! No one EVER wore a mask, either! People got the flu and got sick or got sick and died or they didn't! Its what viruses do! ","It has been medically proven as well, that masks do NOT prevent people from getting the virus, or ANY virus for that matter! ","It's akin to putting a cyclone fence around your house to protect you from mosquitoes! Forced mask wearing is child abuse, in the least, and damaging to their lungs when used extensively! Do your own research and stop believing everything you hear from people with a fancy title, or overpaid snake oil salesmen, but DO question their agendas! "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_debbie_dubbs_loucks","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Experience, knowledge of the community, and the ability to utilize resources to make informed decisions (including listening).  Experience includes 4+ years on the borough council and experience through employment as an administrator, including, but not limited to, project and contract management, supervision, planning, preparing and overseeing budgets, development, mediation, conducting 1000+ meetings, conducting informal hearings, grant writing and team building.  Knowledge of community comes from residing in Jacobus as a child, a renter (went into housekeeping on Main Street) and a homeowner since the 80's.   As a retiree, I can give the time and attention needed to this office.  "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_debbie_dubbs_loucks","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We are a small, community oriented municipality with one part-time employee, the borough manager.  We're fortunate to have many helpful volunteers.   Having financial resources to meet all the needs is impossible, so planning/budgeting to meet the needs over a period of time is necessary.   We're also in need of improving our method of communicating to our residents.  I support, and hope to assist in, developing a new method of providing timely, relevant information in a manner that is accessible to all residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_debbie_dubbs_loucks","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Encourage future and existing business owners to communicate their needs and wishes with us and respond timely to those communications.    I would be open to change, which is sometimes needed. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_debbie_dubbs_loucks","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Currently, maintaining streets, our park grounds and amenities, other property owned by the borough, and our borough building.   These are maintained in accordance with budgeted contracts , and sometimes with assistance from various grants available to the borough.   New to the borough in the not-to-distant future will be Water Street, which is currently maintained by the State (along with Main Street, Valley Road and York Road).   Assisting with the needs of our volunteer fire department and ambulance services is also necessary, which I would continue to support based on the borough's abilities. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_debbie_dubbs_loucks","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["If and when necessary, I would listen to the pros and cons and decide based on what I believe is best for our community.   I would take into consideration any recommendations by the entity the borough contracts with for police services (currently York Regional Police)."]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_debbie_dubbs_loucks","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I believe everyone should be treated equally; however, I am unaware of a reason why our borough should put such protections in place at this time.   That doesn't mean I am against considering local protections for our borough in the future. "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_debbie_dubbs_loucks","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["My answer to this differs from what I might have stated months ago.  At this time, I am in support of such mandates in public places if they are recommended by the local health officials who know the conditions within our health facilities.  In the past, I would have supported individual decisions; however, I join many in our community who have seen that many individuals are not making choices that consider the entire community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_lisa_zortman_gross","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I fought to save the union firefighters jobs when council voted to eliminate the department.  West York deserves people in local government who are willing to do what is right, not what is easy.  I don't shy away from hard work or hard to tackle issues."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_lisa_zortman_gross","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Crime and blight are two of the top issues facing West York presently.  I support the addition of two full time police officers to support our community.  West York is making progress on addressing blight issues, but more can be done.  I'd propose an additional employee for our public works department.  I'd like to also see a volunteer corps in the Borough working with residents to improve properties."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_lisa_zortman_gross","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I'd like to establish a working group of council members, business owners and the Mayor's office to better understand the challenges of doing business in the Borough.  I'd also like to work with local businesses to offer apprentice type training for local students."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_lisa_zortman_gross","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["West York needs to work with neighboring municipalities on flood control.  I support moving forward with current proposals from the Borough engineer.  Additionally, I'd like to see more businesses, residents and borough buildings adding solar alternatives to their energy plans. West York doesn't have much available land, but we have plenty of roof space and we should be making use of it.  "]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_lisa_zortman_gross","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support decriminalization or legalizing marijuana use by adults in both West York and the Commonwealth."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_lisa_zortman_gross","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I'd support an ordinance that explicitly prohibits employment or housing discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation, gender identity, or gender expression.  I'd support a public nondiscrimination statement that the Borough will not discriminate in the provision of public services, programs, and activities, because of race, color, religion, sex, age, national origin, disability, genetic information, sexual orientation, sexual preference, gender identity or expression, or political affiliation."]},{"candidateCode":"west_york_council_lisa_zortman_gross","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would support a mask mandate if COVID cases significantly rise.  Science tells us that masking, social distancing and frequent hand washing helps prevent the spread of COVID.  I will follow the guidelines of the CDC and other medical professionals."]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_timothy_hansen","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a former member of the Heidelberg Township Planning Commission and have been a township supervisor for the past 18 years.  Under my leadership, I have enacted zoning changes to limit development, controlled taxes, expanded police hours and kept a police presence in our township, increased road maintenance and paving, expanded our township parks, and increased our fire company funding.  These efforts have made Heidelberg Township a desirable and safe place to live. ","","Professionally, I am a project manager for a Fortune 500, multi-national medical engineering company, and manage teams of people and solve complicated issues on a daily basis.  Personally, I have been a resident of the township for over 55 years and every decision I have/will make is because I genuinely care about the residents and the future of the township.","","For these reasons, I am the best and uniquely qualified candidate to lead Heidelberg Township going forward, just as I have successfully done in the past.",""]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_timothy_hansen","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The township’s top issue will be implementing a sewer facilities program (ACT 537) mandated by the state.  ","The primary reason I ran for supervisor 18 years ago was because the township was ready to implement a large-scale sewer system which would have cost the taxpayers of Heidelberg Township millions of dollars. It also would have changed the character of the township forever since large-scale sewer systems attract the development of high-density housing. I was able to convince the other supervisors and the DEP to continue with the existing systems and delay the implementation of ACT 537.","","We’ve been successful in delaying this plan until recently, but the township is now required to act.  The township is currently working with the DEP and at this critical juncture, I am well positioned to prevent a large-scale sewage plant from being implemented. I believe the citizens of Heidelberg Township want to keep the township rural and am doing everything in my power to keep it this way.","  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_timothy_hansen","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Our community’s largest and highest income industry is farming.  I will continue to support our farmers by preserving farmland, enacting ordinances, and working with our local law enforcement to protect farmers from nuisance complaints.","","Additionally, my contributions to the creation of the Comprehensive Plan ensured that sufficient land is available today to expand industrial and commercial use.  As a result, Heidelberg Township is well positioned to increase our tax revenue as new businesses move into these designated areas.",""]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_timothy_hansen","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Roads are a continuing infrastructure need that plague small townships such as ours, that have a limited budget.  Under my leadership, the township is constantly assessing roads that are in need of major repairs and attending to those by paving and repairing drainage issues, sometimes even when there are state roads involved and the state refuses to address the issue.  ","","I foresee the drainage problems will worsen with the increased frequency of extreme weather.  Mitigation measures are currently in progress in a number of areas throughout the township by eliminating foliage, grading, and adding culverts and storm drains.",""]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_timothy_hansen","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The township will continue to follow state laws regarding this matter since state law overrides any local ordinance."]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_timothy_hansen","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Throughout my tenure as a township supervisor, the township never discriminated against a person based on their sexual orientation and will continue to do so, with or without protections.  "]},{"candidateCode":"heidelberg_township_supervisor_timothy_hansen","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I trust that the business owners and citizens of Heidelberg Township are able to make their own informed decision on mask usage without government interference. I do not support new or renewed restrictions."]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_nedette_otterbein","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["The experiences, skills, and knowledge I have gained throughout my career give me ","a uniquely diverse perspective that will bring balance to the Board of Supervisors for ","Hellam Township. ","","Each position has taught me:","• Collaborative problem-solving to meet a goal, quota or mission","• Leadership and team-building skills","• Fiduciary and ethical standards","• Strategic planning and volunteer management ","• Process analysis and project management","• Communication, outreach and marketing expertise that promotes transparency","","The best asset we have in Hellam Township is our people. I listen, connect people ","and find the right resources for the job. I am passionate about my community and bring ","energy to the processes and procedures involved in running our Township. ","We need a balanced voice on our Board of Supervisors. Instead of debating whether ","or not growth should be allowed, we need leadership that focuses on how and where new ","development should be accommodated. I am that balanced voice."]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_nedette_otterbein","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Hellam Township is faced with the challenge of balancing the needs of our residents, businesses, and agricultural operations. We need leadership that focuses our community on the maintenance and improvement of our quality of life. We face increasing pressure from the gradual encroachment of sprawl resulting from indifferent leadership. Sprawl contributes to a decline in community distinctiveness and cohesiveness.  We need leadership that prioritizes efforts so that we do not experience the costs and rising taxes associated with sprawl.  Comprehensive planning for the future will help the entire community create, and achieve, a vision for growth. Our last Comprehensive Plan was created 20 years ago and expired 11 years ago. We need a new plan, developed collaboratively and strategically, that can serve as a catalyst for economic and community revitalization while protecting our important agricultural lands and supporting our family-owned farms and businesses.",""]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_nedette_otterbein","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["See the answer to the question above.  An effective comprehensive plan will protect real estate values and quality of life for residents, isolate and mitigate challenges, identify, and capitalize on strengths, and discover opportunities for strategic economic growth.  By engaging our residents, our businesses, and our community leaders, we can create an innovative, well thought out and realistic blueprint for our Township that will address this question. Communication and transparency are vital in creating this type of vision and in addressing the important issues facing Hellam Township.  Planning for business growth is a pillar of comprehensive planning and should include engaging with neighboring communities, regional stakeholders and other economic development organizations to build a collaborative and cohesive region that strengthens all of our communities. "]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_nedette_otterbein","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Within the last several years, Hellam Township has experienced significant flood damage as a result of heavy rain and runoff. In 2021, this damage still exists and yet the root causes have not been addressed. Our residents affected by flooding deserve an opportunity to participate and help develop potential solutions. ","","In additional, Hellam Township needs to incorporate long range planning for the management of budgeted infrastructure priorities including road work, support for our volunteer fire departments, Police and EMS.  Currently, Hellam township needs to be more proactive and less reactionary in dealing with infrastructure issues.  This can be accomplished by using a 5 year, 10 year and 20 year planning process rather than by budgeting on a year by year basis.  "]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_nedette_otterbein","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_nedette_otterbein","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_nedette_otterbein","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_phyllis_m._bowers","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Dedicated to helping our community be the best possible "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_phyllis_m._bowers","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Future growth and sustainability "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_phyllis_m._bowers","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Encouraging new small business endeavors "]},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_phyllis_m._bowers","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_phyllis_m._bowers","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_phyllis_m._bowers","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"jacobus_council_phyllis_m._bowers","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"fairview_township_supervisor_jane_m._vivier","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My background in management and accounting spanning both the public and private sector, coupled with my work ethic make me the best candidate for office. Throughout my nearly 17-year accounting career, I've worked with businesses on a variety of tax and financial issues that have given me considerable insight into pro-growth public policies. And my work with both businesses and individuals from various backgrounds have helped me listen to and learn from many perspectives about what it takes for a township to thrive."]},{"candidateCode":"fairview_township_supervisor_jane_m._vivier","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Dealing with the fallout from COVID-19 remains the top priority for Fairview Township. The Township supervisor position is best suited to help Fairview deal with the economic fallout from COVID-19. I'm hoping to work to identify and secure economic development grants and incentives that can help support existing struggling businesses and attract new ones that will provide good family sustaining jobs to Fairview."]},{"candidateCode":"fairview_township_supervisor_jane_m._vivier","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I'll work with the Board of Supervisors to enhance Fairview's image as an ideal place for businesses to operate, as well as work to develop favorable tax and zoning incentives for companies looking to operate in the Township. "]},{"candidateCode":"fairview_township_supervisor_jane_m._vivier","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["There are a number of existing infrastructure needs throughout Fairview. I'll work with the Board and PennDOT to ensure that state-managed projects are fully funded and on schedule, as well as identify and secure funding and contractors who pay prevailing wage for critical infrastructure needs. "]},{"candidateCode":"fairview_township_supervisor_jane_m._vivier","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. Tough sentencing for nonviolent drug offenses involving marijuana have cost many hard-working individuals the opportunity to secure gainful employment and improve their lives. With  medical marijuana already the law of the land, and more than 70 percent of Pennsylvanians in support of full legalization, it's time that sentencing conventions reflected the will of the people."]},{"candidateCode":"fairview_township_supervisor_jane_m._vivier","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. I'd work with the York County PHRC Advisory Council and the state PHRC to educate township residents about what legal protections and recourse currently exist and work with the Board to advocate for County Commision-level and State-level protections. I'd also work to tailor business development outreach to good corporate actors in this regard."]},{"candidateCode":"fairview_township_supervisor_jane_m._vivier","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. We can collectively beat COVID-19 outbreaks through a combination of vaccination, masking, and distancing. As long as our community includes those unable to be vaccinated, we have a responsibility as public servants to protect those vulnerable populations."]},{"candidateCode":"penn_township_commissioner_2_year_term_justin_j._heiland","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have lived in Penn Township for my entire life and know first hand what matters in our community. I have been a Penn Township Commissioner for 4 years (2 as Health and Sanitation Commissioner and 2 as President of the Commission) and before that I served on the Planning Committee. Over the years, I have come to understand all the unique issues to the Township and its residents, but am always ready to learn and listen as new residents and new issues are brought before the board."]},{"candidateCode":"penn_township_commissioner_2_year_term_justin_j._heiland","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["As always, there are currently many important issues facing Penn Township. Taxes/budget, Sewer Projects, Fire Commission, etc. Over my last 4 years as a Commissioner, I've found that the best way to address the issue is by discussing them at public meetings with the board. The more residents who come out and make their voices heard, the better we are aware of local problems and the best ways to resolve them."]},{"candidateCode":"penn_township_commissioner_2_year_term_justin_j._heiland","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will support growth as I have these past 4 years, by helping to pass a budget that provides all the services required to make Penn Township a quality place to live and conduct business."]},{"candidateCode":"penn_township_commissioner_2_year_term_justin_j._heiland","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The Board of Commissioner recently updated our ordinance to require better/more paving when street cuts are made. We also make sure to pass budgets that have the funds set aside for bridge replacements and any other critical infrastructure."]},{"candidateCode":"penn_township_commissioner_2_year_term_justin_j._heiland","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do not believe this is a policy for Municipal level officials. I would look to the state's laws for guidance."]},{"candidateCode":"penn_township_commissioner_2_year_term_justin_j._heiland","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In my 4 years as a Commissioner, we did have an individual attempt to get the board to back the creation of a Diversity Alliance, but the Board believes that this is best left to the County level. Many of the protections they were suggesting were out of the scope of the Municipal government."]},{"candidateCode":"penn_township_commissioner_2_year_term_justin_j._heiland","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Through the Covid pandemic, my main concern has been the health and safety of our residents and employees. That being said, I would follow guidance from the state when it comes to the Township employees. It's up to businesses and residents to decide on how they will comply."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_council_donald_bair","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Because I'll do what's right for Wrightsville."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_council_donald_bair","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Long overdue infrastructure updates. Focusing on grant funding, as opposed to new taxes  from citizens and fees from the ratepayer. This way we avoid an additional expense to our citizens."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_council_donald_bair","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Our administration made it possible for taverns and restaurants to remain open during the COVID epidemic by enacting legislative measures designed to keep businesses open and workers employed. Our aforementioned measures were adopted, later, by neighboring municipalities. The historic importance of Wrightsville is an untapped resource which will make Wrightsville a destination for serious Civil War historians. I have spearheaded a signage initiative with the Civil War Trails organization which will surely be a draw for cyclists, bird watchers, and hikers alike."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_council_donald_bair","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our water supply lines are in critical need of replacement. In addition, our roads and parks are long overdue for repaving and upgrades. During my first four years in office, our council has planned, found funding and implemented an aggressive program to attack these problems."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_council_donald_bair","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_council_donald_bair","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["These decisions are made at a State/Federal level."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_council_donald_bair","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["No. "]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_devin_winand","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Growing up and working on the Susquehanna River and its surrounding areas has taught me to appreciate where we live.  I see so much potential in Hellam Township and its many features and assets.  Hellam is rich with nature, history, community, agriculture and local businesses, all of which can be leveraged to continue Hellam as we know it and hopefully add to its future as a community.    "]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_devin_winand","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["One of the biggest issues Hellam Township is facing with so many others is stormwater.  We are seeing more large rain events that are causing significant damage to both township and private property as well as negatively impacting our streams and rivers.  I will help the township and residents find both government and non-profit programs that can help us address stormwater and offset some of the costs involved.  The damage caused by stormwater is costly to both the environment and our bottom line.   "]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_devin_winand","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I believe Hellam Township is perfectly positioned to capitalize on our rural character.  We have both open space and large family farms in the township.  Both can be used to drive eco and agri tourism to the township.  Tourism can help support existing small businesses as well as provide opportunity for new businesses to be started in the area.  We can do this while protecting the character of our township that I and so many others love.   "]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_devin_winand","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["This answer can be tied to the previous two.  Maintaining open space and improving stormwater mitigation can help lower the destructive impact on our roads and bridges.  This same open space is what will draw people from surrounding areas to appreciate and recreate in Hellam.  When people from outside the area visit they will also bring their wallets and support our local small businesses.  We must support existing projects like the Lancaster Concervancy's Hellam Hills Preserve and the Susquehanna National Heritage Area's Mifflin House as these are great examples of what we can do in our township.  "]},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_devin_winand","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_devin_winand","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"hellam_township_supervisor_devin_winand","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"west_manheim_township_supervisor_sylvia_musser","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a lifelong southern Pennsylvania resident who embraces the values of fiscal responsibility, community safety and preserving our natural resources.","With a degree in Business Logistics from Penn State and experience in both industrial and medical office sectors, I have qualifications to ensure the best interests of our community are served. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"west_manheim_township_supervisor_sylvia_musser","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe that uncontrolled growth is a big challenge for West Manheim Township. Enforcing existing sewer, storm water, and street standard ordinances and requiring developers to include green/outdoor space is vital for the creation of neighborhoods where people love to live. The EPA and PA DER are also a resource for guidance."]},{"candidateCode":"west_manheim_township_supervisor_sylvia_musser","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I would work with the rest of the board of supervisors to encourage sustainable business growth and  new business start-ups  that add to our tax base and to our quality of life. "]},{"candidateCode":"west_manheim_township_supervisor_sylvia_musser","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["We need to expand use of our sewer system.","More existing homes need to be connected to our sewer system. As time goes on, septic tanks will fail and those homes will need to connect. Newly constructed homes should be required to connect to the sewer system where available.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"west_manheim_township_supervisor_sylvia_musser","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would support the decriminalization of marijuana. Decriminalization is not same, of course, as legalization. Possession and use of marijuana could be punished with a civil penalty, such as a fine. I do not think that a person's chances at future employment should be potentially ruined due to possession of marijuana. Drug use is a health issue."]},{"candidateCode":"west_manheim_township_supervisor_sylvia_musser","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes, of course! As a township supervisor, I would encourage the residents of the township to be a welcoming and inclusive community that embraces diversity. ","It’s regrettable this is a political/legislative issue. I believe everyone has a right to love whom they want and identify as the person they are. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"west_manheim_township_supervisor_sylvia_musser","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, I would support a mask mandate to protect against COVID-19. The CDC recommends that if you are not fully vaccinated and age 2 or older that you should be wearing a mask in indoor public places. ","To protect against the Delta variant, CDC guidelines include wearing a mask in indoor public places if you are in an “area of substantial or high transmission” even if you are fully vaccinated. ","This is a public health issue, not a political one.","","",""]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_harry_s._smith_jr.","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have over 25 years experience working in and with municipal government in central Pennsylvania"]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_harry_s._smith_jr.","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Addressing the continuous increase in costs for services without any real possibility of expanding the Borough's revenue base."]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_harry_s._smith_jr.","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I support business friendly zoning laws. Property owners should not be required to engage in a cumbersome process for minor changes to the use of their own property"]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_harry_s._smith_jr.","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Storm water management is becoming more of an issue with the increase in the frequency of severe weather events. To manage this, the Borough must leverage their funds with all available county, state and federal programs so that the property and safety of the Borough citizenry is ensured.","Additionally, with the cost of everything constantly increasing, the Borough must use the latest in technology to reduce those costs.","Last, the Borough must be proactive in maintaining the existing infrastructure so that little maintenance issues do not become major headaches in the future."]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_harry_s._smith_jr.","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The Borough does not control any agency responsible for enforcing such regulations, so any measures involving this matter would be moot."]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_harry_s._smith_jr.","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Current Borough policies do not support discrimination in any form and I agree with those policies."]},{"candidateCode":"hallam_council_harry_s._smith_jr.","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support following CDC guidance. It really should be about following the science."]},{"candidateCode":"mount_wolf_mayor_louis_t._mccaughey_jr.","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I fell in Love with this area,  here in Mt.Wolf Pa and most of the people and would llike to try to make things better for the people of ","Mt.Wolf  and try to get the main park fix upa little better and get those who break the LAW to face what they doing and make the main park save for all to enjoy and would like to learn from.our GOVERNOR  with talks with him.,"]},{"candidateCode":"mount_wolf_mayor_louis_t._mccaughey_jr.","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Schools, Road and Street repairs done the right way and try to ease the taxes here in Mt Wolf  and to make sure that all rules,  regulations and  Laws are up-to-date  and are uphold for all of our people and children were we all feel safe and sound. "]},{"candidateCode":"mount_wolf_mayor_louis_t._mccaughey_jr.","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["This will be one of the areas  wete i would like to talk to our GOVERNOR and learn from him"]},{"candidateCode":"mount_wolf_mayor_louis_t._mccaughey_jr.","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The same as above,  I amjust learning I"]},{"candidateCode":"mount_wolf_mayor_louis_t._mccaughey_jr.","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am not for Marijuana  but to makeit just a high fine and cost for a nickel  bag or less but jail time if you are behind the wheel of any car or truck "]},{"candidateCode":"mount_wolf_mayor_louis_t._mccaughey_jr.","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I am sorry  as i have no ideas on this matter right nowand would like to talk with our Governor on this matter"]},{"candidateCode":"mount_wolf_mayor_louis_t._mccaughey_jr.","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Forgive me but i believe that this is getting out of hand and just making the American People afraid  , find ways toget our child or children to be able to get shots and for everyone else to get a back up shot. People are going to get sick no matter what and our people die all the time for many reasons, it's time to get back to Country be safe.  Wecan put a stop to this by just getting everyone and everybody to get their shot and to take great care of ourself and that of our Families  and  our Great Country,  The Good Old  U. S. A"]},{"candidateCode":"hanover_council_isaac_riston","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My early experiences as an Eagle Scout and the first Junior Council Person for Millcreek Township have allowed me to understand the role and ability of local government through sitting on multiple different boards. My recent experiences working on the Selinsgrove Comprehensive Plan and as a Fellow for the PA House of Representatives while studying for my degree in Business Administration and Public Policy at Susquehanna University deepened this understanding. These experiences involved real-world results such as data collection, policy research, and drafting my own legislation. These positions and tasks provided the most well-rounded experiences a young person can acquire going into politics. The time I spent homeless while growing up also taught me the direct impact the government can have on improving people’s lives. This revelation and what taxpayers did for my family are things I will never forget. All this has made me a data-driven, problem-solving, and people-focused candidate."]},{"candidateCode":"hanover_council_isaac_riston","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["During my campaign I have been knocking door to door in order to identify the problems constituents have and these issues have been the most common: infrastructure, Guthrie Memorial Library, and the Hanover Comprehensive Plan. Infrastructure issues include train tracks, sidewalks, and roads not being well-maintained, sparse or difficult parking on certain streets, streets flooding during heavy rain, and power outages across Hanover Borough (to name a few). Guthrie Memorial Library’s funding was put into question by the borough during the pandemic; fortunately, funding was not reduced the library received great support from the community in response to this. The library must stay fully funded to keep providing its services to the community. The Hanover Comprehensive Plan from 2015 has items of high priority that have not yet been addressed by the Borough. These will be my priority during my first year as I continue to outline new plans for problems not addressed in the Comp plan."]},{"candidateCode":"hanover_council_isaac_riston","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Hanover Borough can cultivate business growth by creating a community that acknowledges the humanity in small local businesses and allowing business growth throughout the borough rather than businesses being concentrated in Hanover square. Business growth should not just be seen as getting new organizations to open, but also ensuring the ones that are here are being well serviced. The best ways local government can help move toward economic growth are to promote local businesses and all those who work, service, and operate them, as well as creating connections between businesses and younger Hanoverians to create lasting foundations for businesses in the area. Business growth should also match with the wants of the people; as I speak to people, I’ve found that many are wondering what is going to happen to the local movie theater. A project with that property would be a great place to see business growth in Hanover and I would love to be able to help that project along if elected."]},{"candidateCode":"hanover_council_isaac_riston","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["There are a lot of physical infrastructure opportunities in Hanover Borough. What the Hanover Borough Council needs to do is start fixing issues that affect citizens every day. Providing safe and effective infrastructure is the most basic activity our local government is responsible for, and I imagine many people in Hanover can see the \"band-aids\" put on years of neglect, if anything has been done at all, rather than correctly fixing the problems. A priority of mine is to make all of Hanover Borough walkable. As I have walked throughout the borough these last few months it has become evident that work needs to be done to ensure all residents are able to freely walk throughout Hanover. Additionally, the congestion in Hanover is a detriment to local residencies and businesses alike, and will take time to properly address. I look forward to working with local organizations that have been working towards correcting these infrastructure issues."]},{"candidateCode":"hanover_council_isaac_riston","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am in favor of full legalization of marijuana at the state level and decriminalization at the local level. Current laws target marginalized and impoverished communities and continue to ruin the lives of people who have been charged for marijuana-related crimes. Righting the wrongs by following the efforts of other local PA governments, after so many years, is the least Hanover Borough can do. The borough should also look into helping citizens convicted of nonviolent possession get their records expunged, since these convictions have held these people back. In addition, the borough needs to reorient itself to address harmful drug use, such as opioids, which continue to destroy families and communities similar to Hanover. Hanover can work with local and county partners to develop these systems and create a more welcoming community. This will also free up time for police to focus on violent crimes and serious issues with drugs (such as opioids) that are more harmful to the community."]},{"candidateCode":"hanover_council_isaac_riston","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Absolutely. Hanover Borough should do what it can to protect LGBTQ+ Hanoverians from discrimination and persecution. As an ally I also plan on listening to local, county, and state partners to create legislation that better protects and promotes LGBTQ+ members in our community. A first step is to make sure all anti-discrimination language includes gender identity or expression in addition to sexual orientation. Hanover Borough supporting diversity should be something easy for the council to do following the outpouring of support shown at Hanover Pride this summer that featured local politicians speaking including Hanover Mayor SueAnn Whitman. We have a vibrant, diverse, multicultural, multiracial, society here in America. We should never allow the legal ability to discriminate against someone based on identity."]},{"candidateCode":"hanover_council_isaac_riston","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, only if cases and deaths get as bad as they were last year, then mask mandates are unfortunately something we have to consider. Ultimately if we have the resources to contract trace, make testing accessible, and ensure everyone has access to the free vaccine then the local community shouldn’t have to worry about mask mandates going into effect. With deaths now above the 1918 \"Spanish Flu\" it is inconceivable that we wouldn't even consider having the same basic standards they had then. In addition, we need to be consistent and prepare for the future, rather than waiting for emergency meetings or orders. Using data we have so far, we know getting vaccinated and up-to-date ventilation systems help protect lives. Hanover Borough Council should focus on encouraging people to get vaccinated and helping local businesses improve their ventilation systems. With a plan in place for the future, Hanover Borough will be people-focused when it comes to pandemics rather than fear-focused."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_tayne-michelle_slenker","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Being a lifetime resident  of Wrightsville gives me the motivation to make this community a more desirable place to call home or to stop by for a visit."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_tayne-michelle_slenker","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Fiscal Responsibility. I would be more conservative with the budget and look for means to raise money. Some example’s given Fundraisers , Carnivals and Circuses  etc."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_tayne-michelle_slenker","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I wanna  focus on bringing small business to this community , as well as strengthening and supporting those businesses presently existing."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_tayne-michelle_slenker","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["To continue to work on existing plans and projects."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_tayne-michelle_slenker","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would definitely support this. I feel there are many benefits of medical marijuana. This would definitely free up our police and other agencies to concentrate on other important issues."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_tayne-michelle_slenker","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes I would definitely support the LGBTQ community working towards eliminating discrimination."]},{"candidateCode":"wrightsville_mayor_tayne-michelle_slenker","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["No I would not support a mandate, but I would definitely encourage wearing masks as an option. We still are a Country based on Freedoms and Liberties."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["The children and teachers are the top priority, anti-bullying programs where our children can learn and grow to stop the current bullying program, updated safety programs for all schools in the event of an incident, tax reform- we don’t need higher taxes, we need better spending. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["Tax increases, less supplies than ever, teacher cuts. All of this can be solved with smarter spending and applying for more grants. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["No one should be mandated to take a vaccine. Parents and staff should have the right to do what’s best for them and their families regarding masks and schooling. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["CRT has been banned in several states and should not be a part of the AASD curriculum. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am a hard working single mom who just wants the best for the children and the district to provide the best possible future for our families. Please vote for Amy Fitsko for Ambridge Area School District, it’s time for a change. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["While I believe our district has great potential, I also believe that we need to focus on improvements to fiduciary responsibility, equilibrium and improvement of learning/scoring, attendance, reputation/value to our community."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["I believe that the Ambridge Area School district has great potential, but I believe that we have financial and learning/scoring obstacles that need to be addressed. We have much work to do in this regard. As we move forward, we must ensure that we return to an upward trajectory in these areas.","","I believe that a vision and plan need to be created, with tangible benchmarks to measure stated goals. Without a stated plan for correction/resurgence, I believe the district will continue to struggle. While I am only one vote, I believe that I will continue to be a strong proponent of and contributor to this end."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I contracted Covid-19 while double masking in February. My personal belief is that it should be parental choice, as the current AASD board voted for at the beginning of the year. I believe that the district is bound to follow the mandate as written and that anyone who disagrees should share their opinions with their state representatives. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["I am currently exploring CRT. I think it is important to support an integrated learning experience and environment for all students. I will not support division, suppression or inequity in learning. I will consider this and other issues with sound judgement and equity as they are presented. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I will be a strong voice for improvement in the areas I’ve stated. My hope is that those that support me will do so because they have faith in my judgement and resolve to apply my influence on moving AASD back to an upward trajectory in learning, financial sustainability, safety and equilibrium for our students, the district and our community."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["The district strategic plan should drive the priorities of the school board.  The Ambridge Area Board of Directors has hired a Superintendent to be our educational and systematic leader.  My goal is to support the administration and staff while providing the accountability the community wants. As a Board member, my biggest goal is to evaluate and understand why our class sizes  K, 1, 2 are so high and how to adjust this. However, before you can make changes, we need to understand more collectively and data-driven to our community expectations.  We need to have more active collaboration from our community to drive our priorities from the school and the community.   "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest challenges our district faces currently are the pandemic and the systemic changes due to the pandemic.  We are talking more about mandates and what is the law and what is not law.  We need our government to support local education agencies and place wording so that it does not have so many different interpretations.  We need to have our government either do the job or leave at the local decision.  We should be focusing on the student learners or reviewing and asking for educational reform.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["At this point, our Governor has taken away the right for the board of directors to decide on mask mandates for students and staff.  Our current board voted 9 – 0 in favor of parent choice at the beginning of the year.  Therefore, my vote when I was permitted was for parent choice.  As for vaccines for staff, I do not believe I am qualified to decide for someone's medical needs.  Therefore, if I were asked to vote, it would be a teacher/staff choice.  Decisions like masking and vaccines for schools should be state-wide. If the department of health has proof that there is a clear reason for something, I encourage them to use their authority to make the judgment.  However, suppose they do not mandate something as health officials. In that case, I do not feel that my degrees in education make me qualified to determine other people's health decisions.   "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical Race Theory is just a theory that the media has used to debate throughout the state.  However, the framework for CRT is not as new as one would think. It has been discussed at the graduate level and in the legal circles since the 1970s.  Sadly, CRT has been confused with what districts focus on supporting and implementing culturally responsive teaching and leadership practices.  Being a culturally responsive school allows teachers and school leaders to affirm and incorporate the diverse cultural references, identities, voices, experiences, and histories of ALL students and their families.  The board of directors' adoption of education curriculum must be aligned to academic standards established and mandated by the State Board of Education.  It is neither required nor credible that Pennsylvania's school district contemplate adopting a curriculum built specifically around CRT.  Misunderstanding about CRT has created unnecessary attacks and undermined public schools' important efforts to promote equity in their programs.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If elected, I will continue to try my best to advocate for all students in the district.  I also want to provide encouragement and support to our administration and especially our teachers.  We have amazing and talented teachers and students who need to be illustrated.  I hope that I have proven that I am dedicated to you and remain to my integrity and morals."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["Top priorities are Quality Education and sound management of the school's finances for the betterment of all the District's residents."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest challenges we face are a deminishing student enrollment ","And a deminishing tax base.","We need afortable housing costs and afortable rents for all residents.","The solution is to provide Quality Education for each student, at the same time deliver a dollar's worth of service for each dollar of taxes.",""]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["Voluntary as per each school district and as per Pennsylvania's Governor's original stance."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["The Theory is not Fact.","We are all God's children, all races.","We must love one another and work together to promote unity, in this free country,  the \"United\" States of America."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If elected by We The People, Rochester Area School District will conduct open meetings for All citizens to speek any concerns they may have to the board freely!"]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priorities for the Ambridge Area School District are:","1. I will help to create a strategic plan and vision to market our district and community by providing a quality, equitable education with increased resources for mental health, social, and emotional needs, where our students feel safe, welcome, and appreciated.","2. If elected, I will serve with fiscal responsibility, integrity, transparency, and equity; while wisely and ethically spending the tax payers money without unreasonable tax increases that the community simply cannot afford.  Wasteful spending is affecting the economic growth of our community and needs to be carefully looked at in the detailed budget.","3. I want to build a 21st century, technology integrated curriculum to fit the unique skills that our students will need for their futures.  Our students need to be prepared with grit and resiliency and the want to be lifelong learners.  We have 12 years to help each of our students find their path and prepare them for their futures and we need to take that very seriously."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["I believe that some of our biggest challenges are below:","1. Our community members pay the highest taxes in Beaver County, which equivilates to one of the highest per pupil costs in the area.  However, we are one of the lowest scoring districts in the area.  Our focus needs to be on fiscally spending the district's money on meeting the needs of all students, while not further burdening our tax payers.","2. We have a serious need in the department of educational technology.  Our students did not have computers until Fall of 2020.  In my educational opinion, our students and teachers have still not received the proper training in order to utilize the best educational technology advances available to meet the 21st century needs of our students.  I have witnessed as a parent the struggle and frustration that our students feel because there is a lack of strategic technology implementation.  There are so many resources available for teachers to use in their classrooms to provide a more fluid education that students can all participate in and learn from.  Our teachers need consistent professional development in this area, because many of them are ready and willing to learn.  In addition, our school has the curriculum to have a successful cyber option for students if needed, however, does not have the resources to support this program in order for our students' needs to be met.  ","3. I believe, although we have recently made several positive strides towards improvement in our special education department, we still have a long way to go to ensure we are meeting the unique needs of all of our students.  Too many of our students have fallen through the cracks over the past decade and deserve so much better. ","4. We seem to be taking a reactive approach to decision making rather than a proactive approach.  I know we are in unprecendented times with a lot of recent issues in our country, however, we must have strategic, well-thought out plans with contingency strategies to proactively handle situations, rather than constantly putting out the next fire.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["There is a current mask mandate in place that we are required to follow.  I fully support the current school board in their decision to follow that mandate, and also respect the fact that they initially voted to allow for parent/student choice before the mandate occurred, as they felt it was in the best interest of the majority of our students.  If the mandate is lifted at some point, I am very open to discussing pros and cons of mask wearing, as I know we have many residents in our district who feel strongly on both sides of the stance.  In the end, everyone is concerned about their children, and as a representative of the school district, I plan to ensure that we do our absolute best to provide and safe environment for all students.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical Race Theory is a curricular framework that has been around for quite some time, but has recently come back into the spotlight in the media.  I believe that there is a lot of misunderstandings that surround the topic of CRT that lead to unneccessary debates.  If elected, curriculum is one of the things I will be carefully reviewing, and I will ensure that we are supporting and implementing culturally responsive teaching and leadership practices.  I will always advocate for providing an equitable education for all of our students.  I will ensure that we are operating, as I believe we are, as a culturaly responsive school that incorporates and welcomes diverse cultural identities, experiences, and histories for all students to learn.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["Many people ask me why I do all that I do in our district and community, and my answer is very simple.  I care so much about our community members, district employees, parents, and children that I cannot sit back and watch.  I have to and want to do everything in my power to make a difference.  I look forward to having the opportunity to do so as a school board member.  I wish all of the candidates the best of luck and look forward to the opportunity to work with each of you moving forward to build bigger and better things for Ambridge Area School District!"]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["Moving the District Forward, is my main priority.  Working with the superintendent the last four years has created many current opportunities for the district.  I am hoping to reconvene the Citizen’s Advisory Committee to review the past recommendations and to make future plans to be good stewards of the facilities and funds the taxpayers entrust us with.  This will include future upgrades to existing aging facilities and some out of the box planning by coordinating with our district superintendent who has consistently led the board to make decisions that have set us up for continued success."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest challenge we have recently seen would have to be Covid 19.  It literally derailed any district forward movement by continually having to focus on and reacting to it and the constantly changing government mandates. Mandates made by the state with no real thought on how they would play out in the “real world”.  I have tried to explain to people my goal and vision is a long term one that began pre Covid and my goals and visions still are looking forward.  ","","Covid 19 protocols, to me, are a short term distraction to long term planning.  And people have to really think about that when choosing their next leaders.  Do you want someone with a short term agendas or long term goals?  Up until Covid the Blackhawk board was meeting all the goals we had set out to accomplish.  And honestly even during Covid we were able to contract and finish safety upgrades to our high school.  So our leadership has shined through this dark blip in our district history."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["This is a hard question to answer, my personal beliefs don’t matter when it comes to my school board decisions.  Personally, I believe in masking as little as possible, except when required.  I would feel comfortable sending my child to school unmasked and I would be fine working in my district unmasked if allowed, however, the state mandates masking right now so what I think does not matter.  We mask.  There are many things in life we have to do, even when we don’t want to.","","As a school board member, I am responsible for not only my son, but approximately 2000 other students as well.  This is why I supported OPTIONAL MASKING in our health and safety plan. I had many parents ask for masking, although more behind the scenes, then those that wanted us to unmask.   This plan was required by the state for us to submit, but that all went out the window when a week into school the governor decided to mandate masking in schools, because he thought more districts would chose masking.","","I can say that local schools that have masked since day 1 of school, like Blackhawk, we have not missed a day of school due to high Covid numbers or quarantines. This is as of 9/28.  I think that says something, because other schools have lost days.  If our goal is to keep kids in school, Blackhawk is doing it!!  And we have been leading since the beginning.","","I do not believe in  or would I support mandatory vaccinations."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical Race Theory has NO ROLE in the classroom or in our district curriculum.  That is my belief and opinion."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I do not believe in creating board majorities. I campaign on my own because I fought against board majorities for years before running myself. My belief is, if you come to the table and do your research on the issues brought before you and your aren’t interested in promoting agendas, you will be an excellent board member helping to make wise decisions on behalf of your constituents. As a board member, you need to understand not everyone will agree with you, but if you listen and are fair and you lead with integrity people will feel confident and support the district initiatives. It is hard sometimes when a divisive decision is before you, one that means you need to look at both sides and make a decision for the good of the whole district and not get distracted by political agendas, I think I have shown I can do that and do it well. I hope the residents of Blackhawk elect me for 4 more years, as I have shown that I can lead through adversity. Thank you, Melissa"]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priority for the district is to continue in the direction they are going. Continue to provide and utilize technology. Continue to offer college credit courses to high school students. To maintain community relationships with outside organizations that benefit our kids. "]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["One of the biggest challenges facing the district is an aging population in fixed incomes.  A school district needs tax dollars to continue to grow and thrive. Additional tax bills may be harder for those residents to make. While tax increases may be inevitable, the burden can be lifted through grant money. I can help source and write those grants. "]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I am pro mask. I work in schools and I see kids in their masks. The vast majority of students don't mind them especially if it helps them maintain face to face learning. I think caution and safety are a small price to pay for face to face instruction. As for mandatory vaccination for staff, I think that would have to be evaluated per district, taking in account the school population as well as positive covid case counts for the district and the area."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["I think that the curriculum taught in schools should be factual and consist of several points of view so that no groups of people are left out. Children need to know how different things effect different people."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am dedicated to do what is best for our students, our school and our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["I want to see the district work toward a more responsible financial policy. We need to spend the citizen’s tax dollars in a way that provides a sound educational experience for the children of the district.  By spending smarter and more effectively, I’d hope to see test scores increase.  Our district ranks low both within the state and county and I want to see them increase."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["I feel the biggest challenge we face is financial.  Our budget continues to grow every year, but the cuts being made appear to be questionable.  An increasing portion of our budget has been going to charter school fees.  More families have chosen charters over Ambridge and it needs to be explored why.  If answers can be given, the district may be able to win some family's favor back and increase enrollment."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I feel that both masking and vaccines are a personal choice.  These decisions should be left to the parents and staff.  It is quite a hot topic and decisions should not be entered into lightly.  The parents need to make decisions for their own kids.  The staff member should make a decision with their doctor as to what is best for them."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["My feeling on CRT is that it is politically driven to cause division.  I support an environment where all students can learn about all history, no matter what story it tells.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I'm Ambridge born and raised.  I care about this community, the kids and the school.  I want my 3 kids to grow up in a community that cares for one another and where a great education is available to all families in the district."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["Maximize the face to face instruction as we know face to face instruction provides the best education for the students.","Continue to improve the financial condition of the school district while maintaining its high educational standards.","Continue to implement the long range plan for the districts buildings and search for creative ways to fund those building needs while eliminating or minimizing the need for tax increases as much as possible."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["Working through the constantly changing and evolving Covid-19 issues.","Protecting our students from indoctrination programs currently being pushed and any others like them in the future.","Finding ways and financial means to renovate our aging buildings while eliminating or minimizing the impact on our tax payers.","Continuing to reduce our debt in whatever ways we can."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["Personally, I am not an advocate of mandatory masking.  My position is based upon my personal work experiences of thousands of hours with the use of respiratory protection. ","","Personally, I am against mandatory vaccination.  Situations such as vaccinations should be a personal decision never a government requirement."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["I am completely against socialistic/marxist indoctrination of any kind in our schools.  Critical Theory, Critical Race Theory and the 1619 Project, just being the most recent programs being pushed.  Many were ONLY MEANT to be taught in colleges to legal students in order to prepare them for arguments against such biases. They were never intended to be taught as a viable theory in K-12, so most of these programs are inappropriate at best, but none of this should be taught in our schools. Teaching such theories elevates these ideologies and false premises and gives them undeserved legitimacy they should never be given."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I follow a code of ethics in everything I do.  I try my best to act with honor, character, integrity and honesty.  I try to be a good steward in everything I do and I take this same approach with tax payer's funds when making decisions for our district.  I truly believe that we should all give back and try to take care of our community, so I take this position very seriously.  While I will not promise not to raise taxes when necessary, I will promise I will NEVER agree to automatic tax increases.  I further promise to continue to do my best to come up with wise solutions to all of our problems and issues and I promise to do whatever I can to mitigate the need for raising taxes."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priorities are to 1.) learn and understand the current challenges, priorities, and constraints the school district has 2.) disseminate information. ","","Having a good understanding how the school district operates would allow for constructive input to build upon and improve what is already an excellent, sought-after school system.    ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["Right now, political divisiveness appears to be the biggest challenge facing all levels of government, including our school district. My small part in solving this problem is by engaging in meaningful, in-person discussions to genuinely understand differing perspectives and foster civility. I do not participate in personal social media networks which spur fruitless personal attacks and debates."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["The Wolf administration reversed its stance on state-wide masking mandates for schools which sparked much divisiveness within our community.  Masking decisions for students and staff should be left to the jurisdiction of the local school board with a default stance for personal freedom and choice for both masking and vaccines.","","Parents and staff should seek counsel and follow the advice of trusted, medical doctors and pediatricians when making masking and vaccine decisions for themselves and their families.  Likewise, they should understand contact tracing and quarantine implications of their decisions.",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["While standing outside of the polling stations during the May primary elections, Critical Race Theory was the most commonly discussed topic.  It was unanimously opposed by the community members that I spoke to.  I believe Critical Race Theory perpetuates a focus on racial groups and racial division instead of individual merit.  For both reasons, Critical Race Theory should not shape classroom curriculum.  "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["My favorite book is “Team of Rivals”.  I’m interested in learning from and working with people that have perspectives differing from my own.  "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top three priorities are as follows:","","1) Partner with the current board and the community to solve the complex and everchanging challenges associated with Covid-19 mitigation.  The goal is to keep students in face-to-face education and in person while at the same time avoiding any loss of freedoms to choose what works best for students and their families. ","","2) Improve transparency of school director activities and seek ongoing input from students, parents, teachers, and tax payers in the community.","","3) Focus intently on ways to assess and improve the health and wellness of our students.  In particular, I believe there is huge need to focus on their emotional wellbeing and assist them in better navigating the challenges they will face in school and beyond.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["*Please see the associated “top priorities” listed above. The biggest challenges facing our district include:","","1) Solving the complex and everchanging Covid-19 mitigation strategies.  ","","2) Improving the school’s ability to assess and improve students’ health and wellness.","","3) Ensure that all students receive excellent face-to-face and in person education.","","To solve these challenges, I plan to work closely with the current board and community members to clearly define the problem, then measure it, analyze it, and improve it.  We will need to set short-term and long-term goals which will be measured by carefully chosen metrics. Any improvement that has been initiated will have a control mechanism so that improvements are not lost.",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["Mandatory masking is unconstitutional and is a decision that is best left up to parents.  I want to emphasize that the current mandate is not simply about a mask, it’s about giving up parental rights to that of the state and school district.  I am not \"anti-mask,\" instead I advocate for the right of students and teachers to choose what works best for them.  The unfortunate reality is that teachers are put in the challenging position to \"mask police\" instead of focusing on their expertise in teaching. I love our teachers at Riverside and I advocate for their rights to choose what works best for them. ","","In regards to mandated COVID-19 vaccinations, I believe that we are still in the experimental phase and the vaccine should remain optional. The short term and long-term effects of the vaccine are not fully understood.  The VAERS analysis indicates a significant number of adverse reactions, life threatening events, permanent disabilities, and death. The benefits and risks should be taking under consideration for everyone and the decision is unique to individual circumstances.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical race theory has no place in our classrooms. It teaches our children that the most important aspect about them is their skin color and that racism exists, either consciously or unconsciously, in every interaction. I have concerns about this approach because it does not take into account the unique qualities that we have as individuals. Also, this type of education has anti-American qualities, is rooted in socialism, and has the potential to foster more racial division.  Moving forward, I would love to see more focus on a patriotic education that is focused on the vision that our founding fathers had for our great nation.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["•        I’ll respectfully listen to all views ","","•        I’ll do whatever it takes to solve a complex problem","","•        I won’t give up easy ","","•        I’m not afraid to speak truth, even if I stand alone","","",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priority is keeping the kids in school for in-person learning. I’d like to avoid any closures or quarantines due to Covid. I’d also like to ensure there is a virtual streaming option for those who are quarantined. ","I’d like to see a portion of the ESSER funds received by the state be put towards addressing the impact of this global pandemic on the students’ mental health. ","I would also like part in decision making regarding the school’s budget in the coming years. "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest thing on our district’s plate currently is the masking order from the state. I’d like to ensure that we comply with this order and keep the kids, teachers, and administration healthy. "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I think vaccines should remain optional for all students. I myself will be vaccinating my kids, but I understand the hesitancy. Masking, however, should be enforced for everyone except those with a valid medical exemption. The more people in a room wearing a mask, the more effective they are. Think of it as the same concept as coughing into your elbow, or covering your nose when you sneeze. It is a literal barrier blocking droplets that potentially contain the Covid 19 virus from spreading to other people. I think masks should be mandatory until a vaccine is available to all students. "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["This is an extremely divisive topic and I don’t think it should be. I think that learning the truth about history allows us to not repeat the mistakes made in some cases.  "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If elected, I will always have what’s best for the kids in mind with any decision I would make on the board. I’d like to avoid tax increases. And finally, I’d like the kids and staff at the schools to remain healthy and thriving, physically and mentally. "]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_barb_brown","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["The top priority now is getting through what is left of the pandemic. We also must continue to think beyond Covid -19 so that we are ready to continue to make progress in all areas of the curriculum. Our plan must be forward thinking and malleable as the needs of students that are graduating will continue to change considerably in the next several decades. As the focus on going to college lessens, students will need different skills to be prepared for life post-graduation. The district must remain informed and knowledgeable with regard to the current and future job situation in order to best accomplish this. ","","The next priority is to continue to formalize and work on how to attend to our aging buildings. I have been involved in parts of that planning prior to running for school board and certainly intend to remain involved moving forward.","","I also think that continuing education for our staff is imperative. Lifelong learning is how we describe the process to our students. We must all model that and keep abreast of new ideas, technology practices, and instructional practices to the rating of our district high. This in turn will help keep property values stable or on the rise.","","Keeping our taxes reasonable is also always on my mind. I, like many other residents, am retired and would like to remain in this district.  Looking for ways to expand our tax base could help keep property taxes from escalating. I believe this can be achieved by working with our local municipalities to help bring additional business opportunities to the area.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_barb_brown","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The ever-changing Covid-19 recommendations and rules are very hard to follow. That in itself could be a full-time job. I think it will make for many sleepless nights and many meetings to best guide the district forward.","","I believe we should take a hard look at building safety, especially at the Intermediate School as they do not have a captured entrance. Some of the latest funding could be allocated to solve that problem.","","Finalizing the plan for the future of our aging buildings in a cost-effective manner will definitely be a challenge. That will require some out of the box thinking to rectify but the beginnings of that plan are off to a good start.","","Being always mindful of the budget and always looking for ways to reduce spending without affecting the quality of the education provided to our students. Many of those ideas are included as responses to other questions on this form.",""]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_barb_brown","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["The most important aspect of school is the ability to attend 5 days a week. Currently, while vaccine choice for those under 12 is still unavailable, the only way to keep kids under 12 in school 5 days a week is to keep them healthy and off the quarantine list. Due to the current quarantine protocols and rising Covid rates, masking seems to be the only way that is possible. However, I do think that for students 12 and older, where the vaccine is available, there should be some flexibility with regard to masking. As a vaccine becomes available to the 5-11 year old population of students I would expect there to also be less need for masking. Teachers should be masking at a level that would keep them safe and in class. That may depend on either local rates of Covid and/or vaccination status.","","As far as mandated Covid-19 vaccines for staff I believe each person has the right to make that choice for themselves. However, those choices come with great responsibility. If a staff member decides not to avail themselves of the available vaccine, for whatever reason, I believe that if we are in the high level of transmission, or students that are under 12 have no option to vaccinate, unvaccinated staff members should mask.",""]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_barb_brown","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical Race Theory should not be part of the K-12 curriculum. However, I firmly believe in including all students as an active part of your student body. I believe that students learn by example and should be learning about empathy, kindness, and compassion. Every student should feel like they belong in the Blackhawk School District. I know I focused on those very qualities in my classrooms, with my students, and have found that students live up or down to your expectations. My expectations for my students and myself were always set high."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_barb_brown","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am dedicated and love the Blackhawk School District. I firmly believe this district had a large influence on my personal children and helped to make them successful adults. I want the same for all the children that attend school in the district. I think we should always strive to do better. If we set the bar high we will maintain or exceed the wonderful educational excellence that is the Blackhawk School District."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_chris_chill","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["I look forward to working with our current school board members, teachers, and administration to help in making the important, pivotal decisions for our students in order to give them the greatest opportunity to succeed in their academics, extracurricular activities, and to prepare them for their future. ","In addition, I want to assist the current board with making the right financial decisions to prevent significant tax increases, stay on budget, and be prepared for growth.","Lastly, I would like to work with our current board to make improvements to our campus and hire the most qualified staff for our students."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_chris_chill","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["I believe that the Covid-19 pandemic is currently the biggest challenge we are facing. I would want to make sure the kids can remain in the classroom, rather than virtual learning. ","Another challenge is that Riverside does not have a large corporate tax base, so the board is faced with making smart fiscal decisions that will continue the high level of education that we are providing to our students but recognizing we need to keep our local property taxes down. "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_chris_chill","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["This has been one of the most divisive issues at our school and in our country. I believe that no one knows what is best for their kids more than their parents, however, when Governor Wolf issued the mandate I believe the current school board did what it had to do to comply in order to protect the school and its students. ","As far as vaccines are concerned, I believe that is a choice for the individual.  I do believe that people should do their due diligence and gather information from validated and reputable research as well as consulting with their physician or medical professional."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_chris_chill","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["I believe that critical race theory has no place in our classrooms.  I am a proud American and believe that we live in the greatest country in the world.  I think our children should be taught about how this country was founded and the amazing minds that built it. I feel that the critical race theory would actually create more division than unity, and is primarily focused on race rather than the person as a whole."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_chris_chill","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["My family and I are driven by our faith and very active in our church, Northway Christian Community.  My wife and I both come from very large families and enjoy doing life together.  I enjoy hunting, fishing, golfing and spending time outdoors.  Most of all I love spending time with my wife and children.   "]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["My top priorities are impressing upon council why our Police Department needs to be fully staffed. Making sure taxes are kept low and steady and we have not raised taxes while I've been mayor.  And ensuring that ordinances do not infringe on private property rights or become too intrusive."]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":["As of now our biggest challenge is coming from outside vendors like Valley Waste who is having staffing issues leaving piles of garbage on the curb for days. We are working with our solicitor to make sure they are honoring their service contract.  Our other issues include fracking issues. I firmly believe people who have managed to hold onto large parcels of land have a right to use the oil and gas that is under their farm land to their financial benefit."]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["To be honest I don't judge myself against the other candidate.  I'm me!  I wear my heart on my sleeve.  You will know when I'm passionate about issues that I feel are important for individual liberties and protecting those individual liberties is a priority for me."]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I actually eally care about what happens in my borough, as I've said earlier I've attended YEARS of council meetings so I understand the history of many issues in our Borough.  I tend to internalize issues and work hard to find solutions.  I don't like leaving loose end or things only vaguely remedied."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["My top priorities are to bring new ideas to the borough to spread community values and make Big Beaver a place that young people want to bring their families to grow."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["I have fresh ideas and a marketing background that can help to bring a brighter future to the community."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["My family is deeply rooted in Big Beaver Borough and we intend to raise our children here as I was raised here."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["As mayor, I want to put a fresh face of hope on our town. I don’t think the town needs another ‘get off my lawn’ old white man, in the mayor’s office. As a business owner in Ambridge, I have seen some hard times. We had to really hustle and be creative. I think that’s what Ambridge needs, creativity and determination. We have some positive momentum, and it needs to be fed and, with the right energy, we could definitely see more positive things continue to happen in the years to come. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":["I think we have two major issues that need to be worked on, both equally important. One is that we need to bridge the ‘trust gap’ between the police department and the community. Some really good steps have been taken toward accomplishing this, but we still need to work on it. The officers need outlets to engage with youth and charitable organizations. The other issue that needs addressed is, of course, our drug epidemic, which goes hand in hand with the mental health epidemic.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["I view myself as a very socially liberal person. I believe in equality. I pride myself in being a very caring person, without being naive. I have earned the trust of many of the pillars of the Ambridge community. I am approachable for young and old alike. I am always working on my conflict resolution skills, and I really want to bring ‘being neighborly’ back!"]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I am a widowed mother of two children. I understand the struggles of the people in our community. I talk to so many of my fellow citizens every day, in my bakery and walking down the street. I believe that there is something beautiful on every single block of this amazing town. There are genuinely wonderful folks in every corner of this diverse, inspiring melting pot of a community that we have the supreme privilege to be a part of. I wouldn’t live anywhere else. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["As the only elected executive of the borough, the mayor is charged with three primary responsibilities - preserving order, enforcing ordinances and regulations and removing nuisances among some other lesser duties.  In the Army, if we were not on a mission we were training for a mission.  If it worked for the Army it can certainly work for Ambridge. ","","The mayor is traditionally seen as overseeing the police, but not to be a policeman.  In order  to ensure the police are doing the best job they can with the limited resources given them they need to be constantly trained, but also well equipped.  Kudos to our police officers.  ","","Calls to the police and the police's responses are one indicator of what the resident's concerns are and a picture of our collective problems.  Better community communications and police relations is a start, but the systematic documentation of calls, the responses, and any consequent arrests is part of tracking and tackling crime.  If the residents know their concerns and the calls they make are being addressed then they will have more trust and patience in the police force as the police work to tackle the issues.  I want to see all of this quantified so that our police systematically identify the problems, and focus our limited resources on nuisances and problem areas.  ","","Among other duties, the borough manager is the chief code enforcement officer as well as the operations manger.  It's the mayor's duty to see that code enforcement is operating properly, and equitably, for all building owners, residential as well as commercial, and industrial also.  Too many of our residential buildings have been divided up into small apartments maximizing the investor's return on investment.  But this is often at the expense of quality of life for the residents of the neighborhood with resultant scarcity of parking and heavily traveled and congested streets making driving tight and municipal services on them difficult.  With investment in a community comes responsibility to the community.  Investors wanting to make houses into apartments need to adhere to planning commission review to examine their plans as a whole and the impact on the neighborhood.  But planning and zoning need badly updated too in order to provide the tools to check uncontrolled and unmonitored development.  ","","The commercial districts also needs updated ordinances and code review.  New trends in apartment living in retail areas call for updates in our commercial ordinances and zoning to build on the good work already happening there.  Too often the catch phrase \"blighted\" is assumed to mean to eliminate a problem building with county grants by demolition.  What is not looked at is using that same grant money to stabilize our old and historic retail storefronts and preserve them for redevelopment.  It's acceptable and doable by Community Development , it just needs folks willing to see these old retail spaces in a different light.   ","","Finally, our industrial neighbors need to be more involved in our community.  Too often we turn a blind eye to the appearance of our industrial neighbors because we want the jobs and taxes so badly we don't want to somehow offend them.  Industrial neighbors need to be good neighbors too in cleaning up their appearance, planting trees to block views, and to participate in community projects.  These often distant owners are connected via a plant manager we can connect with for their help and express our concerns. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":["The borough has all the ills of other post-industrial towns.  Crime and drugs have to be checked, and they are starting to be checked with a newly reorganized police department, Kudos again.  But we need more cooperation with the state police and other agencies.  Our residents also need speak up more and they need a vehicle to voice their concerns without criticism of fear of retribution.  I will press these other organization to help us as much as they are able.  Our police need all the assistance there is.  But not all issues are so visible.  ","","Our potable water source is carried across a soon-to-be 100 year old bridge.  The county keeps patching the Ambridge bridge, but some believe it is in far worse condition than it appears.  The county has had plans for a bridge a half a mile north for a while.  But how does this old plan address our water supply?  Our water is piped across the bridge.  Why isn't it being addressed as the number one county priority for all the communities dependent on the Ambridge reservoir?  But  instead some are pushing for a recreation bridge for bikes and hikers.  Why isn't the borough demanding something be done to secure our water supply and the water of all the neighboring communities who depend on the Ambridge Water Authority?","","As most residents are aware, we have issues with the lack of a local food supply.  This has been partially addressed with nearby grocery stores, but that in of itself doesn't resolve access to food.  How do those with limited transportation get their food?  How do you shop when there's no public transportation to your neighborhood?  Our store needs to be walkable.  But even then this isn't just a mater of getting a closer store (which will continue to be my priority), but of food security.  We tend to trust the current food supply system which is failing.  Empty shelves tell us that.  The Just-in-time business model is experiencing problems.  I cannot say if it's going to be fixed, but I believe we should look at opportunities to be more self sufficient.  There are communities that are doing some limited urban farming and orchards. We already have some food producers among us most aren't aware of.  It doesn't have to be an either or situation, but perhaps a new focus on leaning on each other as a part of our food security. ","","One other challenge is our access to the water that surrounds us on three sides for recreation. Recreational water access is very doable.  Access to Sewickley Creek, and the Ohio River will take work of dedicated volunteer residents, but is already in early discussions.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["Unlike the other candidates, I wasn't born and raised in Ambridge.  I chose to move to Ambridge.  I chose to build my life here, so I have a lot at stake to make Ambridge a success. ","","I've traveled the country and the world and have seen a lot of community success stories, and a lot of abject failures.  So my view of Ambridge from 30 thousand feet.  It has a richer past than most communities - of such that I believe it deserves recognition as a world heritage site.  But it's more than just our history.  I meet people here every day who are intelligent and of diverse backgrounds, who can help make a difference.  There is no huge bureaucracy running our municipal government.  Residents will say, \"Council should do this, or the borough should do that,\" but I tell every resident I know that without residents volunteering to help we're not going to go anywhere.  The borough is of limited size constrained by a small budget.  But with my management training, world experiences, and the belief we need to pull together, we'll be the best in the county. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I'm married, the proud father of four US service veteran children, the son of a WWII and Korean War veteran, am a retired Army reserve Master Sergeant of 24 years, and an Iraq War veteran.  I served with the US Army as a UN Peacekeeper in Haiti, was a responder to three Gulf Coast hurricanes, worked in private and corporate business, and worked as a federal government civilian.   I chose to move to Ambridge, restore historic houses, and to help work in the Ambridge community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["The children and teachers are the top priority, anti-bullying programs where our children can learn and grow to stop the current bullying program, updated safety programs for all schools in the event of an incident, tax reform- we don’t need higher taxes, we need better spending. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["Tax increases, less supplies than ever, teacher cuts. All of this can be solved with smarter spending and applying for more grants. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["No one should be mandated to take a vaccine. Parents and staff should have the right to do what’s best for them and their families regarding masks and schooling. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["CRT has been banned in several states and should not be a part of the AASD curriculum. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_amy_fitsko","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am a hard working single mom who just wants the best for the children and the district to provide the best possible future for our families. Please vote for Amy Fitsko for Ambridge Area School District, it’s time for a change. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["While I believe our district has great potential, I also believe that we need to focus on improvements to fiduciary responsibility, equilibrium and improvement of learning/scoring, attendance, reputation/value to our community."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["I believe that the Ambridge Area School district has great potential, but I believe that we have financial and learning/scoring obstacles that need to be addressed. We have much work to do in this regard. As we move forward, we must ensure that we return to an upward trajectory in these areas.","","I believe that a vision and plan need to be created, with tangible benchmarks to measure stated goals. Without a stated plan for correction/resurgence, I believe the district will continue to struggle. While I am only one vote, I believe that I will continue to be a strong proponent of and contributor to this end."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I contracted Covid-19 while double masking in February. My personal belief is that it should be parental choice, as the current AASD board voted for at the beginning of the year. I believe that the district is bound to follow the mandate as written and that anyone who disagrees should share their opinions with their state representatives. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["I am currently exploring CRT. I think it is important to support an integrated learning experience and environment for all students. I will not support division, suppression or inequity in learning. I will consider this and other issues with sound judgement and equity as they are presented. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_john_carpenter","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I will be a strong voice for improvement in the areas I’ve stated. My hope is that those that support me will do so because they have faith in my judgement and resolve to apply my influence on moving AASD back to an upward trajectory in learning, financial sustainability, safety and equilibrium for our students, the district and our community."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["The district strategic plan should drive the priorities of the school board.  The Ambridge Area Board of Directors has hired a Superintendent to be our educational and systematic leader.  My goal is to support the administration and staff while providing the accountability the community wants. As a Board member, my biggest goal is to evaluate and understand why our class sizes  K, 1, 2 are so high and how to adjust this. However, before you can make changes, we need to understand more collectively and data-driven to our community expectations.  We need to have more active collaboration from our community to drive our priorities from the school and the community.   "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest challenges our district faces currently are the pandemic and the systemic changes due to the pandemic.  We are talking more about mandates and what is the law and what is not law.  We need our government to support local education agencies and place wording so that it does not have so many different interpretations.  We need to have our government either do the job or leave at the local decision.  We should be focusing on the student learners or reviewing and asking for educational reform.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["At this point, our Governor has taken away the right for the board of directors to decide on mask mandates for students and staff.  Our current board voted 9 – 0 in favor of parent choice at the beginning of the year.  Therefore, my vote when I was permitted was for parent choice.  As for vaccines for staff, I do not believe I am qualified to decide for someone's medical needs.  Therefore, if I were asked to vote, it would be a teacher/staff choice.  Decisions like masking and vaccines for schools should be state-wide. If the department of health has proof that there is a clear reason for something, I encourage them to use their authority to make the judgment.  However, suppose they do not mandate something as health officials. In that case, I do not feel that my degrees in education make me qualified to determine other people's health decisions.   "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical Race Theory is just a theory that the media has used to debate throughout the state.  However, the framework for CRT is not as new as one would think. It has been discussed at the graduate level and in the legal circles since the 1970s.  Sadly, CRT has been confused with what districts focus on supporting and implementing culturally responsive teaching and leadership practices.  Being a culturally responsive school allows teachers and school leaders to affirm and incorporate the diverse cultural references, identities, voices, experiences, and histories of ALL students and their families.  The board of directors' adoption of education curriculum must be aligned to academic standards established and mandated by the State Board of Education.  It is neither required nor credible that Pennsylvania's school district contemplate adopting a curriculum built specifically around CRT.  Misunderstanding about CRT has created unnecessary attacks and undermined public schools' important efforts to promote equity in their programs.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_denise_manganello","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If elected, I will continue to try my best to advocate for all students in the district.  I also want to provide encouragement and support to our administration and especially our teachers.  We have amazing and talented teachers and students who need to be illustrated.  I hope that I have proven that I am dedicated to you and remain to my integrity and morals."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["Top priorities are Quality Education and sound management of the school's finances for the betterment of all the District's residents."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest challenges we face are a deminishing student enrollment ","And a deminishing tax base.","We need afortable housing costs and afortable rents for all residents.","The solution is to provide Quality Education for each student, at the same time deliver a dollar's worth of service for each dollar of taxes.",""]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["Voluntary as per each school district and as per Pennsylvania's Governor's original stance."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["The Theory is not Fact.","We are all God's children, all races.","We must love one another and work together to promote unity, in this free country,  the \"United\" States of America."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_tom_daman","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If elected by We The People, Rochester Area School District will conduct open meetings for All citizens to speek any concerns they may have to the board freely!"]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priorities for the Ambridge Area School District are:","1. I will help to create a strategic plan and vision to market our district and community by providing a quality, equitable education with increased resources for mental health, social, and emotional needs, where our students feel safe, welcome, and appreciated.","2. If elected, I will serve with fiscal responsibility, integrity, transparency, and equity; while wisely and ethically spending the tax payers money without unreasonable tax increases that the community simply cannot afford.  Wasteful spending is affecting the economic growth of our community and needs to be carefully looked at in the detailed budget.","3. I want to build a 21st century, technology integrated curriculum to fit the unique skills that our students will need for their futures.  Our students need to be prepared with grit and resiliency and the want to be lifelong learners.  We have 12 years to help each of our students find their path and prepare them for their futures and we need to take that very seriously."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["I believe that some of our biggest challenges are below:","1. Our community members pay the highest taxes in Beaver County, which equivilates to one of the highest per pupil costs in the area.  However, we are one of the lowest scoring districts in the area.  Our focus needs to be on fiscally spending the district's money on meeting the needs of all students, while not further burdening our tax payers.","2. We have a serious need in the department of educational technology.  Our students did not have computers until Fall of 2020.  In my educational opinion, our students and teachers have still not received the proper training in order to utilize the best educational technology advances available to meet the 21st century needs of our students.  I have witnessed as a parent the struggle and frustration that our students feel because there is a lack of strategic technology implementation.  There are so many resources available for teachers to use in their classrooms to provide a more fluid education that students can all participate in and learn from.  Our teachers need consistent professional development in this area, because many of them are ready and willing to learn.  In addition, our school has the curriculum to have a successful cyber option for students if needed, however, does not have the resources to support this program in order for our students' needs to be met.  ","3. I believe, although we have recently made several positive strides towards improvement in our special education department, we still have a long way to go to ensure we are meeting the unique needs of all of our students.  Too many of our students have fallen through the cracks over the past decade and deserve so much better. ","4. We seem to be taking a reactive approach to decision making rather than a proactive approach.  I know we are in unprecendented times with a lot of recent issues in our country, however, we must have strategic, well-thought out plans with contingency strategies to proactively handle situations, rather than constantly putting out the next fire.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["There is a current mask mandate in place that we are required to follow.  I fully support the current school board in their decision to follow that mandate, and also respect the fact that they initially voted to allow for parent/student choice before the mandate occurred, as they felt it was in the best interest of the majority of our students.  If the mandate is lifted at some point, I am very open to discussing pros and cons of mask wearing, as I know we have many residents in our district who feel strongly on both sides of the stance.  In the end, everyone is concerned about their children, and as a representative of the school district, I plan to ensure that we do our absolute best to provide and safe environment for all students.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical Race Theory is a curricular framework that has been around for quite some time, but has recently come back into the spotlight in the media.  I believe that there is a lot of misunderstandings that surround the topic of CRT that lead to unneccessary debates.  If elected, curriculum is one of the things I will be carefully reviewing, and I will ensure that we are supporting and implementing culturally responsive teaching and leadership practices.  I will always advocate for providing an equitable education for all of our students.  I will ensure that we are operating, as I believe we are, as a culturaly responsive school that incorporates and welcomes diverse cultural identities, experiences, and histories for all students to learn.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_kelly_romasco","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["Many people ask me why I do all that I do in our district and community, and my answer is very simple.  I care so much about our community members, district employees, parents, and children that I cannot sit back and watch.  I have to and want to do everything in my power to make a difference.  I look forward to having the opportunity to do so as a school board member.  I wish all of the candidates the best of luck and look forward to the opportunity to work with each of you moving forward to build bigger and better things for Ambridge Area School District!"]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["Moving the District Forward, is my main priority.  Working with the superintendent the last four years has created many current opportunities for the district.  I am hoping to reconvene the Citizen’s Advisory Committee to review the past recommendations and to make future plans to be good stewards of the facilities and funds the taxpayers entrust us with.  This will include future upgrades to existing aging facilities and some out of the box planning by coordinating with our district superintendent who has consistently led the board to make decisions that have set us up for continued success."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest challenge we have recently seen would have to be Covid 19.  It literally derailed any district forward movement by continually having to focus on and reacting to it and the constantly changing government mandates. Mandates made by the state with no real thought on how they would play out in the “real world”.  I have tried to explain to people my goal and vision is a long term one that began pre Covid and my goals and visions still are looking forward.  ","","Covid 19 protocols, to me, are a short term distraction to long term planning.  And people have to really think about that when choosing their next leaders.  Do you want someone with a short term agendas or long term goals?  Up until Covid the Blackhawk board was meeting all the goals we had set out to accomplish.  And honestly even during Covid we were able to contract and finish safety upgrades to our high school.  So our leadership has shined through this dark blip in our district history."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["This is a hard question to answer, my personal beliefs don’t matter when it comes to my school board decisions.  Personally, I believe in masking as little as possible, except when required.  I would feel comfortable sending my child to school unmasked and I would be fine working in my district unmasked if allowed, however, the state mandates masking right now so what I think does not matter.  We mask.  There are many things in life we have to do, even when we don’t want to.","","As a school board member, I am responsible for not only my son, but approximately 2000 other students as well.  This is why I supported OPTIONAL MASKING in our health and safety plan. I had many parents ask for masking, although more behind the scenes, then those that wanted us to unmask.   This plan was required by the state for us to submit, but that all went out the window when a week into school the governor decided to mandate masking in schools, because he thought more districts would chose masking.","","I can say that local schools that have masked since day 1 of school, like Blackhawk, we have not missed a day of school due to high Covid numbers or quarantines. This is as of 9/28.  I think that says something, because other schools have lost days.  If our goal is to keep kids in school, Blackhawk is doing it!!  And we have been leading since the beginning.","","I do not believe in  or would I support mandatory vaccinations."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical Race Theory has NO ROLE in the classroom or in our district curriculum.  That is my belief and opinion."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_2_melissa_ziegler","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I do not believe in creating board majorities. I campaign on my own because I fought against board majorities for years before running myself. My belief is, if you come to the table and do your research on the issues brought before you and your aren’t interested in promoting agendas, you will be an excellent board member helping to make wise decisions on behalf of your constituents. As a board member, you need to understand not everyone will agree with you, but if you listen and are fair and you lead with integrity people will feel confident and support the district initiatives. It is hard sometimes when a divisive decision is before you, one that means you need to look at both sides and make a decision for the good of the whole district and not get distracted by political agendas, I think I have shown I can do that and do it well. I hope the residents of Blackhawk elect me for 4 more years, as I have shown that I can lead through adversity. Thank you, Melissa"]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priority for the district is to continue in the direction they are going. Continue to provide and utilize technology. Continue to offer college credit courses to high school students. To maintain community relationships with outside organizations that benefit our kids. "]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["One of the biggest challenges facing the district is an aging population in fixed incomes.  A school district needs tax dollars to continue to grow and thrive. Additional tax bills may be harder for those residents to make. While tax increases may be inevitable, the burden can be lifted through grant money. I can help source and write those grants. "]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I am pro mask. I work in schools and I see kids in their masks. The vast majority of students don't mind them especially if it helps them maintain face to face learning. I think caution and safety are a small price to pay for face to face instruction. As for mandatory vaccination for staff, I think that would have to be evaluated per district, taking in account the school population as well as positive covid case counts for the district and the area."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["I think that the curriculum taught in schools should be factual and consist of several points of view so that no groups of people are left out. Children need to know how different things effect different people."]},{"candidateCode":"rochester_area_school_board_of_directors_jocelyn_nicole_haskins","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am dedicated to do what is best for our students, our school and our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["I want to see the district work toward a more responsible financial policy. We need to spend the citizen’s tax dollars in a way that provides a sound educational experience for the children of the district.  By spending smarter and more effectively, I’d hope to see test scores increase.  Our district ranks low both within the state and county and I want to see them increase."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["I feel the biggest challenge we face is financial.  Our budget continues to grow every year, but the cuts being made appear to be questionable.  An increasing portion of our budget has been going to charter school fees.  More families have chosen charters over Ambridge and it needs to be explored why.  If answers can be given, the district may be able to win some family's favor back and increase enrollment."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I feel that both masking and vaccines are a personal choice.  These decisions should be left to the parents and staff.  It is quite a hot topic and decisions should not be entered into lightly.  The parents need to make decisions for their own kids.  The staff member should make a decision with their doctor as to what is best for them."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["My feeling on CRT is that it is politically driven to cause division.  I support an environment where all students can learn about all history, no matter what story it tells.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_area_school_board_of_directors_4_years_matthew_zatchey","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I'm Ambridge born and raised.  I care about this community, the kids and the school.  I want my 3 kids to grow up in a community that cares for one another and where a great education is available to all families in the district."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["Maximize the face to face instruction as we know face to face instruction provides the best education for the students.","Continue to improve the financial condition of the school district while maintaining its high educational standards.","Continue to implement the long range plan for the districts buildings and search for creative ways to fund those building needs while eliminating or minimizing the need for tax increases as much as possible."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["Working through the constantly changing and evolving Covid-19 issues.","Protecting our students from indoctrination programs currently being pushed and any others like them in the future.","Finding ways and financial means to renovate our aging buildings while eliminating or minimizing the impact on our tax payers.","Continuing to reduce our debt in whatever ways we can."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["Personally, I am not an advocate of mandatory masking.  My position is based upon my personal work experiences of thousands of hours with the use of respiratory protection. ","","Personally, I am against mandatory vaccination.  Situations such as vaccinations should be a personal decision never a government requirement."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["I am completely against socialistic/marxist indoctrination of any kind in our schools.  Critical Theory, Critical Race Theory and the 1619 Project, just being the most recent programs being pushed.  Many were ONLY MEANT to be taught in colleges to legal students in order to prepare them for arguments against such biases. They were never intended to be taught as a viable theory in K-12, so most of these programs are inappropriate at best, but none of this should be taught in our schools. Teaching such theories elevates these ideologies and false premises and gives them undeserved legitimacy they should never be given."]},{"candidateCode":"blackhawk_school_district_board_of_directors_region_1_neil_morrison","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I follow a code of ethics in everything I do.  I try my best to act with honor, character, integrity and honesty.  I try to be a good steward in everything I do and I take this same approach with tax payer's funds when making decisions for our district.  I truly believe that we should all give back and try to take care of our community, so I take this position very seriously.  While I will not promise not to raise taxes when necessary, I will promise I will NEVER agree to automatic tax increases.  I further promise to continue to do my best to come up with wise solutions to all of our problems and issues and I promise to do whatever I can to mitigate the need for raising taxes."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priorities are to 1.) learn and understand the current challenges, priorities, and constraints the school district has 2.) disseminate information. ","","Having a good understanding how the school district operates would allow for constructive input to build upon and improve what is already an excellent, sought-after school system.    ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["Right now, political divisiveness appears to be the biggest challenge facing all levels of government, including our school district. My small part in solving this problem is by engaging in meaningful, in-person discussions to genuinely understand differing perspectives and foster civility. I do not participate in personal social media networks which spur fruitless personal attacks and debates."]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["The Wolf administration reversed its stance on state-wide masking mandates for schools which sparked much divisiveness within our community.  Masking decisions for students and staff should be left to the jurisdiction of the local school board with a default stance for personal freedom and choice for both masking and vaccines.","","Parents and staff should seek counsel and follow the advice of trusted, medical doctors and pediatricians when making masking and vaccine decisions for themselves and their families.  Likewise, they should understand contact tracing and quarantine implications of their decisions.",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["While standing outside of the polling stations during the May primary elections, Critical Race Theory was the most commonly discussed topic.  It was unanimously opposed by the community members that I spoke to.  I believe Critical Race Theory perpetuates a focus on racial groups and racial division instead of individual merit.  For both reasons, Critical Race Theory should not shape classroom curriculum.  "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_daniel_kelosky","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["My favorite book is “Team of Rivals”.  I’m interested in learning from and working with people that have perspectives differing from my own.  "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top three priorities are as follows:","","1) Partner with the current board and the community to solve the complex and everchanging challenges associated with Covid-19 mitigation.  The goal is to keep students in face-to-face education and in person while at the same time avoiding any loss of freedoms to choose what works best for students and their families. ","","2) Improve transparency of school director activities and seek ongoing input from students, parents, teachers, and tax payers in the community.","","3) Focus intently on ways to assess and improve the health and wellness of our students.  In particular, I believe there is huge need to focus on their emotional wellbeing and assist them in better navigating the challenges they will face in school and beyond.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["*Please see the associated “top priorities” listed above. The biggest challenges facing our district include:","","1) Solving the complex and everchanging Covid-19 mitigation strategies.  ","","2) Improving the school’s ability to assess and improve students’ health and wellness.","","3) Ensure that all students receive excellent face-to-face and in person education.","","To solve these challenges, I plan to work closely with the current board and community members to clearly define the problem, then measure it, analyze it, and improve it.  We will need to set short-term and long-term goals which will be measured by carefully chosen metrics. Any improvement that has been initiated will have a control mechanism so that improvements are not lost.",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["Mandatory masking is unconstitutional and is a decision that is best left up to parents.  I want to emphasize that the current mandate is not simply about a mask, it’s about giving up parental rights to that of the state and school district.  I am not \"anti-mask,\" instead I advocate for the right of students and teachers to choose what works best for them.  The unfortunate reality is that teachers are put in the challenging position to \"mask police\" instead of focusing on their expertise in teaching. I love our teachers at Riverside and I advocate for their rights to choose what works best for them. ","","In regards to mandated COVID-19 vaccinations, I believe that we are still in the experimental phase and the vaccine should remain optional. The short term and long-term effects of the vaccine are not fully understood.  The VAERS analysis indicates a significant number of adverse reactions, life threatening events, permanent disabilities, and death. The benefits and risks should be taking under consideration for everyone and the decision is unique to individual circumstances.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["Critical race theory has no place in our classrooms. It teaches our children that the most important aspect about them is their skin color and that racism exists, either consciously or unconsciously, in every interaction. I have concerns about this approach because it does not take into account the unique qualities that we have as individuals. Also, this type of education has anti-American qualities, is rooted in socialism, and has the potential to foster more racial division.  Moving forward, I would love to see more focus on a patriotic education that is focused on the vision that our founding fathers had for our great nation.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_mathew_lawrence","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["•        I’ll respectfully listen to all views ","","•        I’ll do whatever it takes to solve a complex problem","","•        I won’t give up easy ","","•        I’m not afraid to speak truth, even if I stand alone","","",""]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What are your top priorities for the school district? Be descriptive. ","response":["My top priority is keeping the kids in school for in-person learning. I’d like to avoid any closures or quarantines due to Covid. I’d also like to ensure there is a virtual streaming option for those who are quarantined. ","I’d like to see a portion of the ESSER funds received by the state be put towards addressing the impact of this global pandemic on the students’ mental health. ","I would also like part in decision making regarding the school’s budget in the coming years. "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What are some of the biggest challenges facing your district currently? How do you hope to help solve them? ","response":["The biggest thing on our district’s plate currently is the masking order from the state. I’d like to ensure that we comply with this order and keep the kids, teachers, and administration healthy. "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What is your stance on mandatory COVID-19 masking in schools for students and staff? What about mandated COVID-19 vaccines for staff?","response":["I think vaccines should remain optional for all students. I myself will be vaccinating my kids, but I understand the hesitancy. Masking, however, should be enforced for everyone except those with a valid medical exemption. The more people in a room wearing a mask, the more effective they are. Think of it as the same concept as coughing into your elbow, or covering your nose when you sneeze. It is a literal barrier blocking droplets that potentially contain the Covid 19 virus from spreading to other people. I think masks should be mandatory until a vaccine is available to all students. "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What role should critical race theory play in the classroom, in your opinion? ","response":["This is an extremely divisive topic and I don’t think it should be. I think that learning the truth about history allows us to not repeat the mistakes made in some cases.  "]},{"candidateCode":"riverside_beaver_county_school_board_of_directors_kate_reed","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If elected, I will always have what’s best for the kids in mind with any decision I would make on the board. I’d like to avoid tax increases. And finally, I’d like the kids and staff at the schools to remain healthy and thriving, physically and mentally. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["The biggest challenge for Ambridge is improving its socio-economic condition.  I would start by analyzing the budget and develop ways to bring more cash flow into the borough WITHOUT raising taxes.  I will work with code enforcement to ensure the community is desirable to residential and business newcomers.  I will work with churches and non-profits to bring more family friendly activities and venues to Ambridge."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I became involved shortly after moving to Ambridge.  I volunteer with the Committee to Clean and Beautify Ambridge.   I have participated in the annual community clean up days.  I patronize, support, and promote our small businesses including bringing friends and family from other communities to shop in Ambridge.  I am active in my Ambridge Church plant, participating in various outreach opportunities."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I am the only candidate with a background in Accounting and Finance.  My professional and my volunteer experience combine to give me the perfect qualifications for a council member.   I have served Ambridge long before I decided to run for council and I have attended council meetings for the past 2 years.   I am fully invested in seeing Ambridge thrive."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am not a politician.  I am a public servant.   I simply love Ambridge and I'm excited to be a part of her vibrant future!"]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["I believe that there have historically been systemic issues of undue separation between council and their constituents. In an effort to combat that, I have been making myself available to anyone who would want to reach out and talk to me. I have an active campaign Facebook, website, twitter, email, Instagram, and cell phone to make sure that any constituent can reach out to me, even if they cannot make it to the meetings, and I make every effort to respond to messages as soon as I can. "]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I have been involved in Economy borough since 2017. I was appointed to both the Zoning Hearing Board and the Recreation Board towards the end of the year. On the Zoning Hearing Board, I have personally ruled in favor of small businesses opening up in Economy Borough, and I would love to see that trend continue. As a member of the Recreation Board, I tend to help set up annual events, and can be seen lending a hand wherever it is needed. Starting in 2018, I have spent just about every election day out at my precinct, no matter the weather, and it is really one of the highlights of the year for me. "]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["For one thing I am the only woman running for council this election cycle. If elected, I will then be the only woman on the council. I am ready to put in the effort and make changes for the betterment of the borough. I look forward to the challenges of being a public servant, and I welcome constructive feedback from everyone. "]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If I had the choice, I do not believe that there would be anywhere else that I would want to live. My husband and I moved to the area to set out on our own, free from being known by family relations. ","If you have any questions about me, you are welcome to visit my website www.ElizabethforEconomy.com where you can send me an email, or link to one of my social media pages. I would be very happy to hear from you. "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Biggest challenges are repairing the lack of funds the borough faces , reorganizing the committees , creating a resident run committee on assisting decisions and problems the borough faces . "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I have not been involved with the community as long as I would have preferred but faced many challenges as a new resident 11 years ago with being a “outsider” as many have called us. "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["Motivation to better the borough for ALL of our residents , I am related to NO ONE whom resides here and have a outsider view which adds many contributions to our community. I own a small business that deals with law enforcement in many aspects and on many levels and I would like to have better coordination and communication with all of the emergency services provided to our borough and surrounding communities. I would like to see more businesses invited into our community also. "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am 35 years of age with an amazing Wife and 3 fantastic brilliant children , we love all of our local community activities , my wife sits on freedom PTA , I sit in the board of the FBCCA,  we strive to do good in our communities and everyone we reach on a daily business . "]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["New demands for costly services"]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["Lifelong resident, returned after education, experience in Big Beaver business (trucking) See above"]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I am of the borough, will be for the borough, and will be buried in the borough, Grandview Cemetery."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["Studied abroad (Spain), Masters degrees from University of Wisconsin-Madison and University of Pittsburgh, taught sociology at Seton Hill College, CCBC, and Spanish at CCBC"]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Finding alternative ways to finance budget.  Economic development.  Potential growth.  Fixing roads, sidewalks and drainage.","I plan on addressing those by... ","Exploring government grants where applicable.  ","Bringing township transparency to the community and encouraging community involvement.","Revisiting zoning regulations and propose change and be accountable."]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["Married, two adult children.","Local, successful business owner for over 15 years.","Resident of Hopewell Township for over 25 years."]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I am aggressive, forward thinking and not afraid of change.","I am not swayed by peer pressure and am not afraid to speak up if I do not agree with something.","I am 100% committed to a job and its responsibility to meet end goals.","I am aware that it takes more than one person to make change.  I will put my best foot forward to push for positive change for our community."]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am not a politician.","I am a \"go-getter\" and not afraid of change.","I realize that being a Commissioner is not a one person job.  It is a TEAM of people and ideas and personalities that need to come together to help our community grow."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["There is a distrust with the government, even at our local level, and the systems it built to care for us, protect us, and represent us as our collective voice.  In addition, all communities have been facing the ravaging effects of a pandemic both in our households and our businesses.  I believe that we rebuild trust by starting at the local level.  We can take many small steps that have a big impact such as increasing access to information, being available to answer questions as openly and as transparently as possible.  We have an opportunity to set an example as to how we can all work together for the best solutions for our community.  We address challenges by respecting and taking care of each other."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I was born and raised in Beaver County.  I am a proud wife and mother of 3 amazing children.  I have always believed in volunteering within the community.  I started as a candy striper in our local nursing home in high school and have always continued to volunteer in a variety of ways, including now as a board member with our local Mental Health Association.  I am a career student with a plethora of degrees, believing that there is always room to improve your knowledge and skills and there has rarely been a time in my life when I was not actively taking classes.  I have dedicated my career to trying to improve the lives of others as a registered nurse; from being the Clinical Director of Behavioral Health in a smaller local health system to my current career as a board-certified case manager in a large health system.  I am professionally most proud of winning a national ACAP Making a Difference Award Honorable Mention, a health system wide Outstanding Patient Advocate Award, and a health system wide Dignity and Respect Champion award, highlighting my dedication to others.  I attend all the local council meetings and volunteer on our local planning commission.  I fervently believe that we should all contribute our talents and time to make our community the best it can possibly be for our future generations."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I have had the pleasure to speak with every candidate running for office.  Each person is doing so with the best interest of the community at heart, in that, I feel that we are all much more similar than we are different.  Each person has a unique set of skills to bring to the table and I believe my strengths lie with in my professional experience and current involvement in our local community."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If voted in to office, I will be a hard-working dedicated servant to the residents of Ohioville.  I appreciate my community and the many individuals who live here and look forward to the opportunity to give back. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Most municipalities have to deal with the balancing taxes with properly-funded government services, and Baden is no exception. We cannot cut corners on valuable government services and institutions, but neither can we expect taxpayers to foot the bill for irresponsible financial decisions. I believe the best way to handle this balance is to understand each expense and its impact on the community. Simply put, smart budgeting requires a lot of hard work, and I'm prepared to do it. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I'm a lifelong resident of Baden, and, as of 2018, a Baden homeowner. I graduated from Ambridge High School in 2007, where I was an unabashed band geek. It was actually my involvement in the marching band that got me started volunteering in the community, since I had to log a certain number of service hours as a requirement for one of our trips. For the next 16 years, I spent every Labor Day Weekend working the silent auction at the Good Samaritan Parish Festival, one of my favorite events. ","I'm also an active member of the Beaver County Young Democrats and the Beaver County Democratic Committee. Through these organizations, I devote a lot of time to educating voters about who their elected officials are, when and how to vote, and the importance of civic responsibility. ","Earlier this summer, I was appointed to Baden Council to fill a vacancy left by a resignation, and I've been learning as much about municipal government as I possibly can. I hope to be elected to a full term to continue this work that I've already found to be extremely enjoyable and rewarding. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["My extensive technical training separates me from the other candidates. Paying for technology hardware and services is expensive, and a lot of training is necessary to pick through the technical jargon in a price estimate. I am the only person with that training. This also gives me the ability to look for ways to modernize our municipal government. ","I am also one of only two non-incumbent candidates on the ballot this year who was regularly attending meetings (before I was appointed to fill the Council vacancy). I am committed to learning and understanding everything I can so I can responsibly serve the residents of Baden. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am a self-taught computer programmer. I didn't study the subject in college. Instead, I had to teach myself, which is extremely difficult and has taken me many years. However, I've built a successful career based on that experience, and I learned that I can handle any subject, no matter how complex, if I put in the time and effort. I've already started doing this for Baden, and I'm hoping for the opportunity to continue. "]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Challenges from taxes to drug and crime issues to infrastructure are always near the top of local community issues.  The way to address them is to solicit community feedback, solicit feedback from the proper authorities that have involvement in the issues, then determine options that protect the communities interest, solicit feedback from the community on the options, and make a decision from there."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I have been in the community for a little more than 12 years.  I originally grew up in South Central Pennsylvania on the family farm and received my education from Penn State University.  I moved to the Big Beaver area a few years back and currently reside there with my wife of 15 years, Carla Lutton Schriver, and our three children."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["An open mind open to changes and a distaste for politicization drives me to be successful.  We are to polarized.  All sides, left or right or middle, all have valid views.  It’s important to be the person who can listen to it all, understand what the community or larger town, city, etc needs and make a decision on that, not who did or didn’t win a larger election."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":""},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["My top priorities are impressing upon council why our Police Department needs to be fully staffed. Making sure taxes are kept low and steady and we have not raised taxes while I've been mayor.  And ensuring that ordinances do not infringe on private property rights or become too intrusive."]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":["As of now our biggest challenge is coming from outside vendors like Valley Waste who is having staffing issues leaving piles of garbage on the curb for days. We are working with our solicitor to make sure they are honoring their service contract.  Our other issues include fracking issues. I firmly believe people who have managed to hold onto large parcels of land have a right to use the oil and gas that is under their farm land to their financial benefit."]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["To be honest I don't judge myself against the other candidate.  I'm me!  I wear my heart on my sleeve.  You will know when I'm passionate about issues that I feel are important for individual liberties and protecting those individual liberties is a priority for me."]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_mayor_jo_ann_borato","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I actually eally care about what happens in my borough, as I've said earlier I've attended YEARS of council meetings so I understand the history of many issues in our Borough.  I tend to internalize issues and work hard to find solutions.  I don't like leaving loose end or things only vaguely remedied."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["My top priorities are to bring new ideas to the borough to spread community values and make Big Beaver a place that young people want to bring their families to grow."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["I have fresh ideas and a marketing background that can help to bring a brighter future to the community."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_mayor_jamie_marshall","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["My family is deeply rooted in Big Beaver Borough and we intend to raise our children here as I was raised here."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["As mayor, I want to put a fresh face of hope on our town. I don’t think the town needs another ‘get off my lawn’ old white man, in the mayor’s office. As a business owner in Ambridge, I have seen some hard times. We had to really hustle and be creative. I think that’s what Ambridge needs, creativity and determination. We have some positive momentum, and it needs to be fed and, with the right energy, we could definitely see more positive things continue to happen in the years to come. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":["I think we have two major issues that need to be worked on, both equally important. One is that we need to bridge the ‘trust gap’ between the police department and the community. Some really good steps have been taken toward accomplishing this, but we still need to work on it. The officers need outlets to engage with youth and charitable organizations. The other issue that needs addressed is, of course, our drug epidemic, which goes hand in hand with the mental health epidemic.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["I view myself as a very socially liberal person. I believe in equality. I pride myself in being a very caring person, without being naive. I have earned the trust of many of the pillars of the Ambridge community. I am approachable for young and old alike. I am always working on my conflict resolution skills, and I really want to bring ‘being neighborly’ back!"]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_lorianne_burgess","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I am a widowed mother of two children. I understand the struggles of the people in our community. I talk to so many of my fellow citizens every day, in my bakery and walking down the street. I believe that there is something beautiful on every single block of this amazing town. There are genuinely wonderful folks in every corner of this diverse, inspiring melting pot of a community that we have the supreme privilege to be a part of. I wouldn’t live anywhere else. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What are your top priorities as mayor? ","response":["As the only elected executive of the borough, the mayor is charged with three primary responsibilities - preserving order, enforcing ordinances and regulations and removing nuisances among some other lesser duties.  In the Army, if we were not on a mission we were training for a mission.  If it worked for the Army it can certainly work for Ambridge. ","","The mayor is traditionally seen as overseeing the police, but not to be a policeman.  In order  to ensure the police are doing the best job they can with the limited resources given them they need to be constantly trained, but also well equipped.  Kudos to our police officers.  ","","Calls to the police and the police's responses are one indicator of what the resident's concerns are and a picture of our collective problems.  Better community communications and police relations is a start, but the systematic documentation of calls, the responses, and any consequent arrests is part of tracking and tackling crime.  If the residents know their concerns and the calls they make are being addressed then they will have more trust and patience in the police force as the police work to tackle the issues.  I want to see all of this quantified so that our police systematically identify the problems, and focus our limited resources on nuisances and problem areas.  ","","Among other duties, the borough manager is the chief code enforcement officer as well as the operations manger.  It's the mayor's duty to see that code enforcement is operating properly, and equitably, for all building owners, residential as well as commercial, and industrial also.  Too many of our residential buildings have been divided up into small apartments maximizing the investor's return on investment.  But this is often at the expense of quality of life for the residents of the neighborhood with resultant scarcity of parking and heavily traveled and congested streets making driving tight and municipal services on them difficult.  With investment in a community comes responsibility to the community.  Investors wanting to make houses into apartments need to adhere to planning commission review to examine their plans as a whole and the impact on the neighborhood.  But planning and zoning need badly updated too in order to provide the tools to check uncontrolled and unmonitored development.  ","","The commercial districts also needs updated ordinances and code review.  New trends in apartment living in retail areas call for updates in our commercial ordinances and zoning to build on the good work already happening there.  Too often the catch phrase \"blighted\" is assumed to mean to eliminate a problem building with county grants by demolition.  What is not looked at is using that same grant money to stabilize our old and historic retail storefronts and preserve them for redevelopment.  It's acceptable and doable by Community Development , it just needs folks willing to see these old retail spaces in a different light.   ","","Finally, our industrial neighbors need to be more involved in our community.  Too often we turn a blind eye to the appearance of our industrial neighbors because we want the jobs and taxes so badly we don't want to somehow offend them.  Industrial neighbors need to be good neighbors too in cleaning up their appearance, planting trees to block views, and to participate in community projects.  These often distant owners are connected via a plant manager we can connect with for their help and express our concerns. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What are the biggest challenges your community faces? How will you address them? ","response":["The borough has all the ills of other post-industrial towns.  Crime and drugs have to be checked, and they are starting to be checked with a newly reorganized police department, Kudos again.  But we need more cooperation with the state police and other agencies.  Our residents also need speak up more and they need a vehicle to voice their concerns without criticism of fear of retribution.  I will press these other organization to help us as much as they are able.  Our police need all the assistance there is.  But not all issues are so visible.  ","","Our potable water source is carried across a soon-to-be 100 year old bridge.  The county keeps patching the Ambridge bridge, but some believe it is in far worse condition than it appears.  The county has had plans for a bridge a half a mile north for a while.  But how does this old plan address our water supply?  Our water is piped across the bridge.  Why isn't it being addressed as the number one county priority for all the communities dependent on the Ambridge reservoir?  But  instead some are pushing for a recreation bridge for bikes and hikers.  Why isn't the borough demanding something be done to secure our water supply and the water of all the neighboring communities who depend on the Ambridge Water Authority?","","As most residents are aware, we have issues with the lack of a local food supply.  This has been partially addressed with nearby grocery stores, but that in of itself doesn't resolve access to food.  How do those with limited transportation get their food?  How do you shop when there's no public transportation to your neighborhood?  Our store needs to be walkable.  But even then this isn't just a mater of getting a closer store (which will continue to be my priority), but of food security.  We tend to trust the current food supply system which is failing.  Empty shelves tell us that.  The Just-in-time business model is experiencing problems.  I cannot say if it's going to be fixed, but I believe we should look at opportunities to be more self sufficient.  There are communities that are doing some limited urban farming and orchards. We already have some food producers among us most aren't aware of.  It doesn't have to be an either or situation, but perhaps a new focus on leaning on each other as a part of our food security. ","","One other challenge is our access to the water that surrounds us on three sides for recreation. Recreational water access is very doable.  Access to Sewickley Creek, and the Ohio River will take work of dedicated volunteer residents, but is already in early discussions.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates?","response":["Unlike the other candidates, I wasn't born and raised in Ambridge.  I chose to move to Ambridge.  I chose to build my life here, so I have a lot at stake to make Ambridge a success. ","","I've traveled the country and the world and have seen a lot of community success stories, and a lot of abject failures.  So my view of Ambridge from 30 thousand feet.  It has a richer past than most communities - of such that I believe it deserves recognition as a world heritage site.  But it's more than just our history.  I meet people here every day who are intelligent and of diverse backgrounds, who can help make a difference.  There is no huge bureaucracy running our municipal government.  Residents will say, \"Council should do this, or the borough should do that,\" but I tell every resident I know that without residents volunteering to help we're not going to go anywhere.  The borough is of limited size constrained by a small budget.  But with my management training, world experiences, and the belief we need to pull together, we'll be the best in the county. "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_mayor_dennis_lapic","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I'm married, the proud father of four US service veteran children, the son of a WWII and Korean War veteran, am a retired Army reserve Master Sergeant of 24 years, and an Iraq War veteran.  I served with the US Army as a UN Peacekeeper in Haiti, was a responder to three Gulf Coast hurricanes, worked in private and corporate business, and worked as a federal government civilian.   I chose to move to Ambridge, restore historic houses, and to help work in the Ambridge community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["The biggest challenge for Ambridge is improving its socio-economic condition.  I would start by analyzing the budget and develop ways to bring more cash flow into the borough WITHOUT raising taxes.  I will work with code enforcement to ensure the community is desirable to residential and business newcomers.  I will work with churches and non-profits to bring more family friendly activities and venues to Ambridge."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I became involved shortly after moving to Ambridge.  I volunteer with the Committee to Clean and Beautify Ambridge.   I have participated in the annual community clean up days.  I patronize, support, and promote our small businesses including bringing friends and family from other communities to shop in Ambridge.  I am active in my Ambridge Church plant, participating in various outreach opportunities."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I am the only candidate with a background in Accounting and Finance.  My professional and my volunteer experience combine to give me the perfect qualifications for a council member.   I have served Ambridge long before I decided to run for council and I have attended council meetings for the past 2 years.   I am fully invested in seeing Ambridge thrive."]},{"candidateCode":"ambridge_borough_council_raquel_branchik","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am not a politician.  I am a public servant.   I simply love Ambridge and I'm excited to be a part of her vibrant future!"]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["I believe that there have historically been systemic issues of undue separation between council and their constituents. In an effort to combat that, I have been making myself available to anyone who would want to reach out and talk to me. I have an active campaign Facebook, website, twitter, email, Instagram, and cell phone to make sure that any constituent can reach out to me, even if they cannot make it to the meetings, and I make every effort to respond to messages as soon as I can. "]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I have been involved in Economy borough since 2017. I was appointed to both the Zoning Hearing Board and the Recreation Board towards the end of the year. On the Zoning Hearing Board, I have personally ruled in favor of small businesses opening up in Economy Borough, and I would love to see that trend continue. As a member of the Recreation Board, I tend to help set up annual events, and can be seen lending a hand wherever it is needed. Starting in 2018, I have spent just about every election day out at my precinct, no matter the weather, and it is really one of the highlights of the year for me. "]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["For one thing I am the only woman running for council this election cycle. If elected, I will then be the only woman on the council. I am ready to put in the effort and make changes for the betterment of the borough. I look forward to the challenges of being a public servant, and I welcome constructive feedback from everyone. "]},{"candidateCode":"economy_borough_council_elizabeth_hawkins","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If I had the choice, I do not believe that there would be anywhere else that I would want to live. My husband and I moved to the area to set out on our own, free from being known by family relations. ","If you have any questions about me, you are welcome to visit my website www.ElizabethforEconomy.com where you can send me an email, or link to one of my social media pages. I would be very happy to hear from you. "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Biggest challenges are repairing the lack of funds the borough faces , reorganizing the committees , creating a resident run committee on assisting decisions and problems the borough faces . "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I have not been involved with the community as long as I would have preferred but faced many challenges as a new resident 11 years ago with being a “outsider” as many have called us. "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["Motivation to better the borough for ALL of our residents , I am related to NO ONE whom resides here and have a outsider view which adds many contributions to our community. I own a small business that deals with law enforcement in many aspects and on many levels and I would like to have better coordination and communication with all of the emergency services provided to our borough and surrounding communities. I would like to see more businesses invited into our community also. "]},{"candidateCode":"freedom_borough_council_eric_climo","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am 35 years of age with an amazing Wife and 3 fantastic brilliant children , we love all of our local community activities , my wife sits on freedom PTA , I sit in the board of the FBCCA,  we strive to do good in our communities and everyone we reach on a daily business . "]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["New demands for costly services"]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["Lifelong resident, returned after education, experience in Big Beaver business (trucking) See above"]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I am of the borough, will be for the borough, and will be buried in the borough, Grandview Cemetery."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_jason_landsbach","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["Studied abroad (Spain), Masters degrees from University of Wisconsin-Madison and University of Pittsburgh, taught sociology at Seton Hill College, CCBC, and Spanish at CCBC"]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Finding alternative ways to finance budget.  Economic development.  Potential growth.  Fixing roads, sidewalks and drainage.","I plan on addressing those by... ","Exploring government grants where applicable.  ","Bringing township transparency to the community and encouraging community involvement.","Revisiting zoning regulations and propose change and be accountable."]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["Married, two adult children.","Local, successful business owner for over 15 years.","Resident of Hopewell Township for over 25 years."]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I am aggressive, forward thinking and not afraid of change.","I am not swayed by peer pressure and am not afraid to speak up if I do not agree with something.","I am 100% committed to a job and its responsibility to meet end goals.","I am aware that it takes more than one person to make change.  I will put my best foot forward to push for positive change for our community."]},{"candidateCode":"hopewell_township_commissioner_barbara_michna","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am not a politician.","I am a \"go-getter\" and not afraid of change.","I realize that being a Commissioner is not a one person job.  It is a TEAM of people and ideas and personalities that need to come together to help our community grow."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["There is a distrust with the government, even at our local level, and the systems it built to care for us, protect us, and represent us as our collective voice.  In addition, all communities have been facing the ravaging effects of a pandemic both in our households and our businesses.  I believe that we rebuild trust by starting at the local level.  We can take many small steps that have a big impact such as increasing access to information, being available to answer questions as openly and as transparently as possible.  We have an opportunity to set an example as to how we can all work together for the best solutions for our community.  We address challenges by respecting and taking care of each other."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I was born and raised in Beaver County.  I am a proud wife and mother of 3 amazing children.  I have always believed in volunteering within the community.  I started as a candy striper in our local nursing home in high school and have always continued to volunteer in a variety of ways, including now as a board member with our local Mental Health Association.  I am a career student with a plethora of degrees, believing that there is always room to improve your knowledge and skills and there has rarely been a time in my life when I was not actively taking classes.  I have dedicated my career to trying to improve the lives of others as a registered nurse; from being the Clinical Director of Behavioral Health in a smaller local health system to my current career as a board-certified case manager in a large health system.  I am professionally most proud of winning a national ACAP Making a Difference Award Honorable Mention, a health system wide Outstanding Patient Advocate Award, and a health system wide Dignity and Respect Champion award, highlighting my dedication to others.  I attend all the local council meetings and volunteer on our local planning commission.  I fervently believe that we should all contribute our talents and time to make our community the best it can possibly be for our future generations."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["I have had the pleasure to speak with every candidate running for office.  Each person is doing so with the best interest of the community at heart, in that, I feel that we are all much more similar than we are different.  Each person has a unique set of skills to bring to the table and I believe my strengths lie with in my professional experience and current involvement in our local community."]},{"candidateCode":"ohioville_borough_council_jessica_janicki","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["If voted in to office, I will be a hard-working dedicated servant to the residents of Ohioville.  I appreciate my community and the many individuals who live here and look forward to the opportunity to give back. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Most municipalities have to deal with the balancing taxes with properly-funded government services, and Baden is no exception. We cannot cut corners on valuable government services and institutions, but neither can we expect taxpayers to foot the bill for irresponsible financial decisions. I believe the best way to handle this balance is to understand each expense and its impact on the community. Simply put, smart budgeting requires a lot of hard work, and I'm prepared to do it. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I'm a lifelong resident of Baden, and, as of 2018, a Baden homeowner. I graduated from Ambridge High School in 2007, where I was an unabashed band geek. It was actually my involvement in the marching band that got me started volunteering in the community, since I had to log a certain number of service hours as a requirement for one of our trips. For the next 16 years, I spent every Labor Day Weekend working the silent auction at the Good Samaritan Parish Festival, one of my favorite events. ","I'm also an active member of the Beaver County Young Democrats and the Beaver County Democratic Committee. Through these organizations, I devote a lot of time to educating voters about who their elected officials are, when and how to vote, and the importance of civic responsibility. ","Earlier this summer, I was appointed to Baden Council to fill a vacancy left by a resignation, and I've been learning as much about municipal government as I possibly can. I hope to be elected to a full term to continue this work that I've already found to be extremely enjoyable and rewarding. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["My extensive technical training separates me from the other candidates. Paying for technology hardware and services is expensive, and a lot of training is necessary to pick through the technical jargon in a price estimate. I am the only person with that training. This also gives me the ability to look for ways to modernize our municipal government. ","I am also one of only two non-incumbent candidates on the ballot this year who was regularly attending meetings (before I was appointed to fill the Council vacancy). I am committed to learning and understanding everything I can so I can responsibly serve the residents of Baden. "]},{"candidateCode":"baden_borough_council_joseph_bosh","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":["I am a self-taught computer programmer. I didn't study the subject in college. Instead, I had to teach myself, which is extremely difficult and has taken me many years. However, I've built a successful career based on that experience, and I learned that I can handle any subject, no matter how complex, if I put in the time and effort. I've already started doing this for Baden, and I'm hoping for the opportunity to continue. "]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"What are the biggest challenges facing your community? How do you plan to address those?","response":["Challenges from taxes to drug and crime issues to infrastructure are always near the top of local community issues.  The way to address them is to solicit community feedback, solicit feedback from the proper authorities that have involvement in the issues, then determine options that protect the communities interest, solicit feedback from the community on the options, and make a decision from there."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"Tell voters more about yourself. How long have you been involved in the community and in what capacity? ","response":["I have been in the community for a little more than 12 years.  I originally grew up in South Central Pennsylvania on the family farm and received my education from Penn State University.  I moved to the Big Beaver area a few years back and currently reside there with my wife of 15 years, Carla Lutton Schriver, and our three children."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"What separates you from the other candidates? ","response":["An open mind open to changes and a distaste for politicization drives me to be successful.  We are to polarized.  All sides, left or right or middle, all have valid views.  It’s important to be the person who can listen to it all, understand what the community or larger town, city, etc needs and make a decision on that, not who did or didn’t win a larger election."]},{"candidateCode":"big_beaver_borough_council_garrett_schriver","question":"What else should voters know about you?","response":""},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_robert_dappenbrook","question":"What, in your opinion, is the duty of a district judge? ","response":["The overarching duty of a District Judge is to apply and uphold the legal protections afforded by the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of Pennsylvania. Consequently, District Judges are tasked with presiding over matters ranging from routine traffic citations to more complex matters such as Preliminary Hearings in criminal cases, and civil claims involving, but not limited to, landlord tenant disputes and business/commercial disputes.  Preliminary hearings in criminal matters determine if criminal charges should be held over for a jury trial at the Court of Common Pleas level.  Additionally, in criminal matters, magistrates set bond amounts for criminal Defendants and are involved in the issuance of search warrants and arrest warrants.  Whether in a criminal or civil context, district judges must be knowledgeable in the law and remain objective and impartial in its application."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_robert_dappenbrook","question":"What is your stance on criminal justice reform and reducing recidivism rates in Beaver County? ","response":["While Judges and Judicial candidates should refrain from partisan politics, and should refrain from bringing their own personal beliefs to the bench, my philosophy is that we as a community must be firm in handling criminal matters in our district, and we must also be compassionate where cases and circumstances dictate.  As a private citizen, I personally support criminal justice reform with the goal of reducing recidivism.  I believe reducing recidivism is a logical approach to achieving personal and community safety.  Programs aiming to address some of the core behavioral issues associated with crime (e.g. mental health, drug and alcohol dependency), should be supported through legislation and community-based programs.  In the limited capacity within which I can directly influence recidivist reduction, I intend to do all that I can."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_robert_dappenbrook","question":"What are your top priorities, if elected?","response":["Of the many priorities a Magisterial District Judge should have when elected, I believe focus on our children and their education is extremely important to our community and to their future.  I believe every single truancy case in our district should be handled individually, and not in a cookie cutter fashion.  Each child and situation needs to be addressed with the goal of keeping our truancy rates as low as possible.  We owe it to all of our children to see that their educational needs are met by both encouraging the children to hold themselves accountable and holding their parents accountable.  I believe these priorities can have the most impact on the community."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_robert_dappenbrook","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates? ","response":["I believe that my professional demeanor and temperament set me apart from other candidates seeking this office.  Every candidate who runs a campaign has his supporters and friends who believe in him or her.  I ask all voters concerned with the qualities of the candidates, especially judicial candidates, not to rely on the friends and supporters of the candidates, but to reach out to those professionals who interact with the candidates on a daily basis.  Whether interacting with fellow attorneys, court staff, court personnel, law enforcement, or individual clients, I believe your professional reputation and demeanor define your ability to serve in this position. I am confident that the voters will find that I am the professional candidate who has and will continue to exhibit the necessary judicial temperament and demeanor if I am elected as your next Magisterial District Judge.  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_robert_dappenbrook","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I believe the endorsements I have received, such as that of the Fraternal Order of Police, and that of my Chairman and our former Magisterial District Judge, Tim Finn, are strong indicators that the people and organizations that back me believe that I am the right candidate to hold this important position.  I am also grateful and humbled to have the support of fellow candidates who ran against me during the Primary Election.  Ms. Donna DeRose and Officer Kate Kelly, both approached me after the results of the Primary Election, and have publicly announced their support for me for Magisterial District Judge.  I think the endorsement and trust of these amazing women speak volumes, and I am especially grateful for their support.","","If I have the privilege to serve this community as your next Magisterial District Judge, I will uphold the law, I will be fair, and I will continue to display the professionalism that this office and community deserve.",""]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-3-04_felicia_jezewski-santillan","question":"What, in your opinion, is the duty of a district judge? ","response":["The duty of a magisterial district judge is to follow the rule of law, as any judge is suppose to do.  One must know the law in order to ensure that the people who come before a magistrate are treated in a fair manner.  The magistrate must also know the law in order for cases to proceed appropriately and to not delay the process.  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-3-04_felicia_jezewski-santillan","question":"What is your stance on criminal justice reform and reducing recidivism rates in Beaver County? ","response":["Judges must not take stances.  Even as a member of the minor judiciary, it is important to follow the rule of law.  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-3-04_felicia_jezewski-santillan","question":"What are your top priorities, if elected?","response":["To ensure that the rule of law is followed and that anyone who comes before me knows that I am following the law.  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-3-04_felicia_jezewski-santillan","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates? ","response":["I have 22 years of legal experience and I am qualified to start the position on day 1."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-3-04_felicia_jezewski-santillan","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I want the voters to educate themselves and compare qualifications.  If an individual is elected who is not a lawyer, he/she must take a certification test.  Please ensure that the candidate whom you support is able to start the position on day1.  It is an important position and should have qualified people in it.  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_william_braslawsce","question":"What, in your opinion, is the duty of a district judge? ","response":["A Magisterial District Judge handles small claims, civil matters, landlord/tenant matters, traffic matters and criminal cases at their outset, to include preliminary hearings, setting bonds, issuing warrants.  This is where experience makes a difference.  I have handled thousands of cases at the Magisterial District Judge level of our court system. The Magisterial District Court is truly the peoples court.  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_william_braslawsce","question":"What is your stance on criminal justice reform and reducing recidivism rates in Beaver County? ","response":["The oath of office of the Magisterial District Judge is clear, in that you will uphold the laws of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and the United States of America, not create new laws from the bench.   It is the duty of the Legislative branch to create the laws and rules so that the Judicial branch of our government has the tools necessary to enforce the laws and rule accordingly with Justice and Equity.  The MDJ has discretion within the laws to make the appropriate decisions, based upon the information available or inquired about.  This is where experience makes a difference.  ","Any action that can reduce recidivism should be taken as long as it is within the bounds of the law.  Diversion programs, treatment programs and community service are some of the options that can assist in the reduction of repeat offenders. "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_william_braslawsce","question":"What are your top priorities, if elected?","response":["To ensure all who come before me are treated with dignity, respect and fairness.  This is truly the peoples Court.  No one will come before me if elected with a favor or free pass.  I will weigh each and every case with the Scales of Justice equally balanced.  I feel that the youth of our district should be a top priority.  Addressing any truancy or criminal issues and providing these individuals with the best opportunity to overcome the problems they have encountered and succeed to become productive citizens in our community."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_william_braslawsce","question":"What sets you apart from other candidates? ","response":["EXPERIENCE. COMMITMENT TO OUR COMMUNITY AND OUR COUNTRY."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_36-2-02_william_braslawsce","question":"What else should voters know about you? ","response":["I pledge to work full time for all citizens of MDJ 36-2-02, upholding the laws of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and the United States of America. I will be a Magisterial District Judge for all, Democrat's, Republicans, Independents, Green Party, Libertarians, and even those unregistered to vote.  ","PLEASE GET OUT AND VOTE NOVEMBER 2nd!"]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a 40+ year resident of Lower Makefield, and the proud parent of 3 Pennsbury graduates, I have been active and invested in the Pennsbury school district for decades. When my children were younger, I served as PTO president at Makefield Elementary for 10 years. As my children grew and moved onto PSD's secondary schools, I became involved as a school board director, a capacity in which I served for 12 years. During this time, I was president, and Vice President, as well as chair of several committees. The combination of my personal investment as a mother of Pennsbury graduates, and my years of community involvement with the district makes me the best candidate for this office. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"What is the top issue facing the school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The immediate top issue is ensuring we get our students back in the classroom for in-person instruction, safely and responsibly. We will need to address learning and mental health issues that stemmed from the past 18-months of the pandemic, all while remaining aware that we are not out of the woods yet. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The district will be guided by the CDC, the American Academy of Pediatrics, and the Departments of Health of both Bucks County and the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. To that end, I support a mask mandate K-12 in all of our buildings, as well as mitigation strategies such as contact tracing and notification of positive cases within the classroom. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, per recommendations of the CDC, the AAP, and county and state governments. Until all of our children are eligible for the vaccine, it is our responsibility to keep them safe. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would strongly encourage anyone who is eligible to receive the vaccine to do so. All three of the vaccines currently offered have been thoroughly vetted, and continue to face rigorous scrutiny and intense safety monitoring. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["The Pennsbury School District has already taken the appropriate steps of hiring Dr. Cherrissa Gibson to serve as the Director of Equity, Diversity, and Education, with the explicit goal of providing an equitable learning environment for every student in our district. We are fortunate to have her as a member of our administration, and I support her position and the very important work she's doing for our community. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["We are not changing the curriculum. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I support the district's policy to provide a safe, supportive, and inclusive learning environment for all students. You can learn more about that policy here: http://go.boarddocs.com/pa/psbr/Board.nsf/goto?open&id=BZ7RMN6CA95D"]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_linda_l._palsky","question":"Would you support a merger with the Morrisville School District? Why or why not?  ","response":["Before determining whether I can support a merger with the Morrisville School District, I need to see the results of a feasibility study. The district is currently beginning this process; I need to keep an open mind with regard to the situation. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["With six open seats, I am one of two candidates running for re-election.  I believe in the value of a Public Education. I would provide institutional knowledge and experience to the new board.  I will continue to support the administration in launching innovative and cutting-edge educational and technology programs. Examples are Full Day Kindergarten, 1:1 Technology Initiative, renovation of Pennwood Middle School and a new 20-year school building renovation plan, JROTC, move to propane buses and Equity Initiative."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"What is the top issue facing the school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Short-term the top issue for me is advocating for resources to increase rigor and academic excellence for all students in post-COVID 2021-22 school year.  Long-term the top issue for me is to promote school practices that foster a safe, supportive, and respectful learning environment for all kids through assisting the new Superintendent to meet Pennsbury’s four-year comprehensive strategic plan’s goals and annual goals."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Three keys – 1. Communicate with parents and staff on issues as they occur by classroom, by building and district-wide. 2. Follow the guidance from Bucks County Health Department, Pennsylvania Department of Education and the CDC on masks, vaccines, social distancing, cleaning and isolation/quarantine.  3. Evaluate the COVID situation on a regular basis and change mitigation protocols as need and make changes."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The primary goal is for Pennsbury to have all students in school five days a week. Yes, teachers, staff and students should wear masks indoors and on buses as part of a holistic plan of wearing masks, encouraging vaccinations, social distancing indoors and daily cleaning to protect each other until everyone can be vaccinated. Families may have children in different grades, relatives with compromised health concerns or multi-generational. With the Delta Variant, the overall approach has changed to protect not just those in school, but throughout the Pennsbury Community. Wearing a mask is both a Patriotic and Humanitarian sign of respect that I do not want to transmit the virus to you. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am vaccinated.  I have and continue to encourage everyone in the Pennsbury Community, not just teachers, staff and students to get vaccinated. Vaccines work. For those who do not want masks, then vaccines must be part of the solution. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["A Challenge: As quickly as you can name the first 5 scientists that come to mind. If you are like most, you probably came up with 5 men. From an Equity lens, just having a teacher add the names of women scientists to the list would be the goal of our Diversity and Inclusion program. A Diversity and Inclusion program has been a part of Pennsbury for decades. So, this issue is nothing new. Pennsbury provides resources for Special Education and Gifted students as part of our Diversity and Inclusion efforts. Pennsbury was first named a National School District of Character in 2015 and each school has been recognized a National School of Character. These recognitions are part of our Diversity and Inclusion efforts to embrace and support every child. Providing social and emotional support for every child, especially during the 2020-21 and 2021-22 school years is part of our Diversity and Inclusion efforts. Making Equity a foundation of the Pennsbury School District is the next logical step.",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The Pennsbury Curriculum is available for everyone to access on the District website.  Changing the curriculum takes years, it is not the issue.  Nor is race and racism.  The focus is how Pennsbury delivers the curriculum.  Any changes are related to creating ways for every student to see themselves reflected in the curriculum and for every student to be exposed to windows to see other people’s cultures, life experiences or achievements."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["The Pennsbury has been at the forefront of the issue for many years.  The Equity Initiative incorporates support for LGBTQ+ students as a continuation of existing policy.  In 2017, I voted for the District's Transgender Policy, which supports the rights of our Transgender students."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_josh_waldorf","question":"Would you support a merger with the Morrisville School District? Why or why not?  ","response":["This intractable issue to incorporate 850 K-12 students is complicated by over half a dozen issues that are hard to reconcile by themselves.  Example, even the simple concept of allowing the Morrisville 9-12 graders to pay Pennsbury tuition could not happen until at least 2022-23 school year as courses at the high school are already set.  Other issues are debt servicing for buildings, staff on different pay scales, increased transportation costs and possible Middle School Redistricting.   The Pennsbury School District has a strong educational program which can support all students, but for me, there has to be long-term tax relief for the Pennsbury School District tax payers to make this work and that financial support has to come from the Commonwealth."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a lifelong reading advocate, community volunteer, trained physician, and passionate about public education, I am committed to using my skills for the benefit of all Pennsbury students. I have the time and energy to devote to the School Board, to support the Pennsbury School District in its mission to prepare “all students to become creative, ethical, and critical thinkers for lifelong success in a global society”."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"What is the top issue facing the school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing Pennsbury is providing a safe and welcoming environment that is conducive to learning, so that all students have the opportunity to reach their potential. To accomplish our goal of providing the best education to all our students will require listening to all stakeholders and synthesizing that information to address the ever changing needs of our community.",""," "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["In order to keep schools open for in-person learning, we need to continue to layer a number of mitigation strategies including: universal masking, vaccination, 3 feet of physical distancing whenever possible, appropriate ventilation, air purification, and effective cleaning of high contact surfaces. Mitigation strategies should be reevaluated frequently and any changes made should be evidence-based."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Everyone entering our schools and our buses should be required to wear a mask at this time, unless medically exempted by their physician. Properly wearing a mask is one of the best mitigation strategies for reducing the spread of the virus that causes COVID-19. At this time universal masking in schools, and on buses, is not only mandated, but is the recommendation of the CDC, the Pennsylvania Department of Health, and our own Bucks County Health Department, and should be maintained throughout the District."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["With the shared goal of keeping our schools open safely for in-person learning, I am in favor of universal vaccination against the virus that causes COVID-19 as a key strategy to ensuring the safest possible learning environment for all our children -- including those with an exemption or exclusion from vaccination."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["To make the Pennsbury education accessible to all students, we need to ensure that the curriculum is representative of the diversity in our community. By incorporating age-appropriate literature that includes fictional characters and real people of diverse backgrounds, we provide an opportunity for students to see life from many different perspectives. Additionally, intentional efforts should be made by the district to recruit and retain faculty and staff who represent the diversity of our community, thus providing our students with role models for success drawn from many varied backgrounds."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Just as we do not tolerate bullying in our schools, we do not tolerate racism in our schools. The only way to prevent racism is to understand what it looks like in its many different forms, so we can identify it. In an age-appropriate manner, the inherent worth and dignity of all individuals should be emphasized in a way that acknowledges and celebrates our differing experiences."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our diversity as a community takes many forms. In order to live up to our shared value of “respect for self and others” and acknowledge the inherent worth in dignity of all individuals, we need to honor each individual’s story. Listening to, and then respecting our LGBTQIA+ community members by using their chosen pronouns, is a necessary first step in creating a safe and welcoming atmosphere in our schools."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_4-year_term_joanna_steere","question":"Would you support a merger with the Morrisville School District? Why or why not?  ","response":["Without knowledge of any specific proposal for the merger of Pennsbury and Morrisville School Districts, there is nothing to support or oppose at this time. To be worthy of consideration, any proposal to merge districts would need to be beneficial to both districts in some meaningful and compelling way."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am running for the position of School Board Director because I care about our children, their education and our community. I have 23 years of experience in education as a special ed and classroom teacher and am currently an Assistant Principal. I can offer a unique perspective as an educator who understands school operations, works with families, and supports teachers so that they can meet their academic goals. I grew up in Fairless Hills and attended Pennsbury from K-12. I believe in the potential of Pennsbury. We need to rebuild our schools for 21st-century learning, equip our teachers with technology and resources to ensure that every child has what they need to be successful, and foster relationships and partnerships with community organizations to coordinate educational services to effectively meet our shared vision.  As a parent in the district, I am concerned about the safety of our children and ensuring that school is a safe place to learn, grow, and engage with others. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"What is the top issue facing the school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our District facilities need attention. Teachers and students are collaborating in spaces that are outdated and unsafe.  Although some schools have been recently updated to support 21st-century learning, other buildings are outdated and have poor ventilation among other concerns. We need to focus resources on updating Pennsbury’s physical plant so that students can learn and thrive in an inspiring and safe environment. I would also work to assist the new Superintendent in meeting Pennsbury’s four-year comprehensive strategic plan’s goals and annual goals.",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The goal is to protect in-person learning and keep our students and staff safe.  We will need to evaluate the COVID situation on a regular basis and change mitigation protocols as needed and make changes based on recommendations from the AAP,  CDC, PDE, PA DOH and the BCHD. We must ensure that buildings and classrooms are well and equipped with HEPA air purifiers recommended by ASHRAE.  ","In addition to addressing the physical environment we also need to be mindful of addressing the mental health of students and staff as we assimilate back into the school environment. In the strategic plan, there is a muti-tiered support system that can be utilized to support staff and students in this transition. Learning gaps need to be identified and specifically targeted supports should be put in place. Long Covid, identified in the DSM V, affects students’ mental health and their ability to engage with learning so resources must also be allocated to support students now and in the future.",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["We must protect in-person learning.  The goal is for Pennsbury to have all students in school five days a week. Yes, students, teachers, and staff should wear masks indoors and on buses, especially when the level of community transmission is high, as it is currently in Bucks County. The plan needs to be fluid and responsive to what is happening locally."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":[" I would encourage all people who are eligible to receive the vaccine to get it.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Pennsbury’s mission: Recognizing our proud traditions and diverse community, the PSD prepares all students to become creative, ethical, and critical thinkers for lifelong success in a global society. Aligning the mission and preparing our students to compete in a global economy with a balanced workforce, PSD should continue its initiatives as a National School Dist. of Character. As a District we believe: a culture of caring is essential for learning• respect for self and others are fundamental because all individuals possess inherent worth and dignity• taking responsibility for one’s actions elevates civility• strong character fosters good citizenship• every child deserves the opportunity to develop their potential to learn & grow. Equity is ensuring that every student has what they need to be successful. Across PSD, roughly 2400 students receive SpEd services, many have a 504 plan or a Gifted IEP. Accommodations commensurate with what these students need are provided. This is equity."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The Pennsbury curriculum was last updated in 2017 and is accessible on the District website. Updating and changing the curriculum takes a long time.  Committees work with a variety of stakeholders to update learning goals.  The delivery of the curriculum should adhere to the standards and create ways for every student to see themselves reflected in the curriculum and for every student to be exposed to an understanding of other people’s cultures, life experiences, and achievements. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["The Equity Initiative established in Pennsbury incorporates support for LGBTQ+ students as a continuation of existing policy.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_lois_lambing","question":"Would you support a merger with the Morrisville School District? Why or why not?  ","response":["This has been a topic of debate since I was a student in Pennsbury.  Currently, I do not have all of the facts to support a decision. It is a complex situation and more information is needed in regards to debt servicing for buildings, staff on different pay scales, increased transportation costs, and possible Middle School Redistricting.  I would start by inviting the Pennsylvania Department of Education to conduct an impartial study to identify issues surrounding the merger.  As an advocate for education, I believe in an equitable education for all students and as a parent and community member in Pennsbury, I will weigh the facts when they are presented."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am one of two candidates running for a 2-year seat in Region 3. I am the best candidate for this office because I have the relevant skills and experience to serve our community and a deep belief in the value of public education and the importance of service and stewardship. I want to volunteer my knowledge and energy to serve the community of the Pennsbury School District. I want to do my part to build the community I want to live in – one that rises above national bipartisan arguments and strives to do what is right for everyone in our district."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"What is the top issue facing the school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our top issue is the need to create a safe, secure, and stable environment where students can learn and thrive. To address this need, I will start by ensuring we are listening to the needs of all our students, staff, and teachers, whatever their zip code. From this informed viewpoint, I will champion the common good in the distribution of our resources across our students, our educators, and our schools while leveraging all available resources to minimize the burden on our community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["There is no “Pennsbury Department of Health,” which means we need to follow the guidelines set by the Pennsylvania Health Department and rely on the latest evidence-based research. In this evolving situation, the guidelines will change over time. At the time I am writing this, current guidance emphasizes implementing layered prevention strategies which should be implemented throughout the Pennsbury district. As the guidance from the Department of Health changes, our policies should be updated to reflect the new guidance as soon as possible."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["We want to return to the classroom as soon as possible, which means we need to follow the guidelines set by the Pennsylvania Health Department. Guidance at the time I am writing this includes universal indoor masking by all (age 2 and older) regardless of vaccination status."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Arguments about the legality of mandatory vaccinations have been occurring for over 150 years.  Nearly 100 years ago, the United States Supreme Court ruled that a school could deny admission to children who failed to provide a certification of vaccination for the protection of the public health. As recently as 2018, the courts ruled that mandatory vaccinations do not violate the right for children to attend school regardless of their vaccination history. Vaccinations to protect against COVID-19 can save lives and have been approved for most people ages 12 and over. I support mandatory vaccinations for teachers and/or students 12 and over, excepting those with medical exclusions. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["I support the Board’s current policy which aims to prioritize fair and just allocation of resources, opportunities, and treatment of students based upon each individual student’s needs. I agree that we should commit to continuous and collaborative effort of identifying various aspects of district programs and operations to this end. We need to take an evidence-based approach and address any gaps our research reveals. We cannot let fear of change prevent us from building bridges to reach all of our students.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["As we examine our curriculum, we should do so with an eye towards inclusivity. We should ensure that what we teach our students includes viewpoints other than our own. As we teach our students the basics, we need to consider not only what we are putting into the curriculum but also what we are leaving out of the curriculum. Pennsbury does and should review its curriculum on an ongoing basis to ensure the success of its students in the modern world. The future success of our students will be dependent upon students having broad age-appropriate knowledge of different cultures, beliefs, and thinking styles, and how these differing viewpoints and experiences impact them and their society. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Current Pennsbury policies should be enforced to ensure gender identity is respected and an environment of inclusivity for all students, teachers, and staff is built. We should ensure district personnel reflect the full diversity of our community. We should prevent bullying and encourage the tolerance of diversity in all its forms. Supporting LGBTQ+ students should be an extension of Pennsbury’s commitment to inclusivity."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_2-year_term_jeannine_delwiche","question":"Would you support a merger with the Morrisville School District? Why or why not?  ","response":["My support or lack of support would be dependent upon the specific details of a particular merger proposal. I would only support a merger if it was beneficial to the Pennsbury community and its taxpayers. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a results-focused business executive, passionate community leader, and a mother of two Pennsbury elementary students, I bring a broad perspective and wealth of experience to accelerate the performance and reputation of our district.  In particular, I am a compassionate voice on behalf of those I serve, I have successfully managed multi-million business turnarounds and budget optimization and, most of all,  I bring the voice of a mother of two Pennsbury students."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"What is the top issue facing the school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["There are several issues that must be our focus in 2021, including addressing inequities in learning created during COVID, ratifying a teacher's contract (expired since June 2021) as well as accelerating overdue infrastructure improvements.  However, in order to make progress, we MUST restore civility, respect and leadership to the Pennsbury School Board. We must move from contention to productive collaboration. We must treat taxpayers, administrators and teachers respectfully while encouraging healthy debate and discussion. School boards function best when they are non-partisan decision-making bodies working to solve local issues on behalf of the community they serve."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Our school must continue to work collaboratively with county health authorities and local leaders to ensure our policies support productive & safe in-person instruction."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["As always, our district policy should take under advisement the latest guidance from both the CDC as well as the Bucks County Health Department for the management of the transmission of COVID-19 in schools - this includes policies on masking.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["As stated above, our district policy should take under advisement the latest guidance from both the CDC as well as the Bucks County Health Department for the management of the transmission of COVID-19 in schools - this includes policies on vaccination requirements for employees (including teachers, support staff and administration) as well as for students."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity is about your unique perspective - embracing all backgrounds, beliefs and the entire range of human experience.  Each of us views the world from a unique vantage point; a perspective that, when fostered, brings value to any classroom.  Inclusion is about creating a deep sense of belonging, where you feel valued, your needs are met and your ideas are heard.  I am committed to ensuring that all of our students have an equal opportunity to succeed academically.  I am also committed to ensuring that our teachers, staff and administration have a workplace to come to every day that embraces these values and actively pursues diversity in our recruitment, retention and training efforts to make Pennsbury THE district to be."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I recognize that  discrimination based on gender, race, religion or socio-economic status does exist in the world around us and may occur in our schools.  I am committed to supporting training and curriculum that teaches respect for others, recognizes the value of the diversity in the world around us, and fosters a sense of inclusion of others regardless of background without marginalizing or denigrating others."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["It is important that we seek to understand the unique needs of our LGBTQIA+ students to ensure we fulfill our commitment to fostering a positive and productive learning environment in our schools for students of all backgrounds.  This starts with understanding what our students need, in their voice, to help fulfill that commitment and then looking at our district policies and practices to ensure that they meet with that intent."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_victoria_czechowski","question":"Would you support a merger with the Morrisville School District? Why or why not?  ","response":["Since this publication first asked me this question in May, there has been no additional data collected on the considerations surrounding a possible merger of Pennsbury School District with Morrisville School District.  In the absence of a thorough evaluation of the key issues and implications, it would be irresponsible to either support or oppose a merger."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["In these divided times, Pennsbury needs common sense leadership.  My experience as a long-time Levittown resident, volunteer, taxpayer, parent to three Pennsbury students, as well as a former Falls Township Supervisor for 8 years, give me the tools needed to represent the taxpayers and students of Pennsbury.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"What is the top issue facing the school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe that funding challenges will always be the biggest issue facing Pennsbury.  The state has consistently reduced the percentage of education funding for decades, shifting  the burden to our local taxpayers.  We must provide a quality education to our students, while also ensuring that we are efficiently safeguarding the needs of the taxpayers.  Once such potential savings could be achieved by aggressively investing in alternative energy sources, such as solar energy and electric vehicles, which would save our taxpayers money while also becoming more environmentally friendly. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I believe that the best place for our students to get their education is with in-person instruction in our schools.  Because of this, I support the adherence to all CDC, State and County guidelines to prevent the spread of COVID.  Prudent precautions allow Pennsbury to remain open- and that should be our primary goal."]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, at this time I support the mask requirement in schools.   We must do everything we can to keep our children and employees safe, while also providing in-school instruction.  A mask requirement helps accomplish both of those priorities.  It is clear, based on published scientific studies, as well as the successful return of in-person education in Pennsbury in the spring, that masks helped prevent the transmission of COVID in our schools.  Likewise, in those districts across the country who refused or were unable to institute a mask requirement (particularly in the South), those districts quickly were hit with a surge in COVID infections, leading to closed schools.  Without a mask requirement in our schools, it is likely that our schools will not be able to remain open. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe that all public employees that interact with the general public, should, as a condition of employment, be vaccinated, subject to medical and religious exemptions.  Therefore, I would support a vaccination requirement for all teachers.  As for students, I do not believe that the school district has the authority to require vaccinations.  Student vaccinations are governed by Pennsylvania State law, which determines what vaccinations can be required in schools.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We must ensure that our workforce adequately reflects the diversity of the students in the district, as well as ensuring that every child in the district has the tools necessary to achieve their idea of success.  Special education needs, race, creed, or economic class should not be a barrier to the school district providing them the resources needed for them to receive a quality education.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["At this time, I do not believe any curriculum changes are necessary, and that any curriculum changes made in the future should be properly vetted and based in fact.  I do not believe that we should politicize education, as has happened in places such as Texas or Florida.  The curriculum should be based on fact and history, not on politics.   History is taught in schools so that our students learn both from the successes and failures of those who came before us.  If we fail to teach the truth, we set up students for failure.  "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I believe that the current Pennsbury policies in place adequately support all of our students, including those who identify as LGBTQ students. "]},{"candidateCode":"pennsbury_school_director_james_prokopiak","question":"Would you support a merger with the Morrisville School District? Why or why not?  ","response":["I do not believe that Pennsbury taxpayers should shoulder the costs associated with a merger with Morrisville, so I do not support a merger with Pennsbury.  The State of Pennsylvania has, for decades, shirked its responsibility to adequately fund schools. burdening local taxpayers. And while all districts, including Pennsbury,  have suffered because of this, smaller districts such as Morrisville have paid a greater price with declining test scores, strained budgets, higher property taxes, and insufficient infrastructure. However, it is not the responsibility of the Pennsbury school board to address the repeated failures of Harrisburg politicians, rather it would be my job to represent the taxpayers and students of Pennsbury.  Based on all available information, I do not believe that benefits of any merger would outweigh the burdens on the district, its students or the taxpayers.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_city_mayor_michael_helfrich","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I was elected to City Council ten years ago. I thought then, and know now, that city government needs to address the social and economic issues that affect our children and families. When we support our families, we reduce violence and crime, improve our neighborhoods, and improve our schools. This vision guides my administration. But, while vision may come for free, experience must be earned. I participated in City Council meetings for 10 years before running for office. This provided me with knowledge in the many aspects of City government. During my 6 years on City Council, I engaged in the budget-making process, drafted legislation, and worked with residents. businesses, and non-profits to help them accomplish their goals. I have now assembled a strong and diverse team that works well together, and for the greater good of all of the people of York. Our team is committed and prepared to work for York City for four more years."]},{"candidateCode":"york_city_mayor_michael_helfrich","question":"What is the top issue facing  the city, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["York’s financial downward spiral began decades ago. In 2020, we saved City taxpayers from a 48% property tax increase and a 41% sewer fee increase with the plan to sell the wastewater treatment system. Many people would have lost their homes and businesses would have closed. We positioned York City to pay off debts and put aside money to help pay growing costs of healthcare and pensions. This does not fix the state taxation system that puts undue burdens on some of the lowest income communities in the state. It does put us in better position than many other cities, boroughs, and even townships. As other municipalities begin to suffer, as we have for decades, the coalition to demand tax reform will get stronger. That is how we address it.","The other top issue is crime and violence. Commissioner Muldrow and I are working every day, not only to improve policing, but to re-establish and activate community centers throughout York City to help steer our young people in a better direction. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"york_city_mayor_michael_helfrich","question":"How will you support business growth in the city? ","response":["I still believe that lifting up children and families, and improving neighborhoods, is the best thing for business in York City. We are about to invest millions of dollars of American Rescue Plan funds in making our neighborhoods safer, mentoring for kids, career training, and helping families. When we lift up families, crime rates go down, people feel more pride in themselves and their community, properties are maintained, streets are cleaner, and kids do better in school. These are all things that are great for business. We need to invest in our people to move York City forward.","We are also working with many partners to stimulate entrepreneurship with grants, loans and free business mentoring. We are supporting the establishment of a Local Sourcing Initiative to connect large industries with local suppliers to grow small businesses. It is time for us all to invest in York City. When we all invest in the city, and each other, the city and her residents and businesses will prosper."]},{"candidateCode":"york_city_mayor_michael_helfrich","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in the city, and how would you address them? ","response":["The City has two infrastructure systems that affect every resident every day – 130 miles of streets and 96 miles of sanitary sewer mains. York City hasn’t had the money to maintain either. When I became Mayor, utilities were cutting into streets, and then paving areas without taking into account the whole street.  Some “repaired” streets were lasting months to a few years before crumbling. Upon recommendation of the City engineers, I changed how we maintain our streets. Now we work with the utilities, get all of the work and base repairs done first, then pave the whole street.  I know we have had some rough streets for these first 3 years, but we will see the payoff. These streets that are getting done now should last for 10 years.","The sanitary sewer system is part of the sale of our wastewater treatment plant.  While we as users of the system will still have to fund maintenance, the new owner should be able to bring economies of scale to reduce the costs of the work that needs done."]},{"candidateCode":"york_city_mayor_michael_helfrich","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in the city? Why or why not?  ","response":["In 2017, I voted yes to changing the possession of personal marijuana to a civil penalty in York City.  I also supported changing possession of paraphernalia to a civil offense.  Too many young people enter the criminal justice system, drastically reducing their chance for future success, due to being in possession of personal marijuana.  As a criminal offense, the charge of smoking marijuana affects education grants, housing, employment, and many other aspects of life.  This penalty not only disenfranchises the individual smoking, it affects our city.  Disenfranchised residents have fewer opportunities for economic success and general survival, so are more likely to commit crimes that could harm other residents, businesses, and visitors to our city.  I believe overall decriminalization of marijuana is a state issue.  I would support this growing trend that has provided large amounts of revenue to state governments with little additional negative social impact."]},{"candidateCode":"york_city_mayor_michael_helfrich","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I will, and already have.  In 2015, with the support of the LGBTQ+ community, I wrote amendments to both the York City Human Relations Commission Ordinance and to the York City Fair Housing Ordinance to add gender identification to the classes protected from employment and housing discrimination.  City Council passed the legislation and Mayor Bracey approved, making it law in York City.  This now provides a level of legal protections for members of the LGBTQ+ community against discrimination that do not exist in most of the rest of Pennsylvania.","While not a protection, as Mayor I am given the privilege to perform marriage ceremonies and I am very proud that I have already performed marriages for gay, lesbian, and transgender members of our community. I support the right of any consenting adults to bond in love through marriage.  I believe strongly that all people deserve to live in an environment free of discrimination, where people are supported in being the best selves they can be."]},{"candidateCode":"york_city_mayor_michael_helfrich","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I think that the battles over legality of mask mandates should be left to the state and federal governments and courts.  I am not expending local taxpayer money to get into fights with the state legislature or other groups with exponentially more resources than our city has.  So, no I will not entertain a local mask mandate. It is my intention to help enforce mandates that come down to us, just as we have been doing from the very beginning.  We will do what we can to create a safe City Hall for customers and staff by continuing our mask mandate in City Hall.  We will incentivize vaccinations among our own employees.  This expense makes fiduciary sense because we are currently losing staff productivity because non-vaccinated individuals must stay at home after exposure. If the spread continues to grow, I will consider canceling or postponing city-sponsored events."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_joe_gothie","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have extensive legal expertise that's been recognized through endorsements and opportunities to teach other legal professionals. ","","First, I was endorsed by the York County and York City Fraternal Orders of Police. Police officers have seen me in court day after day over many years. They are in a great position to assess candidates for judge and me in particular. I was deeply humbled by their endorsements.","","Second, several years ago, the Pennsylvania Supreme Court’s Minor Judiciary Education Board invited me to train magisterial district judges from all over Pennsylvania about defense tactics in some criminal court cases. I was honored that they felt I had expertise that should be shared with hundreds of magisterial district judges across Pennsylvania.","","Third, I’ve taught repeatedly about law and evidence at statewide training sessions for the Pennsylvania Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers, which is the premier legal association for criminal defense lawyers in the state."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_joe_gothie","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["If I am fortunate enough to win this election, there will be 12 other judges senior to me who have their own views of the court system. It is unrealistic to expect they will look to the two newly-elected judges for significant input. I offer my answer based on that reality.","","As a new judge, I can only control what happens in my courtroom. I will work hard, start court on time, bring civility to my courtroom, and do whatever work I am assigned by the President Judge without complaint or ego.","","Beyond my courtroom, I expect the courts to continue to struggle with how to keep the courts working under constantly morphing pandemic circumstances. The upside of this challenge is it provides an ongoing opportunity for the courts to reinvent how they conduct business even after the pandemic abates. Some experiments with technology that were only tried due to the pandemic have been successful and should be adopted permanently to increase accessibility and convenience for the public. "]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_joe_gothie","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["The Judicial Conduct Board of Pennsylvania provides a comprehensive system for addressing judicial misconduct. As a lawyer, I reported one instance of misconduct which resulted in a private reprimand for that judge. The system is adequate for instances of significant judicial misconduct.","","On the other hand, there are many instances of poor behavior which are not easily resolved through the formal discipline system. It is highly unlikely for a lawyer to report judges who are habitually late to the bench or who are needlessly sarcastic, rude, or disrespectful during court proceedings, but that conduct has a corrosive effect on the legal system.","","An annual evaluation system for judges with public and private reports that offers constructive feedback for professional development would be a way to ameliorate some of these problems and bring more accountability to judges. I believe such a program would result in measurable improvement to the quality of our courts."]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_19-1-01_linda_williams","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience as a Magisterial District Judge and a Deputy Sheriff, my reputation as a fair, impartial, and firm jurist, my life experiences and my dedication to continually learn and adapt to better serve the York City community.  I have been a taxpayer and home owner in this community for over 20 years.  My integrity, work ethic, patience, even temperament, and knowledge have earned me the respect of the community, colleagues, attorneys, and law enforcement.  I have an Associates(Paralegal) and a Bachelors(Criminal Justice) Degree.  I strive every day to be fair and impartial in my decisions.  In 2003, I was recognized for my accomplishments and rising above an abusive childhood by being nominated for and ultimately receiving the Essence of Humanity Award.  {This Award recognizes individuals who, beyond the requirements of their work, demonstrate remarkable human qualities including courage, love, strength, determination, and persistence when dealing with adversity.}"]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_19-1-01_linda_williams","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Magisterial District Judges are the “grass roots” level of the Judiciary in Pennsylvania and come from diverse backgrounds, professions and life experiences.  Magisterial District Judges are often not seen as important members of the Judiciary when the opposite is true.  Sometimes, Magisterial District Judges are the only contact citizens have with the Judiciary.  The treatment citizens receive at this level sets the tone for how they view the Judiciary as a whole.  Professionalism, respect, compassion, fairness, impartiality, firmness when necessary and, above all, treating parties with respect are vital components to raise the overall perception of Magisterial District Judges.  I strive to be professional, fair, and respectful with and listen to everyone that comes before me.  It is important for individuals to feel heard even if the decision does not go their way.  "]},{"candidateCode":"magisterial_district_judge_19-1-01_linda_williams","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["Yes.  There are numerous avenues in place for citizens, attorneys and law enforcement to report judicial misconduct.  Litigants have the right to appeal any Judge’s decision up to the Supreme Court.  Judges can also be held accountable through the Judicial Conduct Board which investigates reports of judicial misconduct.  There are penalties for misconduct ranging from censorship to removal from office and criminal charges if the situation warrants them.   Magisterial District Judges in particular have stringent rules of conduct addressing everything from impartiality to the appearance of impropriety to prohibitions against political activity."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_suzanne_s._smith","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My fellow lawyers know that I am hard working and disciplined.  I have been practicing law in York County for almost 30 years.  I am the only candidate with experience in criminal, civil and family law.  I have been involved in both adult and juvenile matters.  I believe that everyone appearing in court should be treated fairly and respectfully.  I believe in honoring the Rule of Law.  I am the only candidate rated as qualified in the areas of professional competence, temperament and integrity by members of The York County Bar Association."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_suzanne_s._smith","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["York County, like many other places, is dealing with an overwhelmed mental health system and the heroin/opioid epidemic.  We know that people dealing with substance abuse and mental health are involved in the legal system.  Addressing these issues as early as possible is key and involvement in treatment is also necessary.  If elected as Judge I will support our Wellness Courts and our involvement in the CARD (Community Action for Recovery and Diversion) program.  We know that treatment and early intervention saves lives and saves tax payer money."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_suzanne_s._smith","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["We need to educate our judges more and educate the community on what to do if you believe a judge is acting inappropriately and needs to be held accountable.  The Code of Judicial Conduct requires that judges act independently, impartially and with integrity.  This Code also applies to judicial candidates.  I believe the majority of judges are following the Code and making good decisions; however, there are exceptions.   Voters need to remember that a judge is different from other elected offices.  A judge needs to be non partisan, independent, fair, impartial, and competent.  In order to maintain independent jurists, we need to elect those who have these qualities.  It is also important to have judges that come from all different backgrounds."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_steve_stambaugh","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["34 years experience, an unwavering commitment to the core principles upon which our Nation was founded, and common sense grounded in a work ethic that was ingrained in me from my childhood."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_steve_stambaugh","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our Nation, our Commonwealth and York County face an onslaught against individual liberty the likes of which have never been seen.  Worse, the Founding Principles upon which our federal, state and local governments are based are being attacked and cancel cultured.  Our governing bodies have lost their way and ignore their oaths to the Constitution.  I will work daily to restore order, sanity, and the Rule of Law."]},{"candidateCode":"york_county_court_of_common_pleas_steve_stambaugh","question":"Do you believe judges are sufficiently held accountable for their actions? Why or why not? If not, what more should be done?","response":["Some are, some are not.  We must have uniformity of the law.  Government bodies can not be permitted to flout the Constitution.  Judges are no different.  At the end of the day, when the executive and legislature branches and their authoritarian police state agencies exceed their authority, the Courts must intervene and not be afraid to enjoin illegal and unconstitutional actions."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_mayor_rebecca_bancroft","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have almost three decades of community involvement in Council Rock Schools, Borough projects, and in Newtown Friends Meeting. I want to take a step forward to become a full-time and fully accessible community leader as Mayor of Newtown Borough. I believe in listening first, finding common ground, and leading with transparency & inclusion.  Building our community hand in hand with our neighbors.   I "]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_mayor_rebecca_bancroft","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The issues that I am most concerned with—public safety and support for small businesses—are issues that years of experience prepare me well to tackle. Support for small businesses. After working as a business manager in Philadelphia, I was a partner in a small business here for 10 years. I will be a mayor who works as a liaison with Borough Council to find new and successful ways to both launch new business and support our current establishments.  ","Newtown has a well-trained, dynamic police force that is always growing and adapting to our community needs.  Working with Chief Sabath to continue good communications between the Council as well as the citizens of Newtown Borough would be my honor.  Our borough website is outdated and could use updating. I also feel strongly about finding ways of accommodating the youth in our community with appropriate gathering locations and activities that give them supervision and occupation while being a part of their neighborhood."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_mayor_rebecca_bancroft","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Newtown Borough could benefit from recruitment of a variety of businesses to add to our quaint downtown.  We have a development that is approved and awaiting the final design phase called Steeple View, that will open up additional business opportunities.  I would like to see an organized approach to introducing Newtown Borough to businesses from other areas of Bucks County, New York City, Philadelphia.  We could enrich our special seasonal activities to increase foot traffic and more regular visitors to our business district."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_mayor_rebecca_bancroft","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Newtown Borough has Grant money arriving in the next two years to update one of our busiest intersections.  Some more updated street lighting could be used to unify our downtown.  Also, our downtown State Streetscape could use an update to define the shopping and restaurant area."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_mayor_rebecca_bancroft","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As Mayor of Newtown, it is important to support our Police Department as they adhere to current PA Laws regarding marijuana.  I do believe with the current trends across the country to create more equitable policies with regard to marijuana arrests and penalties.  Currently Pennsylvania marijuana law, possession of up to 30 grams is a misdemeanor is subject to a fine of $500 and 30 days in jail.  However, since 2014, Philadelphia, Harrisburg and Pittsburgh have decriminalized possession of small amounts of marijuana and instituted $25 fines or those caught smoking marijuana are given a citation for a $100 fine."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_mayor_rebecca_bancroft","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I strongly support LGBTQ+ protections and would continue to offer leadership on the borough level by participating in both national and local county events, parades and  enforcement of policies that protect LGBTQ+ rights.  Any opportunity to demonstrate being an ally to our LGBTQ+ community members is an honor for me."]},{"candidateCode":"newtown_borough_mayor_rebecca_bancroft","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["It is important for Community Leaders to follow the CDC guidelines and act as a good example by following them.  Masks play a part in protecting the vulnerable members of our community from COVID-19 and whatever variants are circulating. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_jeff_hollenbach","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Being born and raised in Perkasie, I have deep appreciation for the quality of character, commitment to community, and the caring nature of its people. This community has deeply impacted me and I feel called to serve.  As Mayor of Perkasie I want to help this wonderful community remain a safe, secure, and enjoyable place to live. I bring a wide variety of leadership experiences to this position including many years as an educator, Pennridge Head Football Coach leading a large staff, being the lead person in a new church start up in a local community, involvement in a number of non-profits including RamPacks - an initiative to support local families that experience food insecurities, and most recently as a church administrator leading a staff of 10 people.  I have been described as  positive, energetic, caring, reasonable, encouraging,  and possessing a desire to help people come to the center in helpful ways. I believe my experience and abilities would benefit the community."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_jeff_hollenbach","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The balance of new local development and maintaining the special history and character of the community.   I will support the business owners, both new and those that are not new, with energy, and a listening ear.   I am also interested in achieving a good balance between those that are excited about progress and development, and those that desire stability, character, and strong appreciation for the rich history of the community."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_jeff_hollenbach","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Between our engaged borough council, active borough staff, and the energetic individuals of the Perkasie Town Improvement Association, Perkasie is blessed with dedicated and thoughtful servants committed to supporting local businesses – not to mention our terrific businesses themselves. It is my goal to be added to that team. As mayor, I would want to work alongside of them in listening to, being aware of, and considering new initiatives that seem reasonable for the community. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_jeff_hollenbach","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":[" As one of only 35 municipalities in Pennsylvania with its own electric department, Perkasie is uniquely positioned to serve as an infrastructure leader on this front. That means managing rates for residents, supporting our electric department staff, and continuing to invest in efficiencies and resiliency programs. In addition, as mayor I will support the borough’s roadwork plan and encourage additional annual investment in our roads, trails, and walkways. "]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_jeff_hollenbach","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While I would listen to those that advocate for decriminalization, my inclination would caution about such a step. Drug issues in our culture are significant often detrimental to individuals, families, and our community as a whole. I acknowledge that the medicinal purposes are real and helpful to some, but I would have concerns about the possible long range and negative impacts of recreational usage."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_jeff_hollenbach","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["As mayor, I will serve all Perkasie residents regardless of race, color, national origin, religion, or sexual orientation. The LGBTQ community is – and must continue to be - afforded the same protections and privileges that any American is afforded under the laws of our constitution: protection of property, and the privilege of living under the guidance of life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_jeff_hollenbach","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would listen to the local and federal recommendations for this topic, using those as guidelines for appropriately responding to the challenges of COVID. Hand in hand, I believe the borough must continue to work with individuals, businesses, and organizations to ensure the impact of any mitigation efforts are considered and addressed in a manner that keeps residents safe but respects our local businesses and allows for an active and engaged community."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_sean_mcvan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My family has been in Doylestown since the 1800s, my father was a former borough councilmember. I grew up here and truly care about the borough. I believe I can bring a new young perspective to the office and the challenges we face going forward. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_sean_mcvan","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing Doylestown Borough is overdevelopment. I do not want to see Doylestown lose that small town feel it has always had. I want it to continue to be a safe, quite and clean place where families can raise their kids and where residents can enjoy what Doylestown has to offer. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_sean_mcvan","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["As mayor I will support initiatives that will help small businesses in the borough. I believe we need to continue to have nights where we block off traffic and allow outdoor dining for our restaurants. These nights bring more folks into the town and help all businesses.  "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_sean_mcvan","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["In order to truly solve the infrastructure issues in the Borough we need to stop the current overdevelopment. Out of control development puts an unnecessary strain on our infrastructure and harms our quality of life in the Borough. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_sean_mcvan","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["While I personally believe Marijuana should be legalized, I don't believe the Borough has the authority to decriminalize marijuana, and these issues should be left up to our state lawmakers. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_sean_mcvan","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support equal protection for all Doylestown Borough residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_sean_mcvan","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Dr.Damsker and the Bucks County health department have done a great job keeping our families safe during the pandemic. We should continue to follow the guidance of our local medical experts. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_mayor_mary_anne_girard","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["One of the many responsibilities of the office of Mayor, and the one that I consider most important, is to act as the liaison between the community and the Council.  If fortunate enough to be elected, I plan to walk the streets of the borough and engage with the people on a more personal level than it has been in the past. I will seek their input and provide them with the opportunity to influence the direction the Borough takes.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_mayor_mary_anne_girard","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["In talking with my fellow residents, many were concerned by the lack of communication and responsiveness between themselves and local government.  All of the Democrats on the Borough ticket are committed to promoting greater communication and transparency.  We pledge to respond to questions from our fellow residents in a timely manner and to explain the reason behind the answers.  Better communication results in a better informed community.",""]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_mayor_mary_anne_girard","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["The best way to support the growth of Borough businesses is to patronize those businesses; I would use any influence I have as the Mayor to encourage just that. Of equal importance would be to publicize the availability of grants to local businesses to fund small projects and business events through the Hatfield Economic Revitalization Committee (HERC).",""," "]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_mayor_mary_anne_girard","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Investment in infrastructure is an investment in the future of our community. The challenge facing the Borough is how to accomplish the planned work within the structure of the budget.  The pandemic has impacted Borough revenues; in order to ease budget shortfalls, we must reduce expenditures and increase revenue without placing a heavy burden on our community members.  Prioritizing the order of capital improvements based on necessity and costs could also help us in attaining our infrastructure goals.",""]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_mayor_mary_anne_girard","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["In speaking with my fellow Borough residents about various topics that concern them, this matter has never come up. Since it doesn’t appear to be a borough issue, I prefer not to address at his time."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_mayor_mary_anne_girard","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In speaking with my fellow Borough residents about various topics that concern them, this matter has never come up. Since it doesn’t appear to be a borough issue, I prefer not to address at his time."]},{"candidateCode":"hatfield_borough_mayor_mary_anne_girard","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":[" It is absolutely imperative that the children return to the classroom for their schooling; it is also  crucial that the schools provide a safe and healthy environment for the kids. The parents, School Board and local health officials should join together to determine the best and safest course to accomplish these goals.  I would support their consensus decision in this matter. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_mayor_noel_sperry","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I’ll be a Mayor who will oversee police operations, work with the Borough Council, be your voice at meetings, & actively promote our community. Public safety is one of the greatest concerns in any community. I will work with our police chief to pursue traffic & speed control solutions & promote community engagement programs.  Strengthening the bond between the community & our police department will be my highest priority. As an active member of the MBA & LBCCC I’ll use my network & contacts to help grow our business community. My work experience includes employee supervision & management, project management, & marketing. I’m Municipal Police Supervision Certified, have no criminal convictions, & an understanding of Borough Code & Mayoral responsibilities. A Mayor needs to be a DOER & I’ll continue my involvement with ongoing projects, local organizations, & support local events. I am the candidate who truly has the experience, qualifications, & commitment to be Morrisville’s Mayor."]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_mayor_noel_sperry","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Setting aside our past differences and openly working together for the benefit of Morrisville. This includes building a closer bond between our municipal police department and the community through community outreach programs and events. By establishing a community watch program and encouraging neighbors to look out for each other and report suspicious activity, we would greatly assist our public safety officers.  With the residents and our public safety officers continuing to engage each other, we will be better able to continue working for a safe community.  We are better working together for a safe, growing, & beautiful Morrisville. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_mayor_noel_sperry","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will use my experience working all types of businesses including my own, contacts, and network, to work closely with the Morrisville Business Association, Morrisville Economic Development Corporation, Lower Bucks County Chamber of Commerce, Borough Manager, & Council to attract businesses by highlighting the benefits and advantages of opening in Morrisville. I will work with the Chief of Police to schedule a walking officer for the business districts and check in with local business owners on a regular basis. Our business community would greatly appreciate the added security and it would be a safe presence for our town. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_mayor_noel_sperry","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["While it is the responsibility of the Borough and Council to plan and maintain infrastructure in Morrisville, I will attend meetings, actively participate, and present ideas that will enhance the safety and comfort of our residents while walking and driving through town.  I will also use my knowledge and experience in the telecommunications industry to make sure that Morrisville will be able to reap the benefits of the growing 5G infrastructure without diminishing the beauty of our town. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_mayor_noel_sperry","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As Mayor I would guide the municipal police department to uphold all Sate and Federal laws associated with controlled substances. It is not the Borough Council or the office of Mayor that creates these laws, we are merely here to make sure that they are enforced without prejudice. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_mayor_noel_sperry","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support ALL citizens of the United States of America being afforded the same rights and protections equally without prejudice or bias under the constitution and by law. I would expect the same from our Municipal Police Department and community. I would ensure that the requisite de-escalation and crisis intervention training would be implemented to manage issues in a respectful manner without placing the public and our safety officers at unnecessary risk. "]},{"candidateCode":"morrisville_borough_mayor_noel_sperry","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I would encourage people, schools, and businesses to follow the guidelines and mandates set out by the CDC, and State and Federal governments. It is a fluid situation that is constantly changing and must be monitored regularly and adjusted in accordance with public safety while not placing undue stress on our residents and businesses."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_mark_moffa","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["New mayoral leadership is needed if the borough is to truly change for the better. It is for this reason that I challenged the incumbent mayor from my own party in the primary election. I'm honored that the voters emphatically nominated me in the spring, and I'm looking forward to earning your votes again this fall.","","The primary results show a desire for change. I am the only candidate for mayor who can deliver the change that is needed and still work alongside the current Borough Council to be productive and move Penndel forward.","","I'm not running to remind you of what Penndel used to be decades ago. I'm not running to preserve a legacy for me or my family. I'm not running to settle a political feud, or to convince you that you should make your choice based on party affiliation. I'm not running to be someone who yells, exaggerates, and grandstands at meetings. ","","I'm running because I honestly feel this is the best way for me to use my skills to make the greatest positive impact."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_mark_moffa","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The revitalization of our business corridors is the top issue facing Penndel. As the figurehead of the borough, I will provide the strategic, practical and representative leadership needed to aid revitalization efforts. ","","For example, we've just had a significant sale of 24 and 50 Hulmeville Avenue, the old Perma-Bilt Furniture Mart by the bridge that is being reconstructed. I invited the new co-owner to a meeting of the borough's Revitalization Task Force, so that he, our task force, our new manager, and the county planning commission could meet for the first time and begin to form a working relationship that will be key to the success of the development. (But instead of embracing the possibilities and working together, my political opponents decided to rudely confront the developer with false conspiracy theories. This is why we don't have nice things.)","","A vote for me is a vote for progress, and against the negativity that has prevailed for too long. I will fight for positive change. "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_mark_moffa","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Our floundering Business Route 1 corridor is an example of the failure of \"the way things have always been done.” Through strategic connections and partnerships, and my close collaboration with our Borough Manager and our Borough Council, I will help bring new life to Penndel’s business district.","","Already, we have accomplished a lot. Just last year, amidst a paralyzing pandemic, I spearheaded efforts at Borough Council to pass three major pieces of legislation: ","1. Massive zoning relief and incentives to encourage revitalization. ","2. An earned income tax to recoup our dollars that were going to other towns.","3. The hiring of a manager to run the borough more effectively and help lead revitalization efforts.","","​So we're already moving forward. We're already working smarter. And now, the borough is in the process of reaching out to each of our existing businesses with information on how to expand and improve, and an offer to help them do so. We've even just reduced certain permit fees."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_mark_moffa","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The Borough Council spends a lot of time, money and effort focusing on our infrastructure needs. This council has received grant funding to help with significant and badly needed improvements to our sewer system, has accomplished a lot recently, and has a plan for future upgrades. ","","Council is also always planning for future road pavings, and currently is trying to revise the borough's procedures for how curbs and sidewalks are dealt with when roads are repaved.","","For Business Route 1, council has been working with PennDot on plans for major improvements at two of our intersections that will improve safety along that corridor. ","","As mayor, I would continue to support these ongoing initiatives in any way possible. "]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_mark_moffa","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes. Decriminalizing drug possession, and instead investing in treatment and harm-reduction services has many benefits for public safety and health, including fewer arrests and incarcerations; increased uptake into treatment and recovery services; the ability to redirect law enforcement resources to prevent serious and violent crimes; and lower criminal justice costs."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_mark_moffa","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. I support full protections against discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity. This includes prohibiting discrimination in private employment, housing, and public accommodations. I would support seeing Penndel join the list of Pennsylvania municipalities on this page: https://www.lgbtmap.org/equality_maps/profile_state/PA","",""]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_mark_moffa","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, because I believe in science and saving lives. "]},{"candidateCode":"_christopher_p._harding","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My record as Mayor shows my desire and willingness to act as a voice for the residents of Yardley Boro.  From hosting town hall meetings, to debating difficult decisions, I have and will continue to listen to our residents and share their concerns and views with Yardley Boro officials.  Also, during my past eight years as Mayor, our community has faced numerous difficult community situations such as high-water events, police emergencies and power outages.  I am confident I have the proven leadership skills required to help lead the Boro through these difficult and challenging situations."]},{"candidateCode":"_christopher_p._harding","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Yardley Boro is an ever growing and changing community, both residentially and in the business sector.  It is important for our community leaders to continue to recognize what continued change can bring to a community, and to properly plan for all that comes along with growth.  Whether it be working on filling business vacancies, welcoming new businesses, helping our current business get through the current difficult times, maintaining a police department that is best prepared to address the growth, or helping our residents with their concerns regarding our development as a community, I am ready to go to work."]},{"candidateCode":"_christopher_p._harding","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We are blessed to have multiple business-related groups in Yardley Boro that do an excellent job in working with our businesses.  Whether it be the Yardley Business Association (YBA), Experience Yardley, or our other local and state officials, as Mayor I will continue to work with these groups.  In addition, I will continue to speak directly to our business owners and provide them the opportunity to promote their business on the “Yardley Boro On Air” radio show that I host twice a month.  Supporting successful business growth in Yardley Boro is and needs to be a group effort."]},{"candidateCode":"_christopher_p._harding","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Yardley Boro is a “River Community”, and with that comes beauty, but also challenges.  Storm water management is our largest infrastructure concern.  Back flow preventers along the river waterways, home elevations in the flood zone areas, flood water mitigation throughout our streets, canal and river maintenance from the North end of the Boro to the south end, and emergency procedures that protect lives and property are all critical to prospering in a river community.  Our resident’s safety and their ability to safely enjoy where they live should remain a top priority."]},{"candidateCode":"_christopher_p._harding","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["With the recent actions of our neighboring state of New Jersey regarding the decriminalization of marijuana, I believe Pennsylvania will soon follow the same path.  Whether it be marijuana or alcohol, my primary goal as Mayor is to keep the residents and visitors to this community safe.  Proper enforcement of our current (and future) laws is of the upmost importance.  If these laws change as the states begin to take a new stance on marijuana, it will be important for Yardley Boro to recognize the change and continue to work to provide a safe environment for all."]},{"candidateCode":"_christopher_p._harding","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes.  I am proud as Mayor of Yardley, to have officiated numerous wedding ceremonies for members of the LGBTQ+ community, and I will continue to do so.  Yardley Boro needs to remain a community where everyone is and feels welcome.  As Mayor I recognize the small role, I can play in ensuring our community is a place where we protect everyone’s rights to live and thrive as they choose."]},{"candidateCode":"_christopher_p._harding","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Through the current COVID pandemic, Yardley Boro has followed the State’s guidelines regarding required precautions and safety directions.  I do not see this community, or the community’s leadership deviating from that path at any point in the future.  At the same time, I recognize everyone has their own individual rights. We need to continue to be a community that diligently works to offer viable options to each individual to safely enjoy all Yardley Boro has to offer."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_val_ridge","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a lifelong resident of Bensalem Township of 55 years. The majority of my life has been given to public service. As a decorated Bensalem police officer my priority is and always will be public safety. I want to reassure the community that I will stop at nothing to make sure Bensalem first responders are given the tools needed to be the best they can be. In 2000 I was honored to be named the National and local police officer of the year for my efforts implementing safety protocols as the school resource officer in the Bensalem school district. As your mayor I will reach across the aisle and work with anyone who will work with me to get the job done. We need to work together as one community, not a divided one. Bensalem is a wonderful place to live and I feel like I will add a fresh perspective and move the township forward. It’s just time Bensalem!"]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_val_ridge","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The single most pressing issue our township is facing, is a decline in business operations resulting in vacant properties. It is my intention to place a pause on business/land development in order to re-purpose existing properties. It is like the broken window theory. If you allow strip malls appearance to decline the ones nearby will follow. If strip malls upgrade their appearance owners will want their businesses there. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_val_ridge","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Bensalem has many empty store fronts and we need to think out of the box. I will create an advisory team to do just that. We need to figure out ways to help businesses thrive. To move Bensalem businesses forward we must modernize the Street Road corridor.  Also, with the world of online shopping we need to give our local businesses the tools necessary to succeed as a brick and mortar business."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_val_ridge","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Bensalem is in serious need of upgrading the storm water management in many areas of the township. There has been an ongoing erosion of our storm water infrastructure. These upgrades don’t happen overnight. Developing a 3,5,10 year strategic plan is essential to keep Bensalem moving in the right direction. With a strategic plan we can prioritize areas of concern and allocate proper funding in the areas of concern. I will also review that township building codes are updated where appropriate."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_val_ridge","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I am in full support of medical marijuana. It has been proven that cannabis when used correctly is beneficial for medicinal purposes. State legislatures need to take a hard look at other areas of the country which have decriminalized marijuana over the past several years and look at the pros and cons before passing this. Ultimately Harrisburg will make the decision and not local government."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_val_ridge","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes I support the LGBTQ+ protections. I fully intend to push for a non-discrimination ordinance in Bensalem. Previously Councilman Ed Tokmajian  and Jesse Sloan attempted to present a non-discrimination ordinance however the other three councilman rejected the idea. It is extremely important to have a government that represents all residents of Bensalem. It will be my goal to diversify our government to reflect our residents. Our residents deserve to be equally represented. "]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_val_ridge","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["As mayor my top priority would be public safety. I am not a medical expert so I would continue to follow what the medical experts are recommending.  "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_mayor_ken_rouse","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":[". Langhorne Manor Borough is, along with much of the country, divided along hard party lines. As an Independent, I back good ideas, not ideas from a particular political Party. ","It's beyond time for someone who can comfortably stand in the middle and arbitrate, or, if necessary, stand up to political pressure and move through gridlock and finger-pointing to help move things forward.","My professional experience in solidifying support from disparate stakeholders and creating a vision that unites, rather than divides, would be invaluable in this position and in helping to create an environment that allows us to work more closely with our neighbors, who are confronting similar issues to ours. ","My background is decidedly blue collar and my education: Holy Ghost Prep, Drexel University and the Wharton School, have all prepared me to have a broad-based world-view of people, without prejudice or pre-conceived perceptions"]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_mayor_ken_rouse","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our top issue is existential. Our Borough must decide what we want to be and to whom, for a 10, 20, and 30 year plan and then begin all the work that takes us there. I have lived in the Borough for more than 13 years and my neighbors and I have never been asked what our vision of the future looks like. We feel that new leadership and vision is needed. This is the main reason that I decided to run for Mayor.","Emergency Preparedness is another one of the more serious issues that seems to move weakly forward and without as much coordination and cooperation as there could and should be. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_mayor_ken_rouse","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Langhorne Manor is a residential Borough covering a small geographic area. Although we don't have much in the way of business growth opportunities, it would be in our best interest to support business growth in the surrounding boroughs of Langhorne, Penndel and Hulmeville. Those businesses are patronized by our citizens and we could help in getting the businesses and jobs that we need. That is not currently being done. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_mayor_ken_rouse","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Infrastructure like roads and bridges have come to the forefront locally, regionally and nationally and we need to make sure that we receive the infrastructure and financial support that feeds into a long-term plan for our citizens. Cooperation and planning with the neighboring Boroughs strengthens our voice and power. Currently, we are in the midst of a major change to Rt. 1 and our most important bridge that was suddenly closed because it was literally crumbling and as I have met with our residents they have described a process that has been less inclusive, informative and creative than they had expected."]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_mayor_ken_rouse","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["The Marijuana laws need to specify levels of intoxication, especially when driving, before they are considered. All Rights come with Responsibilities.  Responsible people understand this. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_mayor_ken_rouse","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["All citizens should have the same opportunities and protections under the law, regardless of any group affiliation. Fair for one, fair for all. Some specified groups require additional legal protections and additional scrutiny of processes to insure that we are doing our best to be fair, to follow the law and to provide every Constitutional protection that can and should be afforded.  ","That also requires that we are always on the lookout for nepotism, unbid contracts, statutes and variances that favor -or even APPEAR to favor- or exclude citizens because of their \"connections\" (or lack thereof) or political affiliation. "]},{"candidateCode":"langhorne_manor_mayor_ken_rouse","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["As someone who works in Healthcare and in particular, Infection Prevention as well as  Critical Care, I have been asked to wear a mask in almost every setting. Like most people, I don't find them comfortable, but as someone who believes in Responsibilities first, I would support mandates that are based on vetted science, data and an expected, communicated positive result, benefit or improvement resulting from any restriction. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_hope_borough_mayor_frank_deluca","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I offer 34 years of experience as a  police officer and six years as the Borough’s Constable. I have worked closely with six police chiefs and five mayors in ensuring the safety and security of a New Hope’s residences and businesses community. I am certified in crisis intervention and trained as an elder abuse investigator. This has enabled me to foster positive relations with the community at large.      I’ve always wanted to make a difference in my community through volunteerism and in service to others. I’ve been on the Boro’s Shade Tree Commision for the past 20 yrs. I offer my time and service at my local church with Peace Meal, feeding those lest advantage. I am member of H.O.P.E. (Helping Other People Everyday) driving local seniors to doctors appointments and shopping errands. I’ve also volunteered with Code Blue, keeping the homeless in Bucks County warm during winter months.     I am confident that I can serve as Mayor for the betterment of New Hope.     I’ve always wanted to make a difference in my community through volunteerism and in service to others. I’ve been on the Boro’s Shade Tree Commision for the past 20 yrs. I offer my time and service at my local church with Peace Meal, feeding those lest advantage. I am member of H.O.P.E. (Helping Other People Everyday) driving local seniors to doctors appointments and shopping errands. I’ve also volunteered with Code Blue, keeping the homeless in Bucks County warm during winter months.","    I am confident that I can serve as Mayor for the betterment of New Hope."]},{"candidateCode":"new_hope_borough_mayor_frank_deluca","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic after the impact it has had on our business community, residents, and children returning to schools is the number one issue that I would like to address it head-on. Parking, traffic and noise are also issues requiring attention.      As mayor, I would strongly encourage vaccinations and mask wearing as recommended by organizations like the CDC. We are still in a crisis stage with COVID-19, and to get through it as quickly as possible, we have got to work together and proactively as a team in fighting this virus. As for traffic, I will partner with the chief of police to have officers increase foot patrol as well as restart the bike patrol unit. We have four devices to measure the volume of sale. I would encourage that all officers trained in the use and they have the bike patrol officers carry them on the weekends. Parking has always been an issue, and I’ve been monitoring the progress of the three story parking garage off of W. Bridge St.     As mayor, I would strongly encourage vaccinations and mask wearing as recommended by organizations like the CDC. We are still in a crisis stage with COVID-19, and to get through it as quickly as possible, we have got to work together and proactively as a team in fighting this virus. As for traffic, I will partner with the chief of police to have officers increase foot patrol as well as restart the bike patrol unit. We have four devices to measure the volume of sale. I would encourage that all officers trained in the use and they have the bike patrol officers carry them on the weekends. Parking has always been an issue, and I’ve been monitoring the progress of the three story parking garage off of W. Bridge St. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_hope_borough_mayor_frank_deluca","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["New Hope was named the prettiest town in Pennsylvania by architectural digest (July 2018). We are recognized for our arts, historic charm, lodging, dining and quaint shops along the Delaware river and Canal. We are also the number one tourist destination in Bucks County. I would encourage our borough officials to reach out to businesses and residents, working from a clear vision of what we want our towns future to be. I’d like to see the water return to our empty Delaware canal and bring back the barge rides as a tourist attraction. In order to sustain a thriving business community, we must create an economic development plan to maximize our strengths while minimizing our weaknesses. It’s critical that we have those residents and the business community working together as one. We must also look closely at oversize development in our town. We need to find a balance that preserved New Hope‘s old world charm that makes it a top destination while keeping it moving forward."]},{"candidateCode":"new_hope_borough_mayor_frank_deluca","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["As a River community, New Hope has always been prone to flooding. With climate change causing more severe storms, our town will inevitably see more damage from flooding and High winds. I will work with the chief of police and the fire department to make sure residents know how to best secure their property and prepare for these storms so they can weather them safely, with as little damage as possible. Second, as I mentioned above, the borough is currently exploring the possibility of adding a multi-tiered parking garage to the town. As mayor, I will make sure residents are aware of the plans and can have input.Second, as I mentioned above, the borough is currently exploring the possibility of adding a multi-tiered parking garage to the town. As mayor, I will make sure residents are aware of the plans and can have input."]},{"candidateCode":"new_hope_borough_mayor_frank_deluca","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Outdated marijuana laws simply do not work. As a former officer I’ve learned that arresting  and incarcerating people for possession of small amount of marijuana has not helped reduce the use of the drug. In fact it wastes an enormous amount of police resources. Decriminalizing marijuana will allow officers to concentrate their efforts on violent crimes. Marijuana criminalization has led to the mass incarceration of predominately black and Latinx people. Nationwide, a black person is almost 4 times more likely to be arrested for marijuana possession than a white person even though people of all races use the drug at the same rate. I am of the position that our marijuana laws need to be downgraded to a summary offense, avoiding possible incarceration. Our prisons are overcrowded as it is, and a recent gallop poll found that 68% of people support making marijuana use legal. Marijuana use is far less dangerous then opiates and alcohol and no one has ever died of a marijuana overdose."]},{"candidateCode":"new_hope_borough_mayor_frank_deluca","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In 2002, New Hope was the first Borough in the state of Pennsylvania to pass a landmark ordinance protecting LGBTQ citizens. I supported this ordinance and was appointed as New Hope Borough’s LGBTQ liaison officer. My mother and I lead the first New Hope Celebrates Gay Pride parade back in 2004 and it done so every year until 2014. We both authored our story of how we came to live in a town we love in a book entitled “Embraceable You”. My husband and I have supported several LGBTQ events in our borough throughout the years and we are proud of our story of how we came to live in New Hope and that we want to remain a truly inclusive community."]},{"candidateCode":"new_hope_borough_mayor_frank_deluca","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Absolutely! We must balance the safety of our community along with economic recovery. Public health experts show that by wearing masks properly indoors can slow the spread of the COVID-19, and masks are specially important when there is a high community spread. If mask wearing helps keep schools and businesses open, I will support mandates as recommended by the state and the CDC. Of course, I will never support restrictions just for restrictions sake. Instead I will look to well respected scientists and public health experts at the local, state, and federal level for guidance."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_jeffrey_gilmore","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have either lived in or worked in New Britain Borough every day of my life. I served two terms on New Britain Borough Council from 2011 through 2019. I spent two of those years as council president. During my tenure on borough council I created the Appointment Advisory (AAC) and the Financial Advisory Committees (FAC). The FAC, of which I am a current member, brought much needed oversite of the financial operations of the borough. I was instrumental in developing a plan for economic development of the University Village area. I currently serve on the Planning Commission, which recently submitted a similar plan for the west end of the borough. I have been an advocate for community involvement in the borough and have served as the Chairman of the Community & Business Committee.",""]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_jeffrey_gilmore","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Fiscal Management - the borough operates on a very tight budget and does not have sufficient capital reserves. The FAC have proposed a plan to build the borough's reserves to an acceptable level. It is critical that borough council adopt said plan and manage the borough's finances in accordance with the plan.","Responsible Economic Development - 5 years ago, under Republican leadership, borough council changed the modus operandi of the planning commission from being simply reactionary to being proactive. The planning commission is now focused on improving the economic wellbeing and quality of life in our community. It's imperative that we maintain this focus","Equality - The best way for us to solve our need for diversity is by increasing our involvement with minority groups and by engaging our friends. We can also achieve this by encouraging more young people to vote. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_jeffrey_gilmore","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["We need to ascertain that we have the right zoning in place. Every community needs a mix of residential, commercial, educational, industrial and open space. I helped lead the effort to modify the zoning ordinance for the east end of the borough, allowing the property owners to use their properties for both residential and commercial purposes. As a member of the planning commission, we have proposed a similar ordinance for the west end of the borough. Both ordinances will promote future business growth."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_jeffrey_gilmore","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["With the exception of the one state road in New Britain Borough, our local roads are in sound condition. that is due to the FAC's efforts to secure funding that allowed the borough to resurface all of it's roads within the past 3 years. The remaining major infrastructure hurdles that the borough faces concern public water and walkability. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_jeffrey_gilmore","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I'm not in favor of New Britain Borough passing any ordinances that decriminalize marijuana or reduce the penalty for the use of it. That is because state law trumps any local ordinance, and police departments can determine what emphasis marijuana arrests can be, without a local ordinance. The DA's office already diverts those caught with a small amount of marijuana through a treatment program. Upon completion of that program, the case of the marijuana user is dismissed. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_jeffrey_gilmore","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I have no tolerance for any form of discrimination against anyone. I also have no tolerance for brutality of any kind. I am in favor of protecting the rights of all citizens equally."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_jeffrey_gilmore","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Like most people, I don't like wearing a mask. At this time I believe that wearing a mask is a matter of individual choice. I currently do not support government mask mandates.  However, I do support businesses and institutions having the right to require their patrons to wear masks. All of that being stated, I would strongly consider supporting a government mask mandate if COVID cases continue to increase. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_kelly_laustsen","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a parent, small business owner, and active member of the community.  I love Perkasie and the people who live here.  My business survived the pandemic because of the incredible support of our residents. I wish to pay back my neighbors with public service.","","I am an active member of the Perkasie Town Improvement Association.  PTIA works alongside the borough and local businesses to promote fun and unique events in our community.  I love seeing our town’s center when families gather to enjoy music, food, and entertainment.  A sense of neighborly fellowship leads to a safer, happier, and more prosperous borough.","","I have the background and knowledge required to successfully interface with businesses, local government, and volunteer organizations.  I am an open and approachable person who loves to help people.  I want to make the borough work better for the people and empower citizens to have a greater stake in local government.",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_kelly_laustsen","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue in any borough is a moving target.  It is impossible to predict what the primary challenge will be when the next mayor takes office.  I can only speak for the present.  Perkasie is currently grappling with the aftermath of a devastating flood.  Helping citizens recover and acquire critical resources is something that is important to me.  I understand the limits of what local government entities can do in these situations.  I believe in hybrid solutions that involve both locally-organized volunteers and borough officials.  Connecting the energy and passion of community members with government resources is the most effective way to tackle unprecedented problems.  I have experience with both and I know that I would be a very effective advocate for the people of this community."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_kelly_laustsen","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I am a small business owner in Perkasie borough.  I started a flower shop with very limited resources.  I bet my family’s financial future on a dream and a strong belief in the strength of this community.  It has not been easy, but it has been extremely rewarding.  I have an unmatched understanding of the challenges that small businesses face in Perkasie.  If we want local business to survive in an era of Amazon and big box stores, we would be best-served to adapt to current times.  I believe that the borough needs to rethink the various fees it places on our business, especially new ones.  I believe doing so would pay tremendous dividends and promote growth.  While the mayor does not have much legislative power, he/she does have the ear of borough council and the political capital to make suggestions.",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_kelly_laustsen","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["The safety of borough roads is major concern of mine.  I believe that we should continue to make improvements in how quickly hazards, such as potholes, are addressed.  I also believe that infrastructure should include preserving and expanding our beautiful bike and walking trails.",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_kelly_laustsen","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["It is my personal belief that the federal and state legalization of recreational marijuana is likely inevitable. I also believe that enforcing marijuana laws is not the best use of law enforcement resources.  If adults use marijuana in the privacy of their own homes, and do not cause a nuisance to their fellow community members, I think the best policy is to simply let them be.  That said, I have the strongest respect for our local police Chief and trust that he will enforce all laws with wisdom and an appropriate level of discretion."]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_kelly_laustsen","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I am very proud of borough council for their progress on this issue.  I fully embrace the LGBTQ+ community and promise to be a strong ally.  I want all people to feel welcomed, embraced, and safe in Perkasie.",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_kelly_laustsen","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe this is an issue that is out of the scope of mayoral authority.  I will make the personal choice for my family to follow guidelines of the experts that we find to be most qualified.  As a business owner, I would strongly encourage citizens to respect the wishes of private establishments.  If a store or restaurant policy requires masks, I believe customers should either abide by that request or simply take their business to a different establishment."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_mayor_timothy_j._schultz","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I believe I can bring our business and resident communities together to grow our town in a responsible, ethical and sustainable manner."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_mayor_timothy_j._schultz","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Responsible growth.  I plan to work diligently with the Council and its committees to ensure that we develop our town with adherence to our history and ensure open space for the future."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_mayor_timothy_j._schultz","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will continue to promote Hatboro as an attractive location for all businesses.  I will also continue to promote our \"small town\" charm by organizing events through the Greater Hatboro Chamber of Commerce."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_mayor_timothy_j._schultz","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Flood control and planning.   I would make sure there is responsible development adhering to current zoning and promote the acquisition of open space in and around our waterways."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_mayor_timothy_j._schultz","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes.  Its time to recognize the decriminalization of marijuana."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_mayor_timothy_j._schultz","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes.  Hatboro has already adopted an LGBTQ ordinance that protects the rights of ALL individuals.  I stand for inclusion of ALL people in our community.  "]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro_mayor_timothy_j._schultz","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes.  I believe in science and our experts in the Health field.  Masks are a tool to limit contagion of a deadly virus.  Its simple, not political."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_timothy_w._main","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a Bensalem resident of the last twelve years, I felt now was the best time to have a new voice heard in the political arena. I also wanted to show the people of Bensalem that they have a choice, outside of the duopoly, at the municipal, county, state, and national levels.   ","","My home is in Bensalem and I would like to see positive changes in the community.  As a third party candidate, I have the ability to collaborate with all sides and find the best solutions for Bensalem."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_timothy_w._main","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing Bensalem is fiscal responsibility.  Bensalem residents need to know that their tax dollars are being spent responsibly to address the needs of the community and achieve our common goals. ","","As Mayor, I would direct a thorough review of all the financial records of the township, and fund distribution, with an eye toward complete transparency.  I would like to see the budget list a line item for every expenditure, including all salaries for the township.  This will enable us to better understand where we can eliminate unnecessary spending, and reduce taxes appropriately."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_timothy_w._main","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I will work to strike down unnecessary regulations that stifle businesses.  I would welcome business owners to work with myself and others in the municipality to make progress on these issues."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_timothy_w._main","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["In light of the recent weather emergencies, we need to review the municipal infrastructure in those areas hardest hit by the recent flooding, and proactively design an action plan for disaster relief for the residents of Bensalem Township.","","We also need to put pressure on the state to complete the Street Road infrastructure as it is the major avenue of travel throughout the township."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_timothy_w._main","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["As a Libertarian, I support the decriminalization of marijuana.  I support and individual’s freedom of choice in this matter."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_timothy_w._main","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I support all individuals’ rights to be true to themselves honestly and openly.  I do not support any policy that creates a disparity of one group over another."]},{"candidateCode":"bensalem_township_mayor_timothy_w._main","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I support the rights of all individuals and private industry to choose what is best for themselves, their families, and their businesses, without the use of force by the government.  I am against mandates instituted by government which infringes upon personal liberty.  I believe personal liberty and rights never come secondary to the strong arm of the state."]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_noni_west","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My candidacy for Mayor is based upon my commitment to the whole health and well-being of Doylestown Borough. We have a wonderful town filled with history, cultural institutions, diverse businesses, organizations who care for those in need and residents who volunteer. We also have challenges moving forward; environmental change, lifestyle/economic changes, and infrastructure/technology changes.","I would bring Doylestown-specific experience in governance to the role of Mayor. For twelve years I have served on Borough Council and currently serve as Vice President and Chair of Finance. I have served or participated in every committee of Council, serve on the Regional Police Commission and am part of the COVID Recovery Task Force.  My thorough understanding of the inner workings of the Borough have uniquely prepared me for the role of Mayor as outreach director, strategic planner, and public safety czar. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_noni_west","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The Borough’s desirability as a place to live is bringing development, affecting neighborhoods, infrastructure, affordable housing, and more. My knowledge of the Borough’s zoning and infrastructure needs will be valuable to Borough Council and staff as we pursue an updated and community-informed Comprehensive Plan.","Updating the Borough’s Comprehensive Plan will entail not only a review of our zoning ordinances but also our environmental sustainability goals including storm water management, out water utility, traffic/transportation, our business environment, emergency services and issues the community identifies as important.",""]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_noni_west","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["The Borough as well as our business community and non-profits have suffered revenue shortfalls and changes in consumer buying patterns resulting from the COVID pandemic. The Borough has formed a COVID Recovery Task Force, of which I am a part, to respond to and assist our retailers/restaurants during the pandemic and adjust to changes of the future. Based upon the COVID emergency declaration the Borough was able to waive ordinances and allow outdoor dining accompanied by pedestrian walking zones. The approach has been beneficial to our businesses and for our visitors/residents. The Borough is currently in the process of revising our ordinances to allow similar approaches that will continue after the COVID pandemic. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_noni_west","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Currently our attention is on storm water management and our water utility. Should everything go as planned the Borough will address our storm water management mandates from the state within the next few years.  We are also in the process of replacing/upgrading water mains in the north section of town. The Water Department just completed a leak assessment of the system. As with all communities and water utilities, the only drawback to infrastructure upgrades is cost. The Borough is continually pursuing funding that will assist and reinvesting the revenues generated by the department in capital expenditures. "]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_noni_west","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["In April 2021, Doylestown Borough decriminalized small-amount possession of marijuana by passing an ordinance that directs the Central Bucks Regional Police Department to issue a non-summary violation and a $25 fine when a person is arrested in the borough for marijuana possession under 30 grams, which is currently a misdemeanor under state law.","In case you are wondering I voted to approve the ordinance.",""]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_noni_west","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["In August 2010 Doylestown Borough passed an ordinance protecting LGBTQ+ individuals from discrimination in employment, housing, and public accommodations.  Council also formed the Human Rights Commission where resident/individuals can report discrimination and the Commission will administer oversight. Council also wrote a resolution encouraging the state to enact the same LGBTQ+ protections.","The ordinance was passed unanimously. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"doylestown_borough_mayor_noni_west","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Doylestown Borough Hall is adhering to CDC masking recommendations.  During the past year and a half, the Borough has not issued any mask mandates. We have relied upon public education and signage from both the Borough and our businesses. Although there has been an uptick in COVID cases, both zip code 18901 and Bucks County are well below the number of weekly new cases that were generated during the Fall of 2020 and Winter of 2021. ","The health and safety of Borough residents, visitors and staff is important to us. We held an open-air vaccination clinic and follow Bucks and 18901 cases on a weekly basis. At this point there is no plan for a mask mandate and the most optimistic outlook is there will be none. ","As of writing this answer, new cases have significantly shifted to ages 0-19.",""]},{"candidateCode":"richlandtown_borough_mayor_iolanda_logan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I believe that I am the best suited candidate for borough Mayor due to my dedication to the borough.  I have been on council for several years as well as the planning commission, fire/police liaison, organizing events such as, the 20 year 9/11 anniversary candle night vigil as well as bringing back the neighborhood watch committee.  I am able to balance my professional life and family life to provide for the needs of the community.  I take the needs, concerns, and voices of the residents seriously and try to reach out to as many resources as I can so that their voices can be heard.  "]},{"candidateCode":"richlandtown_borough_mayor_iolanda_logan","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe our top issue is listening to the residents voices more and helping with their concerns.  Currently, if residents are having an issue with another resident, the belief is to have them resolve themselves.  I believe that sometimes that can bring more issues and resentment and I believe that as a council member we need to help the residents if they are asking for it.  That is one of the reasons why I am bringing the neighborhood watch committee back as a resource for the residents to anonymously reach out with their concerns via our updated website."]},{"candidateCode":"richlandtown_borough_mayor_iolanda_logan","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["I am a strong advocate for people who want to enter the business world.  Having the experience on the planning commission I feel, gives me extra knowledge to help guide residents with their growth so that they can have all the resources that they need to grow within the community while following zoning rules and so on. "]},{"candidateCode":"richlandtown_borough_mayor_iolanda_logan","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["A major infrastructure need is communication networks. As previously mentioned, I am working with the council President in creating a submission form for residents on our updated website.  This form with be for residents to fill out with their contact information or anonymously and they will be able to list any concerns, requests and recommendations.  "]},{"candidateCode":"richlandtown_borough_mayor_iolanda_logan","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"richlandtown_borough_mayor_iolanda_logan","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["My job on council, as well as if I were to become Mayor, is to do what is best for ALL the residents.  We cannot single out any residents, our job is to be available for every resident, listen and help with what we can.  "]},{"candidateCode":"richlandtown_borough_mayor_iolanda_logan","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_matthew_d._lynch","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Being involved with the people, businesses and all areas of Perkasie government throughout my career as electric lineman for the Borough and working with various organizations over the past 45 years I feel deeply connected to the people and our community. I am proud to be a resident of Perkasie and I will work hard to keep us safe, promote community spirit and maintain our unique history. Being chosen as your mayor would give me a chance to give back to a town that has given so much to me!",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_matthew_d._lynch","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["When I speak to the residents of Perkasie, I get asked what are the most important issues facing the community in my opinion? ","","Five issues come to mind: Traffic, Development, Preserving our unique history, Small Business Support and Volunteerism.","","All of these concerns are important to the community and need consideration. For the safety of our residents we need to slow down traffic. I have lived in Perkasie for 45 years, in that time our community has seen a lot of development.  Responsible development is good for our economy and supports local business.  Perkasie is such a special town rich in history it is important to preserve it.  Finally, I would promote Volunteerism it is vital for our community to thrive","","I will work with both the Borough Council and Police Department to address these and other concerns that may arise. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_matthew_d._lynch","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_matthew_d._lynch","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_matthew_d._lynch","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_matthew_d._lynch","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"perkasie_borough_mayor_matthew_d._lynch","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, but I feel that it is a personal preference."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_james_d._donovan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My willingness to listen to the residents of New Britain and volunteer my time and efforts so our local government can help when and where it's needed."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_james_d._donovan","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Support of our local businesses I believe is the top issue right now. To find ways for local businesses to communicate their needs that will make them more successful, which in turn benefits the community at large. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_james_d._donovan","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":["Open line of communication is the key to most problems. To be transparent in our governing and listen."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_james_d._donovan","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Addressing the ever increasing need for better roads and smoother traffic. Try to work with our surrounding communities to stay ahead of problems and address them quickly."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_james_d._donovan","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe that to be a state wide issue better addressed by the Governor and the legislature."]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_james_d._donovan","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["Yes. I want this to be a community that welcomes the person and stops judging based on outdated ideas of the word normal. "]},{"candidateCode":"new_britain_borough_mayor_james_d._donovan","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe if we are diligent about how we handle ourselves in public places, respect the notion of personal space, and think about how each of us would feel if we contracted this or any other contagious illness and spread it to someone else, the issue would be settled simply."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_thomas_c._sodano_jr.","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I grew up in Penndel Borough, and my wife Barbara and I moved back here a decade ago. I am not, and have never been a politician at heart. I'm not a hand picked minion of some Doylestown political machine sent here to gain political experience in preparation for a run for a state or federal position. I'm a husband, a father, a grandfather, an American, your neighbor and a concerned citizen of Penndel Borough. Our country's form of government relies on a system of checks and balances to keep it of the people and for the people. Currently, all elected Borough positions are filled by members of the same party. I think one party rule breeds a feeling of being above the law, clouds the judgement of those in power and brings out the politicians who have put their own goals and agendas before the greater good. I am a fiscal conservative who doesn't believe in tax and spend policies. I will bring Leadership, not Partisanship, to the office of Mayor of Penndel Borough."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_thomas_c._sodano_jr.","question":"What is the top issue facing your municipality, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Penndel is facing a financial crisis. The current administration enacted an exorbitant EIT in an attempt to balance our budget. I will do everything in the power of the Office of Mayor to reign in the irresponsible spending of the resident's hard earned dollars. We need better communication between our elected officials and the constituents, regardless of political party affiliation.  I will make myself available to all the Borough residents, all the time. I offer my personal contact information to all Borough residents, and will encourage other elected officials to do the same. I will be fair and impartial and promise to treat all residents with the same honesty and dignity they deserve."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_thomas_c._sodano_jr.","question":"How will you support business growth in your municipality? ","response":[" I have managed a small business in Penndel as well as retail and wholesale facilities for a national big box chain, giving me the experience and knowledge to work with businesses of all sizes to bring back a positive business climate along our downtown and Route 1 corridors."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_thomas_c._sodano_jr.","question":"What major infrastructure needs do you see in your municipality, and how would you address them? ","response":["Our ageing storm and sanitary sewers are being stressed well beyond their limits. I will support measures to find and eliminate problems and abusers. I will not only support and work hard to aid acquiring grant monies for this area, I will also support efforts to keep sewer funds for that purpose only, not to pay other bills. And I will work with Borough Council to have a pro-active plan to keep our streets in a better state of repair."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_thomas_c._sodano_jr.","question":"Would you support measures to decriminalize marijuana or loosen penalties in your municipality? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe any municipality has a responsibility to uphold the laws of the state. When Pennsylvania decriminalizes marijuana, and I believe it will do so in the not so distant future, I will wholeheartedly support it. To do so in defiance of current state laws could expose the Borough to unnecessary legal issues."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_thomas_c._sodano_jr.","question":"Would you support LGBTQ+ protections on the local level? If so, what would they be?  ","response":["I am a supporter of LGBTQ+ rights, as my daughter and her wife can attest. I do not ever support special consideration of any group over any other, regardless of race, color, creed, religious or political leanings or sexuality. My only exception to this belief is the physically disabled, whom I believe deserve any considerations we can offer to help in making their daily life less difficult."]},{"candidateCode":"penndel_borough_mayor_thomas_c._sodano_jr.","question":"Would you support local mask mandates or other restrictions if COVID cases continue to rise? Why or why not?  ","response":["I think masks and other restrictions should be mandated at the county and state level, and we should comply. Small municipalities do not have the financial ability to employ the health experts necessary to support and institute such measures. Doing so could expose a municipality to legal issues in the event of a challenge to our mandate. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I believe that my experience in the urban and suburban school setting combined with my professional leadership experience provide me with perspective to contribute in a meaningful way in an effort to prioritize the maximizing of educational outcomes, supporting initiatives that foster 21st century pedagogy, and becoming a more financially responsible district. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I believe that the biggest issue facing both the short term and long term district success is the lack of appropriate prioritization of capital projects versus initiatives that would better benefit student needs. I believe that all financial decisions need to be re-evaluated to determine what effect each investment has on student performance in their academics first with peripheral programs occupying a lower priority."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I believe that districts need to understand that the significant gaps in educational quality need to be closed as soon as possible. To that end, every reasonable effort needs to be made to guarantee that schools remain open for in-person instruction. Though remaining open is paramount, implementing protocols in place to make the building safe are necessary including daily disinfection of classroom spaces, opportunities for outdoor classroom experiences, and the use of 3 feet of social distancing should be integrated. In addition, there should be a significant effort made to address the increased concerns surrounding mental health and student emotional support."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["This is a sensitive issue as there are reasons for many children and teachers to be exempted from masking procedures. Between the academic needs in early learners, needs for learning support students, & medical needs of the staff, there has to be for these cases to remain unmasked. ","There are concerns related to effects of masking which are documented in the ","Journal of Orthopaedic Translation in the July 2018 report which highlights adverse effects of masking related to pathogens introduced to the mask wearer. Ireland’s Department of Health determined that they wouldn’t require masks in schools because they “may exacerbate anxiety or breathing difficulties for some students.” Another consideration is that children attempt to compensate for the masks by breathing through their mouths which can cause additional medical issues including impairment of maxillofacial development. For these reasons, as well as the minimal infection rate in children, I understand desires to not mask children."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Until these vaccines have been thoroughly tested with long term guarantees of no side-effects, it should remain voluntary. To be clear, I am all of my family have been vaccinated and I would prefer everyone to seriously consider it as the best method of combatting COVID as the number of deaths and serious hospitalizations have reduced significantly despite the Delta variant in comparison with this same time last year but to mandate vaccines at this point would be irresponsible and violate people's Constitutional Right to privacy and choice."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity and inclusion are often viewed through cultural and racial lenses but need to include our special needs population, our English Language Learners, and our migrant populations. We need to celebrate the beauty of cultures around the world and embrace a school community that takes pride in all of its citizens. I believe an overall philosophical approach needs to shift where learners of all backgrounds feel welcome to participate in all programs that meet their needs in our schools and in a manor that provides as much equal access as is possible. I believe that districts currently look at the discussion from an emotional perspective but we need a content driven approach as well. Offering coursework that embraces the exploration of cultures from around the world, providing classes that allow for LGBTQ+ students to have a voice is essential, and allowing our learning support children to access as much of the curriculum as possible is a must."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Students need to be aware at age appropriate times of challenges that marginalized populations have experienced in history. We do still need to reinforce the incredible opportunities that our nation provides. I believe that there is a percentage of those that feel a need to correct the injustices of the past in the quickest manner possible. This can be problematic for our youngest learners who cannot and should not be exposed to those concerns. Higher level secondary students should be able to have a deeper conversation about the complexities of social justice. We need open dialog about curriculum as there are topics that are excluded and that should have a place in our classrooms (red-lining, true purposes of Monuments, and the dark history of some of our founding fathers). The introduction of significant racial discussion at an early age opens a doorway to content not appropriate for our young ones. AP courses and Universities would be a better environment to discuss these topics."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_frederick_froehlich","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["We need a firm commitment that our schools are safe and welcoming to every student and that they should be allowed to be their true self as they see fit. Schools are supposed to be a melting pot of sorts for all sorts of children and every one of them should be confident that they will be accepted every day. Policies that protect these children from aggressors as well as adverse treatment by staff and educators should be in place and reinforced. In addition, students should feel secure in their decision to share their private information with their teachers and know that these educators are there to support them and maintain confidentiality. In terms of outreach, clubs and organizations are currently a part of our district and are a great way for students to gather with peers who may have similar perspective. In the end, the schooling experience for all kids should be a positive one and an inclusive one."]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am a long-time resident of the township who believes in full transparency and inclusion.  Our community is small enough to allow for everyone to have a voice should he/she/they want it.  I am highly experienced in making data driven decisions to create long-range plans and budgets.  With my strong professional background in government contracting and my deep understanding of school policy gained as a citizen/parent and spouse/daughter of teachers, I am well positioned to ask the difficult questions and make logical assessments.  Lastly, I believe in the democratic process and understand that we must act together to do what's best for the greater good which will prepare our students to become productive members of society.    ",""]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our district is growing, and we must be better prepared to take this on.  Our facilities are out dated and over crowded.  As we take on major construction projects, we need to be careful that these facilities are not out dated when they open or shortly thereafter.  With this growth also comes more than just numbers but also various student needs.  We need to make sure that facilities, staff, and curriculum meet these needs.  Just as a baseline, this should be addressed though continual monitoring of real estate development throughout the township.  Although there were listening sessions during last school year, this program must be overhauled to be statistically significant, fully transparent as to the goals, and needs to be conducted on a more regular basis with the entire community and not just students.  We need to make better decisions using information obtained from students, families, teachers, guidance counselors, and administrators.  "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["There needs to be a continual monitoring and reasonable handling of this and any health/well being situation.  There was additional cleaning of our facilities last year and extra people brought in to do it.  That's not the case for the upcoming school year, and that is a mistake.  Whether there is COVID or not, our schools need to be kept cleaner!  We also need to make sure that our facilities are properly outfitted for good hygiene practices.  That means there must be ample soap in the restrooms and paper towels, hand sanitizing stations, and cleaning supplies readily available.  "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["For now, students and teachers should be required to wear masks inside for the very simple reason that not all of our student population is eligible to be vaccinated.  It also needs to be extended to administrative staff and building visitors.  "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["At this point, anyone who wants to be vaccinated is.  Anyone who does not wish to be vaccinated should not be required to be unless at Pine Road since those students do not have a choice due to their age.  If there are Pine Road teachers who are not vaccinated and do not wish to be, then they should be required to undergo frequent testing until their students are eligible to be fully vaccinated. Those unvaccinated at Murray Avenue or the High School have assumed their own risk and there does not necessarily need to be a testing protocol at those buildings.  "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Only after issues were brought to a wider audience on social media did we receive communications from the administration that there have been multiple incidents involving our students.  We were told of plans to hire a diversity consultant for $7500 and not provided with much more detail.  ","","While these are issues that are ugly and no one wants to address them, they must be and not just when they blow up on social media!  Hiring a consultant was very reactionary and really just a minimal response that was lacking transparency. ","","Faculty and staff must not turn a blind eye to any incidents of racism or classism. Students need a safe way to report such incidents.  Racism and classism need to be addressed in a  student code of conduct as well and clearly stated how such incidents will be addressed. "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Our students at all levels need to be aware of race and racism at age appropriate levels.  To ensure that our students appreciate the diversity of our country and community, we should integrate into our curriculum a celebration of the differences between people and hold special programming for levels K-12 with age appropriate material!  By better focusing on the American experience, our students will be more prepared as civically engaged adults.   "]},{"candidateCode":"lower_moreland_school_director_pamela_lipschutz","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Lower Moreland should be a place where all students should feel that they have an opportunity to succeed.  The school should encourage and celebrate the diverse community of learners that make up our community.  Each individual student should feel safe, and that they have a voice which will be heard by teachers and administration.","","Teachers, guidance counselors, and administrators need to be aware and sensitive to all student populations.  Just as there are workshops and in-services about other student issues, this too should be addressed on a regular basis during the contract-mandated in-service time.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I currently work at a school. I work as IT Support and teach technology, research skills, and moderate the student DEI group. I have the unique view of working closely with students, teachers, administrators, and parents in nurturing and preparing children for adulthood. I also am on the board for Upper Moreland Free Public Library, The Choristers, Equity Alliance for Upper Moreland, and AAPI Montgomery County PA. I am very active in Upper Moreland, as well as surrounding areas. I have worked with the Peace Center in Bucks County, facilitating community discussions on diversity, equity, inclusion, and building understanding between law enforcement and BIPOC youth. I believe in helping people. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The most imminent issue affecting the school district is health and safety during the pandemic. Currently, the district has a comprehensive plan that has requires masks for Substantial and High transmission risk scenarios, and recommended for other lesser risky scenarios. The most important thing we can do is monitor the situation as closely as possibly with our public health experts, so that we can be flexible to make sure our kids stay in school as much as possible while still maintaining health. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The current comprehensive plan is to require masks indoors, during substantial and high transmission, while only recommending at all other times. I don't think there is a better compromise."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Health experts are recommending that wearing masks helps to keep infectious disease, including COVID from spreading. Since there is no vaccine for children under 12 yet, this seems to best way. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["As long as there is no medical reason not to, it would be in the community's best interest to take steps to keep any infectious deadly disease from spreading within such a close knit environment, much like prior mass infectious diseases such as small pox. We should rely on peer reviewed science-backed public health advice."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Currently, there is a Diversity Task Force in the district. I believe that our district should have a diversity professional that helps steer this committee and work to make sure we aren't just putting on band-aids where we need stitches and fix systemic issues."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe that knowledge is power. It has the ability to break down barriers between race, which in turn is a remedy to racism. We need to teach our children that America, as great as it is today, has had a painful history that has not been properly addressed and we are seeing echoes of that pain to this day. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_a._tom_hasani","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["I think each school should have student support group where LGBTQIA+ students, teachers, and allies participate to help students, and address issues that exist in the community. There should also be education around LGBTQIA+ so that students, parents, and teachers can understand how best to support the community. Gender neutral bathrooms, and requiring faculty and staff to use their pronouns. Would also be a good start. We can also hand a rainbow flag on campus."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As a first-generation college graduate I am passionate about education and ensuring that our district reaches its full potential. Throughout my career in higher education I have a proven track record of supporting and advocating for students and teachers. I have also worked in a team environment throughout my life as a scholarship athlete at Penn State, a professional athlete in the Toronto Blue Jays’ baseball organization and a senior leader at Temple University. My experiences position me to serve as an effective member of our School Board, and have equipped me with the necessary skills to contribute to our district’s quest in providing every student with the opportunity to grow and reach their educational goals."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Top-4 Immediate Priorities","1. An immediate needs assessment to determine how COVID has impacted our students (academically, mentally, socially, emotionally) and teachers/support staff this past year,","2. We need to positively reengage parents into our schools to cultivate and strengthen these partnerships and find ways to encourage parent/student advocacy,","3. We need a swift and comprehensive analysis of our school rankings and make a contemporary plan for the future, while continuing to advance equity work,","4. We need to bring local businesses and business leaders to the table to connect them with the district -- connecting local business with education."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Our school district should be committed to the well-being of all members of our community and understand that we all play an essential part in the effort of keeping our community safe. Our district should develop a COVID-19 mitigation and containment strategy by following recommendations from public and local health agencies -- this should include layered prevention strategies such as promoting vaccination, masking protocols (when necessary), practicing good hand hygiene, physical distancing (where appropriate), health monitoring, testing and tracing, and preparations to respond to a rapidly changing situation. "]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Due to the surge in delta variant COVID-19 cases as well as updated guidance from public health agencies masking should be required in schools to help prevent the spread of the virus, avoid a disruption of in-person education and keep our community safe. Making masks optional will not only leave the unvaccinated and vulnerable populations at a greater risk but it may also disrupt in-person education and create segregation in our schools, which can have an adverse social, physical, and psychological impact on our students.  "]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Since the vaccines have not all received full FDA approval and state law does not currently include COVID vaccines as required for attendance I believe teachers and students should have the choice of being vaccinated. It should be promoted and strongly encouraged among those eligible (and not exempt due to medical or religious reasons) but I do not believe it should be required until the COVID vaccine has been added to the state's school immunization requirements per state law and department of health. This is why it is critical to implement layered mitigation strategies in protecting the health and well-being of our community."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["All children living in the United States have the right to a free public education in an environment that fosters respect, open-mindedness and the appreciation of others. Research has shown that students thrive in a learning environment that promotes a strong sense of belonging anchored in diversity, equity, and inclusion. Therefore, I believe school districts have a moral and legal responsibility to foster a strong DEI school culture and learning environment that promotes equitable educational practices and policies that are designed to accommodate differences in the contexts of students' learning and not to simply treat all students the same."]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":[" I believe our schools or teachers can and should teach:","- developmentally appropriate concepts like empathy, kindness, and respect for others","- narratives of people from a wider range of racial, ethnic, religious, and cultural backgrounds","- students to be civically minded, civically responsible, and civically engaged","- how to counter forms of intolerance and discrimination against people of color, LGBTQ individuals, people with disabilities, immigrants, religious minorities, and other marginalized groups","- diversity of our world, identities of all cultures and to be globally minded"]},{"candidateCode":"hatboro-horsham_school_director_shawn_fagan","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["- promote safe spaces within the school community ","- promote respect and appreciation for others","- develop LGBTQ+ student organization ","- professional development and workshops to help educate faculty and staff and to ensure our district is inclusive and safe for our LGBTQ+ youth and community"]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["In addition to having two children who are current SASD students, my wife, Sarah, and I have lived in the district for 17 years, and I've been a teacher for 20 years. Our family is very involved in our community, volunteering in the schools and at the Shepherd's Shelf in our church, participating in Scouts, and playing and coaching youth sports. I am the candidate who can represent the widest range of our district's stakeholders, as a parent of students, a resident, a taxpayer, and an experienced educator. If elected, I would bring the experience of a career in public education to the table and work with the other board members to help them make more informed policy decisions.   "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["We are in the midst of a global pandemic, so our school district needs to trust its school directors to protect the health and safety of its students, teachers, and staff. The school board is comprised of people who care about our schools, our budget, and our community, but they are not medical experts or public health officials, so we need to trust that these elected directors will be listening to the recommendations of the experts and not the loudest voices in the room. Furthermore, a school board should be representative. In our community, there are many people who do not find representation on the current board. A strong, healthy school board should consist of a cross-section of the community, so everyone is able to be represented. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["While school boards need to consider logistical, financial, and communal factors unique to their school district, they are mainly tasked with putting children’s needs first, so we must hold them accountable to seek out and act on expert scientific advice in order to make informed decisions. These decisions should not be based on public opinion, but should be made while working closely with local experts. The ABC Science Collaborative is a good model, where scientists and physicians are paired with school and community leaders to help understand the most current and relevant information about Covid-19."]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["This depends on the data. Wearing masks, along with other steps to mitigate the spread of Covid-19, should be required when called for by current data within the school district. In periods of substantial or high transmission, CDC recommends community leaders \"encourage vaccination and universal masking in indoor public spaces\" in addition to other layered prevention strategies to prevent further spread. However, school board members must be prepared to adapt and pivot as guidelines change, being prepared to follow the advice of national, state, and local health experts in order to keep our students safely in schools. Evidence suggests that many K-12 schools that have strictly implemented prevention strategies have been able to safely open for in-person instruction and remain open. Our school board members should work with local physicians and scientists to ensure their policies are in line with the current recommendations in order to keep our students in school.",""]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["While I believe vaccinations against Coivd-19 are essential to reduce the spread and stop the introduction of new variants of the virus, this is not a decision for local school boards. All 50 states have legislation requiring other specified vaccines for students. At this time, no state requires children to receive the COVID-19 vaccine for school entry. While this may change, that decision should be in the hands of the state health department."]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Our school district has a lot of work to do with diversity, equity, and inclusion. Fortunately, the Pennsylvania School Boards Association (PSBA) has outlined a framework for school boards in our state to follow. The first steps involve conducting a true audit of our current data and practices, where we involve as many of the stakeholders as possible in a frank and honest assessment of our needs. While the process begins with conversations identifying where we are, it does not end there. Equity is not just a statement... it’s policy. It doesn’t end with conversations. You can’t just stop at the framework. There is no equity without systematically embedding equity into the school district’s structure. It takes leadership at the school board level to make sure equity is not just a one-time in-service day discussion, but it is the foundation for the entire school district."]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["School board members should avoid the temptation to succumb to the latest trends in curricular activism, and should instead look to the education experts in the district to determine curriculum, as past practice dictates. That is not to say that curriculum should not be frequently reviewed, but board members must ensure that these reviews are conducted by a diverse cohort of stakeholders from the district who will work with educators and administrators to review proposed curricular changes.     "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_scott_p._swindells","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["LGBTQ+ students face various challenges because of how others respond to their sexual orientation or gender identity/expression. Sadly, suicide risk in LGBTQ people is extremely elevated, and is thought to be highest during the teen years and early 20s, according to the Fenway Institute. As a health and safety issue, school board members must ensure policies exist to prohibit discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity/expression."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I will do my best to bring the North Penn community together through balanced policies and opportunities for more positive and productive community input. I believe that board members have a responsibility to bring the community together through balanced policies and representation. I believe parents are the experts of their children, that teachers are the keys to children’s success, and that success can unite a community. I pledge to make fiscally responsible decisions that will fuel academic excellence, and fight to keep tax increases below the Act 1 index. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Improving academic facilities while","being fiscally conservative is one of the top challenges NPSD is facing. The first thing I will do is push for a grade level structure plan to go into effect with the completion of the ninth grade center, and do my best to create opportunities for positive and productive community involvement in that process. I will then call to re-evaluate the 10-year facilities plan based on the conclusion of grade level structures, push to allocate ESSERS funds into facility improvements within the guidelines, and ensure that every penny is spent with the purpose to strengthen academic success in our facilities. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I have to say that North Penn is going above and beyond health and safety measures recommended by the CDC, Unions, Dept. of Health and County Commissioners to address COVID. I would like to see the district go above and beyond to work with parents. I would like to address the lack of A/C in schools and outdated HVAC systems that make learning conditions more unbearable with mandated masks. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["There is a lot of division when it comes to masks. Health and well-being are imperative  for academic success. I believe parents are the experts of their children’s health and safety, and their input should valued and taken into great consideration.  For months, parents have presented the NPSD board with valid data from the CDC, Montgomery County Board of Health, JAMA, and peer reviewed studies from other countries, that challenges the benefit/risk ratios of masks. One public comment that has stuck with me the most came from a nurse who suggested to require masks during high transmission activities like walking in the halls, but allowing masks to be optional in low transmission activities such as sitting at a desk. This seems to be a reasonable solution that most people could reasonably agree with, and that I would be happy to support. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["No to vaccine mandates. This is a new vaccine, only one is FDA approved beyond emergency use. We don’t know long term effects, and the fact is (per the CDC) that the seasonal flu is more harmful to children under the age of 17 than Covid. I believe every individual and family has the right to do a benefit/risk analysis and make the best decisions for their health. I am all for making vaccines accessible for those who want to get it, but it should be a choice. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["North Penn is one the most diverse districts in the county, it is also a leader in Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion. Along with a history of academic excellence, diversity is one of the reasons we chose to raise our children here. I believe that we should support and give teachers and staff tools they need to ensure that all cultures, abilities, and backgrounds are respected, valued, and have the opportunity to excel. I want to ensure  that positive and productive environments are promoting the academic success of ALL students. I also want to see students in special education have academic experiences that maximizes their potential. I believe that parents should have access to view online lesson plans and assignments, to help ensure that divisive elements such as privilege walks, racial privilege or oppression topics, stay out of classrooms, unless it is a relevant educational topic which promotes critical thinking not just theory among ages that can rationally process such issues. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Creating safe, positive, and productive environments that promotes respect for diversity, and forming and enforcing firm and fair behavior and anti-bullying policies from day one in all schools helps curb racism in schools and beyond. It’s important to understand black history from slavery to the civil right’s movement, so we can continue to learn, do better, and not repeat past travesties. Racism in today’s society, should be discussed apolitically, with critical thinking, and a balanced view."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jessie_bradica","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All children should be valued and respected across all levels from support staff, to teachers, to fellow students. Strong anti-bullying policies should be implemented firmly and fairly. Children should be addressed as individuals, and be provided a positive and productive environment where they have the tools to reach academic success. If an individual is struggling with issues surrounding sexual orientation that hurts their academic experience, supports should be in place both inside and outside the classroom. Those supports should be decided upon by a combination of administration, schools, and parents. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been honored to be entrusted by my fellow  directors to be the President of the North Penn SB for the last four years, but we are absolutely  a team of 9.  During our first term, we have effected major change in our district - one of the first things we did was implement Full Day Kindergarten. We've emphasized transparency by having community forums, a board newsletter and videotaped Committee meetings. We developed a comprehensive 10 Capital Improvement Plan to address our many infrastructure needs. We've promoted Diversity & Equity with in our schools so that every child that enters NPSD feels welcomed, safe and supported to be the best student they can be. I feel I am the best candidate for this office because I want to continue the work that we've started - we have accomplished a lot but there is still so much to do. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["One of the top issues in our district, as is with so many other districts, is aging infrastructure. Specifically our high school and middle schools. One of the first things that we did upon taking office was to work with our administration to develop a 10 Year Comprehensive Capital Improvement Plan. We wanted to address our needs in a holistic way, to take into account the needs of every building, instead of addressing one building at a time, as had been done previously. Doing so would allow us to budget taxpayer money on these projects in a more fiscally responsible way. The major part of our plan is to add a 9th grade center onto the High School and to renovate the High School itself. This would allow us to move the 9th graders up from the middle schools  where they would have access to such things as advanced courses or  the tech school. It would allow us to finally remove the temporary modular units that are at the three middle schools and put A/C into middle schools. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Since the pandemic began in March of 2020,  every decision that we have made has been with the health and safety of our students and staff in mind. Together with our administration, we have worked with our local health officials and followed the guidance provided by them and the CDC to implement a multi-layered mitigation strategy. In 2020 this included  initially going virtual and then moving to a hybrid option. We made a major investment in technology which allowed us to provide these educational options. This year we are back to in-person school for those that want it while still offering a virtual model to those who prefer that for now. Since last January, we have offered assurance testing. In addition, our district hosted several vaccination clinics during the spring, knowing that helping our community get COVID under control would help our schools as well. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Our Board of Directors worked with our administration on a Health & Safety Plan that follows the guidance of the CDC and the Montgomery County Department of Health.  For our elementary schools we require masks for every level of transmission - low, moderate, substantial and high - while indoors, because children 12 and under do not currently have the option of being vaccinated. And until they have that option, it is incumbent on us to make sure we do what we can to keep our younger students as safe as possible. For our secondary students, masks are optional during low and moderate phases of transmission, but required at substantial or high levels of transmission while indoors.  Unfortunately, at the beginning of our school year, we were back in a substantial mode, so everyone was required to wear masks. Masks have been one of the most effective ways of mitigation and if wearing them helps us keep schools open for in-person learning, then I do think its a strategy we need to implement. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I consider vaccine mandates for staff to be a separate issue from students. To date we have followed the recommended guidance from the CDC and the Montgomery County Department of Health and we will continue to so.  We are fortunate to have an extremely high rate of vaccination amongst our teachers & staff and I would rather provide incentives for people to get vaccinated. Our community has come together in the past -polio being one example of such a time- and we have to do so again to get past this pandemic. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity and inclusion has been a key focus of ours since we took office- we want every child that goes through NPSD to feel welcome, safe and be afforded every opportunity to succeed. Some of the things we have done to date were to hold a Cultural Proficiency forum to get input from our community. We hired  Director of Diversity & Equity.  We’ve done a school climate survey and we are examining disproportionality in suspensions & punishment. We’ve strengthened our hiring practices in an effort to hire teachers & staff members that more reflect the community we serve.  Again our goal is to assure that every student has the opportunity and tools necessary to meet their full potential and become a productive member of our community once they leave NPSD.  "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Representation matters. We live in a diverse community and it is essential that every child see themselves in our curriculum. History needs to be taught accurately and honestly. We’ve updated some of our reading lists to include books that are much more reflective of our incredibly diverse student body. We are examining  and addressing the achievement gap vs. the opportunity gap.  We have met with many different student groups during our tenure to hear what their concerns are. There is still so much work to be done and we look forward to continuing this work as we move forward.  "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_tina_stoll","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Our Board was thrilled to be able to have over 100 students & residents of the NPSD community at the Educational Services Center in June, to raise the Pride Flag. We have met with the LGBTQ student club at the high school several times to hear their thoughts and concerns. It is important to us to have all of our students feel safe in our schools and for them to know that we value them and stand by them.  "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I feel I am the best candidate because there is so much more to be done.  Our current board has faced many challenges this past year and I am very proud of what we have accomplished.  I am pleased with our progress, and am passionate about continuing our efforts to achieve our ultimate goals to make our school district stronger, more efficient, equitable and cohesive."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["One of the top issues facing our district right now is building a more diverse and inclusive staff with a focus on equity for all of our students and staff.  I will continue to represent the interests of our community and do what is right for equitable education for all of our students. I believe we need to keep moving our LGBTQIA+, anti-bullying and hate speech policies forward and making sure those are enforced.","I am committed to continuing to build strong relationships and to work collaboratively with all stakeholders towards a stronger school district",""]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Our district has a detailed health and safety plan in place.  Which includes masking, social distancing, appropriate building cleaning protocols, and quarantine/contact protocols if there is a confirmed COVID case."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, masking is the easiest thing we can do as a whole to ensure schools stay open and to help protect all students and staff."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I feel everyone eligible for the vaccine should get it.  But I also understand that this a very personal choice for each person and family to make."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We need to address our outreach with local universities, colleges, and surrounding communities, to attract new graduates and prospective candidates who better represent our student body and community as a whole."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":""},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_loucrecie_garlanger","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All of our students need to know they are seen, hear, cared for, and matter.  And school should always be a safe place for them to grow and learn.  Especially our students of color and LGBTQIA+.  I will keep working to make that happens and put policies in place so we cannot backslide if the board of school directors changes from election to election."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have served on the North Penn School Board for 4 years.  During that time, I have been a part of the initiation of full day Kindergarten, the implementation and expansion of the Property Tax & Rent Rebate Program, I’ve voted to convert a quarter of our bus fleet to propane fueled vehicles, I  supported the renovations of Knapp Elementary and Crawford stadium, championed the district’s DEI work including passing an Equity Policy to bring accountability to district programs and operations and I’ve overseen the review of the 100, 200 and 900 series of policies as part of a comprehensive Policy Review process.  Much of the work I’ve been a part of continues to this day, and my leadership and experience in helping shape these initiatives makes me the best candidate for this office. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["North Penn’s infrastructure needs and program of studies are two of the biggest issues I will focus on in a second term.  Through my work on the Education Committee I support modernizing our educational programs with a focus on college and career readiness.  I also support the construction of a 9th Grade Center and renovations to our high school.  This will allow sixth grade students to move to our middle schools, freeing up much needed space in our elementary schools, so a more effective plan can be implemented to address class size concerns.  "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Public schools should follow the science.  Until we have reached a critical mass of people who’ve gotten vaccinated, including children under 12 years of age, we should do all we can to mitigate the spread in our buildings.  That includes requiring students wear masks at the elementary level and pegging the decision to allow for optional mask use to community transmission rates.  Other strategies including assurance testing and social distancing should be a part of the plan as well.  "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Elementary students and teachers should be required to wear masks because this population has not had an opportunity to get vaccinated which puts them at greater risk for infection and transmission to others in the community.  At the secondary level, since the students and teachers in those buildings have had an opportunity to get vaccinated, when community transmission rates fall below the substantial designation, then they should be recommended, but not mandated.  "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Everyone should get a vaccination because that is what our country is asking us to do.  Generations before us have heeded the call, but unfortunately that is not the case today.  I will not vote to mandate vaccinations in schools because I do not believe it is the role of a school board director to make that decision.  However, I would fully support adding COVID vaccinations to the long list of those required for attendance in schools should it be considered in Harrisburg.  "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["North Penn should continue the work started four years ago outlined in our Cultural Proficiency Plan using disproportionality data and pre-determined benchmarks to gauge success.  That work includes diversifying our workforce, address issues of disproportionality that exist in our schools and programs, cultural proficiency training for teachers and staff and this work should be done in collaboration with the families we serve.  "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Novels read in class should invite students to understand perspectives of other races, cultures and lived experiences.  We should not be afraid to teach the truth about American history but instead put into context the country’s evolution to a more perfect union.  Also, we should remove barriers to more challenging course offerings for underrepresented groups of students.   We live in a diverse world and we owe it to our children to teach them about that world."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_christian_fusco","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Listening to kids is key to understanding how to meet their needs.  LGBTQ+ students have a higher likelihood of being bullied in school, so training to identify and intervene in these kinds of situations is key to supporting these kids.  Outward, symbolic gestures, demonstrating institutional support are important to communicate to all that our schools are safe spaces for all the students we serve.  That is why this school board decided to fly the rainbow flag over our Educational Services building this year."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience and perspective will add value to the School Board and add more complementary expertise to those of existing School Directors. Our diverse community needs representation where all perspectives, needs, and choices have value. I believe in leading with empathy, being accessible, transparent, and inclusive. I want to help our district engage with the community to offer every child the opportunity to grow and achieve – to build a better future for EVERY Upper Moreland student, every family, and our entire community. My experience in the tech industry has sharpened my critical and strategic thinking skills and business acumen. Dealing with contract negotiation and managing a multi-million-dollar budget has enabled me to make data-driven decisions.  My career has also enabled me to give back by volunteering as a Diversity and Inclusion ambassador, mentor, and teacher to showcase STEM to the next generation."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["There are many issues and challenges facing Upper Moreland, however, balancing the district budget and improving fiscal responsibility is a key priority. Upper Moreland School District had been projecting large budget deficits and continues to project deficits for future years even with federal and state level funding that has been significantly increased from prior years. Rather than relying on increases in state and federal funding and hoping these increases become available, we need to consider our expenses as well as our revenues. We need to eliminate any wasteful spending and direct these resources towards items that have the most direct educational benefits – like teacher salaries and smaller class sizes. While we are on the path to stabilizing our budget, we must also work to expand equitable outcomes for all students and the broader community and promote a deeper and more open partnership between the School board, administration, and the community they serve. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The district should offer in-person as well as virtual options to allow families to choose the modality that feels safest and works best for them. Our district should also focus on a layered mitigation strategy, which is found to be most effective at minimizing transmission: including leveraging outdoor spaces for instruction. In addition to continued efforts to reduce transmission as we move forward into cold and flu season, the district must also address the learning and educational impacts of COVID and school closures that occurred over the past year.  We have students that were dramatically affected by virtual learning that need special attention to renew their enthusiasm for learning.  We have other students and teachers that may be anxious about being back in class in-person.  And, we have students who have lost a loved one who may need expanded emotional support."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["District officials have limited power within the context of existing laws to require or mandate masks. I believe we will generate more usage by recommending and requesting mask usage rather than requiring or mandating. We should consider current transmission levels within the schools, the efficacy of other mitigation protocols, and age-appropriate strategies such as what the World Health Organization recommends (https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/q-a-children-and-masks-related-to-covid-19). We can come together as neighbors to keep each other safe rather than forcing compliance without these considerations."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Vaccines are an effective method of reducing the transmission and severity of COVID. However, there are many reasons that individuals may not be comfortable with receiving the vaccine for themselves or their children. As of the date of this response, the FDA vaccine has not granted full approval for 12-15 years old; therefore, government entities cannot legally mandate the vaccine for this age group.  Once the vaccine is approved for this age group (and younger), the state will be legally able to mandate the vaccine. As with existing required vaccines, parents should have the full slate of religious, philosophical, and medical exemptions available to them. With respect to teachers, districts should collectively bargain with the teachers to establish vaccine requirements and testing alternatives."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["I support continued diversity and inclusion efforts within Upper Moreland School District. I have been a volunteer and organizer for many Diversity and Inclusion efforts, both in the community and through my employers. I believe in a relational and actionable model of advocacy which appeals to our common human nature with an emphasis on Fairness, Understanding, and Humanity for all people, not just based on race or skin color. Having a multi-racial background, I have experienced criticism or discrimination for being too white or for not being white enough, but my race is only one part of my identity. Rather than being singularly focused on what parts of our identities makes us different, we need to focus on what we have in common using a pro-human approach."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Schools should discuss race and racism in a manner that respects the dignity and unique identities of all children.  Any curricula addressing race or racism should not stereotype, dehumanize, or divide our children.  It should be age-appropriate, and not attempt to indoctrinate students. Our students’ curricula with respect to race and racism should be discussed with the community in a transparent manner in the spirt of open-mindedness.  The district should offer the community the opportunity to give multiple rounds of meaningful feedback and revision of materials before implementation.  "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_lindsay_lindstrom","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["LGBTQIA+ students should receive as much support as other students, without discrimination. Our schools are attended by unique individuals whose identities, culture, interests, faith, and abilities should be fully supported by our administration, teachers and staff, and all resources. We need to increase awareness and accessibility to resources like our K-12 social worker, guidance counselors, and school psychologists who are equipped to address LGBTQIA+ concerns."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I would like to serve as school director because I care deeply about our community and","would like to represent all stakeholders – parents, students, teachers and taxpayers. Using my extensive experience with people of diverse backgrounds, I will seek to drive positive social change and advocate for academic standards that are competitive."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing our school district is community engagement. The Upper Moreland","School District’s mission statement includes the phrase “…in partnership with community…”;","however, there is a critical need to implement and actualize that goal. In recent years, the","administration and board have discounted and acted against community feedback, or limited the ways that the community can interact with the board and the district. I believe we can increase community engagement and address rather than ignore public comments and community feedback. As we create a more open, accessible, and engaging culture in our district we will be able to better accomplish our Upper Moreland Mission of providing “…all students with educational opportunities to develop knowledge, skills, and behaviors necessary for excellence and success as critical thinkers, caring and confident individuals, and as contributing members of society."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I feel Upper Moreland should use a layered mitigation approach and focus efforts on the strategies that have the most impact on reducing transmission and are least harmful to students. Enhanced ventilation, effective hand washing, staying home when sick, cleaning of high touch surfaces are all strategies to keep our children safe. I would like to see our district utilize outdoor classrooms to the greatest extent feasible to limit the amount of time students must spend masked indoors."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["","School districts should follow the high quality, scholarly evidence that is available to them with respect to masking in schools. As the pandemic continues to be prolonged, we have more competing mitigation strategies to evaluate both within the US and across the world. We are seeing other countries acknowledge that masking strategies have little or no benefit to justify the potential harm.  As a Registered Nurse, I know students are not trained in proper mask usage, nor do they have the wherewithal at a young age to execute properly – masks are meant to be changed frequently with proper handwashing in between. The more children touch their faces, the higher risk they are for illness. For these reasons, I believe mask usage should be recommended rather than required and districts should focus on measures that are more effective at preventing transmission."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Since the early days of the pandemic, it has been clear that the virus has different levels of","severity dependent on age-bracket and co-morbidities. The risk calculus associated with the","vaccine is much different for a healthy child than for an aging senior. In any and all cases, these medical decisions need to be made on an individual basis with one’s physician’s input. Additionally, government entities cannot mandate COVID vaccinations in students under age 16 until it is fully FDA approved. The district would need to negotiate mandatory vaccinations and alternative testing programs with the teachers’ union."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Our district should address diversity and inclusion issues, but our efforts to do so should not be partisan based or done in a divisive manner. We need to include our entire community in our diversity and inclusion efforts – not just those we agree with. I would advocate to reboot the Upper Moreland DEI taskforce using a transparent and public process in order to truly engage the community on these DEI issues. We need to listen to and interact with all stakeholders to truly move our district forward."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["There are many challenges to addressing race and racism at school. The school district","should be transparent about what is currently being taught with respect to race and racism, and hold in-depth public meetings to explore any changes. I support teaching a","full and balanced history of our nation, including its failures – but I don’t believe we will solve past discrimination with present discrimination. Instead, we must encourage critical thinking and pursue a pro-human approach with an emphasis on fairness, equality, and shared humanity to promote and protect the civil liberties of all Americans.",""]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_kaitlin_mclaughlin","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["All children should be able to attend school in a safe environment free from discrimination, and LGBTQ+ students should be have access to the support systems and resources available to all of our students.  "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience as a CPA working directly with nonprofit organizations, as well as school districts, provides me with a unique skill set both among the current board, as well as among all candidates running. This knowledge has served me well during my first term and has continued to grow while serving as the Treasurer."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I have many concerns for our district including increasing BIPOC and LGBTQ representation among our employees, infrastructure planning for increased populations and (hopefully) reduced class sizes, as well as continued curriculum adjustments to reflect the changing needs of our students' interests and teaching techniques. While I would love to see these addressed more proactively, the bulk of my concern and time has been, and will continue to be, spent on COVID related issues. COVID is the single largest obstacle that our children, staff and admin are dealing with today. It is impacting every part of district while increasing demands on an already over-stressed and woefully underfunded education system. Please see the following question/answer regarding steps to address COVID."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["UM has the benefit of seeing how districts have handled COVID that have already started the school year. What we are seeing is in line with the science and guidance that experts in pediatrics and epidemiology have discussed. Districts utilizing masking and higher vaccination rates report lower cases. Conversely, those districts where these measures are not in place or not enforced are seeing larger cases and larger student quarantine due to potential exposure. Vaccination (where able), universal masking, distancing of at least 3 feet, increased ventilation and proper hygiene layered together provide the best defense. In addition to mitigating spread, the district will also need to address the learning loss and emotional trauma caused by the pandemic. This is not a one size fits all situation. Instead a multi-layered approach should be used that involves parents, teachers and mental health experts to identify children in need and develop the necessary action items for each child."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["COVID and the science around it are ever-changing and it is important that mitigation plans that are in place remain flexible so as to meet increasing, or decreasing, risks. At this time, since vaccinations are not universally available, I am in favor of universal masking in our schools. Masking is one of the scientifically proven mitigation methods that helps reduce the spread of COVID. In addition, by implementing masking of our students/staff we are able to reduce the number of quarantines required for our students/staff. This results in our students being able to attend school, in person, in our buildings and for our classes to be staffed with our teachers rather than subs. As noted, this plan should be reevaluated as new information comes to light as well as when vaccinations become more widely available."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["While I am a proponent of the COVID vaccine and believe that it is one of the best ways to prevent/protect against the virus, I don't believe that it is within the District's ability to mandate vaccination of our students. Having said that, I would be supportive of mitigation measures in the future that take a person's vaccination status into consideration. For example, masking or social distancing may be required under more circumstances for an unvaccinated individual but not required for a vaccinated one. Science backs getting vaccinated against COVID and so do I."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Increasing the diversity of our teachers and staff is a step that the District needs to take in order for our teachers and staff to reflect the wonderful diversity of our community. As a current board member, this was stressed to Dr. Roth when he joined a year ago and he has made strides towards achieving this goal. However, further progress is needed. The District needs to take a multipronged approach to recruiting, hiring and retaining. We need to make UM more attractive as an employer and more competitive with benefits/pay offered at surrounding districts. If a teacher is able to obtain a higher pay or better benefits at one of our surrounding districts they will likely choose that district. We need to ensure that our hiring practices take into account any implicit biases and work to reduce them. And, lastly, we need to ensure that our employees are well cared for, listened to and appreciated so that they remain with us and our children."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Racism exists. It exists in our country and it exists here in Upper Moreland. To believe differently would be to discount the lived experiences of our neighbors. It is the responsibility of each of us to tackle the issue of racism in our community. As a District, I would like to see us look at our curriculum with a fresh lens and ensure that BIPOC contributions and experiences are included and represented. For example, our English classes  should include a diverse list of authors, our science and math courses should include relevant contributions from BIPOC, and our history lessons should be expanded to include a larger dialog of race in America."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_jennifer_solot","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Similar to my answer on racism, it is important that we recognize that discrimination against LGBTQ+ exists and that the District should actively fight against it. In the past I have been vocal about including LGBTQ+ language in our policy reviews and updates, but this is only a bandage. UM should adopt an LGBTQ+ policy to codify our support of these rights for our students, staff and teachers. However, a policy alone is not enough. As we have seen with racism, discrimination and hate will continue to exist unless we are active in combatting them. Our BIPOC and LGBTQ+ are some of our most vulnerable children. Acceptance of them is not enough, they need to be supported and celebrated. Our District needs to openly welcome LGBTQ+ staff and teachers so that children see themselves represented not only by the color of their skin but by the love in their hearts and we need to ensure that our LGBTQ+ students are not only accepted by our District but protected as well."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I can bring a balance of ideas and perspective.  I believe in studying an issue from all sides and considering a multitude of perspective.  With transparent debate and discussion, we can evaluate the merits of proposed solution and make decisions based on intellect, rather than emotion or personal agendas.  I believe in connecting with the community, listening to all constituents, and serving as their voice."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["To me, the top issue facing our district is the current school board culture.  Board culture should be about strategic thinking, a culture of inquiry, inclusivity, and no personal agendas.  I can help move our board towards these ideals.  I don’t have all the answers, but I can ask challenging questions.  I can request the administration address all questions and public comments in an inclusive manner, rather than side-stepping questions from community members who disagree.  If a board makes decisions with little discussion and no debate, the community is left to wonder if the decision was pre-determined in private, or if the board is rigorously exploring all options surrounding the decision.  While there are many issues facing Upper Moreland School District – budget issues, academic excellence, special education, DEI issues – these issues cannot be adequately and substantially addressed without improving the board culture."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The district should adopt practical, balanced, and common-sense strategies to address COVID in schools.  Keeping children and staff safe is a priority, but the school district needs to partner with parents and engage the community on the best way to accomplish this goal.  COVID should no longer be treated as a stigmatizing pandemic. The virus is no longer brand new, and we have made substantial progress on how to treat the illness. We can proactively address it with heightened awareness, layered mitigation strategies and voluntary contact tracing. We should continue to monitor scientific studies and guidance but always keep the focus on educating children."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Masks should not be required in schools. Mask studies should be reviewed and implemented based on their merits, not pre-conceptions. Risks and negative side-effects should be acknowledged and the district should allow parents to weigh these risks against the scientifically proven benefits. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Vaccination is more effective than some other mitigation strategies at preventing transmission, and it has been shown to be effective at reducing the likelihood of severe outcomes like hospitalization and death.  Our school district should promote and encourage the vaccine; however, vaccine requirements for students come from the state level and our board should not be determining these requirements. As COVID has similarities in transmission and effects to influenza, I feel a wholistic approach should be implemented to combat these contagious respiratory illnesses."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Diversity and inclusion cannot be limited to race or wealth. They should encompass the full spectrum: learning ability, physical or mental impairments, age, culture, etc.  Upper Moreland School District should make sure all students are treated fairly and equally.  In some cases, DEI efforts are used disingenuously and are agenda-driven – we need a balanced approach.  We need to make sure high-character individuals are participating in these efforts and that Upper Moreland’s DEI taskforce is fully engaged with the community in a transparent and open public forum. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Race and heritage should be respected and studied, but they do not fully define anyone. Racism is a shallow and disrespectful action. Children should learn to make judgements based on character and collective actions, not characteristics and isolated decisions, choices, likes or dislikes. We need to teach to teach humility and respect to combat racism. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_shawn_hopkins","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["The district and schools should promote acceptance of all people. Curriculum should be age appropriate. Young kids focus on fundamentals of values and kindness. LGBTQ+ is one of many things that define or describe a person. Everyone has differences and schools should promote the freedom of expression balanced with respect and self-control."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I honorably served in the US Air Force, have a BA in Business Management from Moravian College, a BS in Computer Science from Penn State University, and a MS in Business Administration from Central Michigan University.","","I have lived in Montgomery Township for 21 years, and previously in  Hatfield Township for 3 years. I have two grandsons at Inglewood Elementary School and one grandson at Bridal Path Elementary School.","","During my career I designed, developed, and implemented computer systems for major corporations including GE Aerospace, GE Astrospace, Smith Kline, Wyeth, Aetna, and Independence Blue Cross. I have been a School Board Director at North Penn for 2 years.","","My business experience includes writing business proposals, business analysis, project planning, project management, and team leadership.","","I donate blood, have donated bone marrow, taught Sunday school, clean our parks and neighborhoods regularly, coached girls basketball, and worked at the St. Stans festival.",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Our top issue is the aging infrastructure. Past school boards invested in infrastructure on a “as needed” basis, instead of making strategic long term decisions. A good example of this are the temporary modular classrooms that exist at many of our schools. Some of these modular classrooms are 30 years old. ","","The North Penn Neighbors for Progress team developed and implemented a fiscally responsible 10 year strategic investment plan. This plan is discussed in public meetings several times a year, stored on North Penn’s website, and updated as needed.",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The North Penn Neighbors for Progress team is committed to listening to the experts and implementing the COVID solutions they say are necessary. Our school administration is tasked with informing the school board and our community with the latest information from national, state, and local government officials. Our administrators have also developed a close relationship with the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia.","","Our administration presents this information to the School Board and our community at School Board Meetings, so our community can discuss the data and make an informed decision. ","","North Penn has updated both our online course offerings and technology to make virtual education state of the art. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe that this is a decision that should be made by the CDC or other public health officials and not school boards. I promise that when these public health officials make a decision, we will implement their decision to the best of our ability. ","","My family and I are currently wearing masks indoors per the current mandates. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["I believe that this is a decision that should be made by the CDC or other public health officials and not school boards. I promise that when these public health officials make a decision, we will implement their decision to the best of our ability. ","","My family and I have been vaccinated and will continue to get vaccinations as they become available.",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["Every student deserves a quality education in a safe environment. We must do everything possible to make sure this happens. People from different cultures, religions, races, sexual orientations, and handicaps must be included. As a person with dyslexia, this is very important to me. ","","We must meet with these students and their parents to listen, learn, and address their issues. For the first time in recent North Penn history, the North Penn Neighbors for Progress team along with our administration has started to meet with the various clubs to discuss the issues they face, guide them, and work on solutions.",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["The curriculum needs to provide a 21st century education. I know that in the military and in my professional career, I lived and worked with people of many cultures, religions, languages, sexual orientations, and races.  To be successful, our children must respect and understand all people.","","Our curriculum must teach respect and understanding of all people.",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_alfred_r._roesch_iii","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Like other student, LGBTQ+ students deserve a quality education in a safe environment.  LGBTQ+ students must be represented in our curriculum with respect and understanding.","","We must meet with these students and their parents regularly to listen, learn, and address their issues. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Over my 59 years of life I have been involved in many areas that fit the characteristics of a School Board: a coach, a teacher, business owner, youth leader, elder CFO, served on many boards (College, Non Profits, Trade Associations), Education Trust)"]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The elephant in the room at this time is Covid and all of it's facets."]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Being  the only school in Montgomery county to be open and have on line learning last year here are some of the many actions that made it a successful year:  Thorough Health and Safety Plan (HASP).  Giving parents and guardians the option to send their child to school or online learning.  Great execution of the HASP.    "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["No, it should be optional.  There are 5 other controls put in place, distancing, sanitization, personal hygiene, proper ventilation, bio-blasting, and vaccinations.  Being a Risk and Safety officer, engineering and administrative controls need to be performed first then PPE should be used.  "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["No, It is a choice."]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["It has always been the districts goals to serve the whole child and many of the policies have been created to ensure diversity, inclusion and the potential for all students to achieve the education they need to be a person who can add value to their community, family and themselves. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["I believe that teaching of honest history and the continue of reviewing curriculum to make sure it supplies ALL Students the information and ability to become a person who is able to think on their own.  "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_stephen_nelson","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["As I stated before, It has always been the districts goals to serve the whole child and many of the policies have been created to ensure that all students are treated equally."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am the best candidate for office because I can see the big picture and seek solutions with the future in mind. I have experience on other working boards of directors and have successfully contributed to policies and processes that bring equity across mission-driven organizations. I have a seasoned background in marketing and am an effective, clear, and concise communicator. I am currently an executive search consultant in higher education, healthcare, and nonprofit leadership. I recruit and guide both clients and candidates through an inclusive, consistent, and fair process that has resulted in the strengthening of world-renowned institutions. I am a founding board member of a nonprofit organization dedicated to giving everyone in UM a sense of belonging. Lastly, I am a mother of two school-age children (soon to be three) in the Upper Moreland Township School District. I am engaged with their experience and have advocated for their safety as well as that of others in the classroom."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["There are three issues UMTSD faces: DEI Strategic planning, COVID response, and staff hiring and retention. DEI strategic planning and staff recruitment and retention go hand-in-hand. The majority of the leaders I place are chief diversity officers of varying scales and areas of expertise. A consistent challenge we see across DEI leaders is the need to recruit and retain a talented and diverse workforce. UMTSD employs only a handful of teachers of color, though the student body is becoming increasingly more diverse. To recruit more teachers of color, I would encourage the administration to form student affinity groups, support them, and elevating them by showcasing their programming. This could draw teachers who are impressed by and want to support a diverse student population. We are surrounded by exceptional higher ed institutions. They could help inform both a DEI strategy as well as COVID response, especially community buy-in which is critical given the divisive political climate."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["It would be influential to see the UMTSD form a COVID response task force of community members who are accomplished medical and public health professionals with and without children in the schools. They should provide masks as well as vaccination on-site for those who qualify. COVID has impacted everyone's health, whether physical or mental and the school should respond by hiring more on-site medical staff (school nurses) and social workers. There is also a socio-economic impact of the pandemic. The school should be more forward-facing in its efforts to decrease the food insecurity of UM families and host job fairs for folks of all ages. We also need to implement innovations around curriculum, technology, and the classroom having experienced virtual learning. We are hung up on taking sides on the mask debate and missing an opportunity to deepen schools' learning environment and community service."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["If scientists and doctors who have dedicated their lives, not just the past year-plus, to infectious disease and public health say that we are all required to wear masks, then students and teachers are not an exception. The schools are our local hub--whether we have traveled overseas, wear a mask regularly, or don't wear them at all, we all come together and are all exposed to one another 5-days a week at school through our children. Wearing a mask is looking out for and protecting one another. We all have responsibilities for the collective good of our fellow community members wherever we find our communities."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Yes, those who qualify for the vaccine should be required to be vaccinated. There are already vaccination requirements to enroll in school. COVID-19 should be added to the list because vaccines are why this pandemic is not due to measles or polio again, for example. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["I am deeply troubled by how often racial slurs are being used by students. The Code of Conduct needs to be revamped to adjust the response by the administration with restorative justice in mind. This program should also offer optional space for parents/families/guardians of students to get involved in those efforts. All students must have a platform for their voices to be heard and the administration can offer town halls to open these avenues. This could give students from diverse backgrounds and experiences a place where they feel heard by all. I mentioned earlier the formation of student affinity groups, this should be done for teachers and staff as well. UMTSD needs to also develop relationships and pipelines to Philadelphia universities, HBCUs, and minority-serving colleges and universities where all of UMTSD's students can go to meet peers and leaders with similar experiences and find greater support on their unique journey to success."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Students are already learning about racist acts in history books and current events, but they are not having enough conversations specifically about racism in the classroom where learning should be equal and equitable rather than skewed by bias. It's already being learned indirectly, so having conversations about racism in the classroom completes a more comprehensive learning experience. To ask teachers to increase their students' understanding of racism and what they can do to confront and minimize racism is a heavy lift. I think asking important questions and encouraging courageous conversations in a safe and respectful environment will equip our youth to be a part of the effort to finally end racism and achieve social justice for all."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_tiffany_weber","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["UMTSD needs to be fluent in weaving preferred pronouns and names throughout the system. The commencement attire is also incredibly restricting and gender-informed. Students should not have to dress in colors and attire assigned to by how society recognizes their gender. I also wonder what the students' thoughts would be about gender-neutral restrooms. The curriculum should be expanded to include gender-diverse leaders as well."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have served the community since 2018 as chair of the Safe Schools and Facilities & Operations committees. I'm passionate about public service and results-oriented: we delivered full day kindergarten and AC in the elementary schools within the first year, developed an innovative tax rebate program for seniors and advanced an Equity Policy informed by extensive community input. ","","Drawing on my career in education security, I ensured that our school safety program was reoriented for the 21st century, with a focus on student mental health. I led development of a comprehensive ten year plan and the district has a first-ever strategic plan to guide infrastructure investment. Results can be seen in the new ADA compliant Crawford stadium, the total renovation of Knapp Elementary and the upcoming renovations of the high school and potential 9th grade center. I'm committed to ongoing community outreach and responsiveness, civility and compromise that will best serve all our students.",""," ",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Safe, Secure and Vibrant Schools — there can be no student success without the most primary needs being met; if we are mindful of well-being and create a culture of proactive safety, communication, trust and responsiveness, then students can focus 100% on education. A holistic safe schools program needs to be inclusive and reflect the needs and goals of the entire community, with transparency, data-based accountability, student input and cultural proficiency at the forefront of efforts. To this end, a 21st century education means that we have a comprehensive strategic plan to maintain and renovate facilities, with the appropriate resources, to support academic, experiential and professional pursuits for students to attain their personal goals. This approach needs to continue as we look to address North Penn High School, decades-old \"temporary mods\" across the district and HVAC and other significant upgrades in our middle schools and beyond. ","",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["We started having students safely back in schools since fall of 2020, and those safety measures worked to keep our community safe throughout last school year. If one student's suffering due to traumatic illness from Covid can be prevented, then I'm going to continue to follow the overwhelming body of peer-reviewed science and recommendations from health experts. In this ever-evolving delta phase, we have to be especially focused on those younger than 12 years who cannot yet participate in the FDA approved vaccine. Risks need to be mitigated or reduced as much as possible within reason. Masking at the secondary levels is pegged to community transmission rates and masks will be optional as rates decline. With the extensive feedback received, the input from the community to continue social distancing and masking is a compromise the majority in our community desires. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["Because those 12 and under cannot receive the vaccine, elementary students and teachers must wear masks, unless a legitimate medical or learning reason exists for a waiver. In this variant phase of the pandemic, we must lean towards more cautious practices since risks seem to be increasing for infection in students, which will likely increase transmission to other community members. Masks are optional at the secondary level due to access to vaccines and our high level of vaccination rates of teachers and staff. However, we have pegged the decision to require masks, or not, to the county Board of Health recommendations for when transmission rates rise to, or fall below, the substantial designation. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["The vaccines are safe and fall into the same range, or exceed, risk margins for other vaccines required in schools and even some workplaces. I'm very happy to see that one vaccine has already received full FDA approval, this is a major development for our nation and community. It is not the standing of a school board to establish such a vaccine mandate, this is a state legislative purview and decision with statutes already established -- I would support seeing our representatives advance such a goal, adding to the already required list of vaccinations every student needs to start school."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We need to facilitate brave, honest conversations, increase transparency and use data to drive accountability across all operations. A major step was made earlier this year when we passed a comprehensive Equity Policy which will ensure benchmarks are set, met and progress reported to the community. Coupled with a Cultural Proficiency Plan adopted in 2018, we aim to reduce the achievement gap, address disproportionality, increase the diversity of our staff at all levels and increase family engagement. ","","DEI has been demonized by those with divisive political goals. Such disinformation doesn't change the fact that North Penn is simply embracing the same goals and practices of our armed forces, law enforcement and nearly every corporate workplace across our nation for the past two decades or more. To reject DEI initiatives only harms our students from being best prepared to be successful contributing members of society after graduating North Penn. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Curriculum that invites students to better understand other perspectives and experiences across races, religions and cultures only strengthens the learning and preparation of North Penn students for real world success. This is a diverse community, in an ever diversifying nation -- curriculum always changes, so why would we abruptly pause this evolution of instruction? ","","If districts are focused on teaching facts within the context of the shared civic goals of a more perfect union, then I support a curriculum that represents the breadth and depth of the entire American experience, which includes racism. Any substantive changes should always be discussed publicly and transparently, as they have been at North Penn board meetings and community forums; so long as we continue this discussion as a community, I'm confident we can avoid the problems that have sadly divided communities elsewhere. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_jonathan_kassa","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Across all levels of government, the human and civil rights of our fellow LGBTQ+ citizens have been reinforced and championed. Underrepresented and/or marginalized students are more likely to be victims of bullying, crime and even suicide. The LGBTQ+ community exists across every demographic of our community, so it is important to acknowledge our LGBTQ+ students and their families. It is essential to build lines of communication with families and students in order to foster better understanding and address needs.  ","","This is why I made it a personal goal to facilitate the board's raising of the rainbow flag at our headquarters in June to demonstrate support. It was a heartwarming event with over 100 participants, student speakers and bi-partisan political support from across the district. Signaling the core value of inclusion, of all students and people across North Penn, this will continue to set a course for years to come so long as I'm representing the entire community."]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["  I am 47-year-old and have been a North Penn resident for 27 years now. I have 6 children, 2 of which went through North Penn K-12 and at the tech school. Over the years while living in the North Penn community I have been very involved in various youth athletic programs here in the community and it has provided me with the ground roots relationships with various members of the North Penn community.","   Professionally, I have had the great privilege of serving as an educator for the past fifteen year within the Philadelphia school district. Teaching history and serving as a dean of students at Frankford High School has given me a unique prospective to effectively serve as a board member here in North Penn. Understanding the inner workings of the educational system including special education, ESOL, and tech school, I believe this experience would aid me in guiding the board in various decisions that would best serve to address the academic gap and the over all North Penn community. ",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["1.        The preparedness of North Penn graduates. After their experience in North Penn, to many young adults are falling short once they leave North Penn at the next level. Countless students are unable to complete or feel ill prepared for the next step.  Either at the college/trade level or in joining the work force. This is not unique to North Penn and I believe that we as a district we can do a better job in guiding and creating a foundation for our students. Ideally, identifying and recruiting students in the trades at a younger level would help in bridging this gap and address the effects of Covid learning.  ","2.        Our upcoming budget short fall. Decisions made by the current board to move forward on various projects have created an economic crisis that needs to be addressed with a more conservative approach. Having new voices would add value to the conversation and help aid North Penn in moving towards a balanced budget","",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["Decisions made by the board has created animosity between parents, staff, administration and the community at large. Repairing this relationship is vital in moving forward for our students. The region is still dealing with the pandemic and further decisions and the potential effects are still unknown and new minds to deal with these effects are needed. Board members should work towards involving parents and community members in the decisions for the schools. This was a tradition in the past in our community and we need to return to allowing the voices of the community to be heard.  ",""]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The decision on the topic of masks was decided by the Governor and current school boards do not supersede  that decision. Once the department of health lifts the mandate then and only then should individual school districts conduct a surveys in their communities to hear the voice of the public. Options should be created for every student no matter the circumstance. The widening of the educational gap should be also part of the conversation. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Personal health should be between an individual and their doctor. The decision should be made by the individual not mandated through employers and our governing bodies. As an individual who has had Covid-19 and is confirmed to have antibodies, I believe the discussion on vaccine is personal and the decision should be in the hands of the individual to maintain personal liberties for all. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["As a Philadelphia teacher the topic of diversity and inclusion is a topic I take very serious. The issue with the topic is that it has become a politicized and both sides. In Philadelphia the topic is used to provide professional development to better prepare our teacher and  students to address the academic gap. Curriculum is selected for the sole purpose to address real issues and not used to gain favor with voters. Here in North Penn the important issue is not understood and glanced over without truly looking to address the issues. Capital is spent on teacher professional development and no real monitoring is held to look for effectiveness or ineffectiveness. So therefore misunderstand, animosity, and division is left in the wake. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Making sure all of our community in included in the curriculum and studies. At the upper levels I fully support classes that teaches various cultural appreciation. Having political science classes at the high school level would be widely popular and effective in creating a diverse community. Teaching our students critical thinking is essential in creating well rounded life long learners. What we can not have in any form of political activism promoted through our teachers. As an educator myself, I greatly enjoy the promotion of students being involved in current events with having open minds to embrace all ideas. I have taught African American studies for several years and have seen the results of students learning and embracing their history as a culture and as Americans. "]},{"candidateCode":"north_penn_school_district_michael_kennedy","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["Making sure ALL of our community in included in the curriculum and studies. At the upper levels I fully support classes that teaches various cultural appreciation. Having political science classes at the high school level would be widely popular and effective in creating a diverse community. Teaching our students critical thinking is essential in creating well rounded life long learners. What we can not have in any form of political activism promoted through our teachers. As an educator myself I greatly enjoy the promotion of students being involved in current events with having open minds to embrace all ideas. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I love the students and want the best for them and their families. I have been on the board for 2 terms and am familiar with the policies and the regulations. I am here for our community and will listen to you while trying to find the best solution within the boundaries of the law and the guidelines. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Today the top issue appears to be masking and vaccination. As I previously described, I love the students and want the best for them and their families and will support the best solution within the boundaries of the law and the guidelines. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["I endorse implementation of county, state, federal, FDA, and CDC guidance within the context of PDE recommendations and community feedback. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["We, the school district, must follow the law and implement it as defined by the county, the state and the federal legislature and groups. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Our school district must follow the law and implement it as defined by the county, the state and the federal legislature. I will always seek the solution that ensures the safety and maintains the privacy of our students and their families. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["We have always embraced diversity and inclusion. The administration considers all viewpoints and seeks feedback on relevant issues from different groups within our community as a whole. As required by the state, the administration is working on the annual comprehensive plan. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["Our curriculum was currently revised and implemented. It adheres to state and federal regulations. We are always monitoring PDE guidance along with state regulations to ensure we are compliant with the laws and the most current recommendations. "]},{"candidateCode":"souderton_area_school_district_janet_flisak","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["We support all races, genders and sexual orientation groups which includes LGBTQ+ students. "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My 3 primary strengths I would bring to the School Board are ","1) a business approach to problem solving and accountability, from which I would draw upon my MBA degree and experience as a Chief of Staff at a Fortune 500 firm.","2) proven ability as a community leader in Upper Moreland, where I'm on the UM Human Relations Committee and run the Class of 2034 and Class of 2031 Facebook groups where I regularly share information, make connections, and help fellow parents","3) experience managing corporate diversity & inclusion programs, which I would use to build upon the great work already happening in the District"]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":"What is the top issue facing your school district, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["I suspect Covid will continue to be a top issue this school year.  The trajectory of Covid-19 and the Delta variant are uncertain; we could start seeing more students quarantined; and there may be a vaccine available for younger children available in the coming months.  All of these issues bring complexities for the District to work through.  In addition, we are seeing a broad spectrum of perspectives on whether and when to mask, which will mean a challenging road ahead for any School Board."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":" What steps do you feel the school district should take to address COVID in schools?   ","response":["The District has already passed its Health & Safety Plan, which sets the policy for masking, quarantining, etc. I support the plan, which was passed unanimously by the current board. Should the spread of the virus or availability of a vaccine change the landscape, I would consider updating the Plan to better serve the situation."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":"Should students and teachers be required to wear masks in schools? Why or why not?  ","response":["The priority is to keep kids in schools.  Kids need to be in school for a myriad of reasons, such as to receive services, develop social relationships with peers, and to ensure reliable access to food.  Teachers are instrumental in identifying abuse or negligence at home, and can't do this effectively via Zoom. We cannot risk disrupting kids' access to these benefits which is why I'm supportive of requiring masks in schools while Covid transmission levels are high."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":"Should teachers and/or students over the age of 12 be required to be vaccinated against COVID? Why or why not?  ","response":["Given the federal mandate for all employers of 100+ employees to require a vaccination or be tested weekly, Upper Moreland should be in compliance. Regarding a vaccination requirement for students 12+,  keeping kids in schools continues to be the priority.  I'd want to hear from the community about the current vaccination rates, and reasons for vaccine hesitancy, so the Board can approach the matter informed on the potential effect a vaccine mandate would have on attrition.  "]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":"What steps, if any, should your district be taking to address diversity and inclusion in the district?  ","response":["No child should feel limited to achieve because of their identity.  I have professional experience delivering on DEI programs in a corporate setting, and would translate those skills to the academic setting.  One area on which I'd focus is development of a more inclusive recruiting program so we can work toward a staff and administration that is as diverse as our student body.  Kids need to see that anybody can become a leader, and I'd love to see our schools become a proof point."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":"What changes, if any, should be made to the curriculum to address race and racism?  ","response":["As School Director, I'd like to connect with our staff to better understand how the current curriculum addresses race and racism, and work together to identify gaps and solutions. ","The US is expected to be minority white by 2045. Students who aren't BIPOC know others who are.  Children should learn to embrace these differences. Awareness of the broad spectrum of differences and experiences should be shared in an age-appropriate way that drives acceptance.  At the High School level, we owe students an education on topics such as celebrating cultures, recognizing bias and racism, and understand the reality and impact of racism in the US today."]},{"candidateCode":"upper_moreland_school_director_2_year_jolie_r._price","question":"What steps, if any, do you think your district should take to support LGBTQ+ students in school? ","response":["As School Director, I'd like to connect with our staff to better understand how the district addresses support of LGBTQ+ students, and work together to identify gaps and solutions. A 2020 Gallup poll showed 16% of adults 18-23 to be LGBTQ.  Students who aren't LGBTQ will know people who are.  Children should learn to embrace these differences. Awareness of the broad spectrum of differences and experiences should be shared in an age-appropriate way that drives acceptance.  At the High School level, we owe students an education on topics such as sex vs gender, pronoun usage, and demystifying the range of identities within LGBTQQIA+."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_neale_dougherty","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["As the incumbent Bucks County Controller I love the work and I love serving my community in this capacity. As Controller, my job is to protect taxpayers and ensure our county government is using tax dollars appropriately. My office is authorized to examine the accounts and official acts of all individuals who collect, receive, or disperse the county's money and during my time as your independent watchdog I have worked to provide an independent check on the fiscal activities of our Bucks County elected leaders. If reelected I will continue to ensure our county government works for you."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_neale_dougherty","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["When I was first elected, it had been years since many of our county offices had been audited, depriving Bucks County taxpayers of transparency into how their tax dollars were being spent and leaving our County government unchecked. My first act as Controller was to have my office get to work on conducting audits of other row offices and county departments. I believe accountability makes people, systems and organizations better, and if reelected I plan on continuing to provide that accountability on a daily basis on behalf of Bucks County taxpayers."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_neale_dougherty","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["My primary duty is to serve as the financial watchdog for all Bucks County residents and taxpayers, to assure them that county funds are only spent appropriately. I believe transparency makes us better and is central to building trustworthy relationships with the larger community. Under my leadership this office is committed to completing and posting audits of Tax Collectors, District Courts, county departments and other row offices on the county website so that members of the community can review and evaluate the performance of their county government. Recently we completed and posted an audit of the Sheriff's office, the first of its kind since 2006, in order to inform both the department and the citizens of Bucks County how that law enforcement office was performing. We will audit all departments, law enforcement or otherwise, objectively and to the highest professional standards."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_neale_dougherty","question":"How will you ensure proper use of state and federal COVID relief funds coming into Bucks County?  ","response":["As Controller, I have seen to it that our office has been involved in the vetting of applicants for federal COVID relief funds coming into Bucks County.  I also have the ability to conduct audits and provide oversight of the programs allocated for COVID relief funds.  This central role provides transparency to Bucks families on the efficiency and effectiveness on how those funds are dispersed. I am proud of my reputation as a nonpartisan elected official. So, regardless of how that money is used and who is authorizing that allocation, my office will provide a fair, facts based report that Bucks County residents can use to draw their own conclusions."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_pamela_a._van_blunk","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["Traditionally, the Controller's seat has been held by an attorney because the job involves a lot of statutes and regulations. For example, the Controller accepts all bids on the County's behalf (a highly regulated process); verifies that all bills submitted to the County are legally due and that the supplies or services provided were furnished or performed under legal authority; has authority to refuse to approve payment if the bill is not legally due or provided with legal authority; and has the power to issue subpoenas and authority to collect evidence and take testimony under oath. I am the only candidate with legal experience. Through my law practice, I have extensive experience reviewing financial reports, working with accountants, investigating spending and \"where money goes\", gathering and presenting evidence and taking testimony under oath. I have the knowledge and disposition to do the job of Controller. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_pamela_a._van_blunk","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["First, we need a check against one-party rule in Bucks County government and hold the Commissioners accountable to the taxpayers. I will be the fiscally conservative, independent watchdog for all taxpayers. Second, Bucks County residents deserve to know where the millions of dollars in COVID-relief money is being spent and I will fully audit all COVID-related money coming into our county. Third, the County Commissioners authorized a special audit of the Coroner's office which set off a legal battle between the Coroner and County. I will regularly conduct audits of county departments, thereby reducing the need for special one-time audits of specific Row offices or agencies."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_pamela_a._van_blunk","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["Government transparency is critically important to our democratic system by holding our elected officials accountable. As stated above, I will be the check against one-party rule in County government and hold the Commissioners accountable to our taxpayers.  I will also increase transparency by educating our residents on the role of Controller. For example, as a member of the salary board, I will make taxpayers aware of the County's expanding payroll. As a member of the pension board, I will make sure that taxpayers are aware of under performing investments.  "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_controller_pamela_a._van_blunk","question":"How will you ensure proper use of state and federal COVID relief funds coming into Bucks County?  ","response":["On day one, I will audit each and every dollar of all state and federal COVID relief funds coming into Bucks County. Transparency to our taxpayers will ensure the proper use of state and federal COVID-related money into our county. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience in crisis is what makes me particularly qualified to continue to serve as your Bucks County District Attorney. It's easy to lead when times are good. It is much more challenging to lead in times of crisis, when a person's decisions are subject to second-guessing by the public and his detractors. Public scrutiny comes with the this job. I've stood with my community in times of crisis, such as during the investigation of multiple homicides, while simultaneously trying to catch the killers, comforting the families of lost loved ones, and informing the public in a responsible yet transparent manner. I've kept our community safe throughout the COVID and opioid pandemics. I've ensured peoples' right to assemble and to freedom of speech during the recent civic unrest without a single riot, clash with police, or loss of life. I clearly communicate with our community leaders and members, including our 39 police chiefs and their 1,000 officers who serve and protect us every day."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing the Bucks County District Attorney's Office is the public's fair demand for individually tailored justice. Our primary goal will always be to keep our community safe.  As prosecutors, we have tremendous power in the form of discretion. We must exercise this discretion judiciously and fairly.  While people must be held accountable for the crimes they commit against others in the form of punishment, I also believe in trying to get at the root causes of individual criminal behavior.  By addressing root causes such as substance use disorder or mental illness, we will prevent future crime.  This is why we've committed tremendous resources to our  drug diversion and treatment programs, our mental health court, and our prison reentry coalition.  All of these program assist offenders in addressing their problems so that they can successfully reintegrate into society after rehabilitation."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"What further police reforms are needed to address issues of racial bias and police brutality? ","response":["We in law enforcement must lean into these issues.  While I believe that Bucks County law enforcement officers are not racially biased in general, and that our police are not \"brutal\" in their treatment of the public they serve, I understand that there are instances in which this occurs here. I also understand that this is a commonly held perception among some segments of our population.  We can't accept any police racial bias or police brutality. Zero.  So we have to train our police to be categorically and situationally aware of these issues in order to avoid them.  Some proactive steps that we've already taken in this regard include implementation of our \"L.O.V.E. is the Answer\" program, the 39 Bucks County Police Chiefs' commitment to adopt our model universal use of force best practices, and making sure that our police are trained in crisis intervention and deescalation."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["I pride myself on making the Bucks County District Attorney's Office transparent to the public. We respond personally to every call, text, email, tip, and visit that we get.  We post daily on social media and CRIMEWATCH about cases that we handle, and public service projects that we and our partners engage in.  I know how important it is for the public to know it's safe in times of crisis, and to be generally informed on law enforcement matters, as soon as possible.  Although there is currently a PA law (CHRIA) that prevents us from releasing investigative police reports and other media to the public, we are currently striving to make that law less restrictive through legislative action. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"How would you address gun violence in Bucks County?  ","response":["We are currently partnering with our law enforcement partners at the PA Attorney General, ATF, and in the surrounding counties to crack down on straw purchases of firearms, which are disproportionately uses to commit crimes.  I and a number of my staff regularly attend  Bristol gun violence coalition meetings to support that community on this issue, and would certainly participate in these coalitions in communities throughout the county.  Another simple, yet effective, way that we combat gun violence is through \"Ben's Campaign,\" in which we provide free gun locks to anyone who asks for one.  Through this campaign we've provided thousands of free gun locks to people all over the county so that they can store their guns safely.  "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"Do you support efforts to decriminalize marijuana or lessen penalties? Why or why not?  ","response":["I don't support efforts to decriminalize marijuana. That leaves them in the same place they started, with a potential substance use disorder problem.  I do support efforts to get each person who suffers from marijuana use disorder the assessment and treatment they need.  By decriminalizing marijuana use, people lose access to treatment.  Through our county-wide District Court Drug Program, people who have been arrested for marijuana possession are diverted from the criminal justice system, and into treatment. It's cheaper, closer and quicker than going through the traditional criminal justice system.  And for Bucks County residents, its free.  In fact, once someone completes the program, the charges are dismissed, regardless of whether its their first marijuana offense or more."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"How would you address the opioid problem in the county? ","response":["Plain and simple, we need more treatment beds, and better transportation to get people there.  These are my five goals when someone suffers from an opioid disorder: 1. Keep them alive with narcan, 2. get them treatment quickly, through BPAIR (Bucks POlice Assisting in Recovery) or other programs, 3. reintegrating them back into their former pre-disorder lives, 4. addressing their criminal charges, because those don't go away on their own, and 5. I never want to see them again, because that means we've been successful.  I also encourage people tor report drug dealing to our elite County Drug Strike Force, which I founded, through our website at Bucksda.org, or anonymously through our \"Push out the Pusher\" tipline.  Because drug dealers don't stop at the borders, we've also taken advantage of the assets of the federal, state and local law enforcement members through our membership in HIDTA, which creates a force multiplier effect."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_matt_weintraub","question":"What steps would you take to diversify the office?  ","response":["I am proud of our efforts to diversify our office as we have a number of native Spanish speakers on staff.  We need to do more though.  We've participated in ongoing racial equity training to become better aware of these issues as an office staff.  We've also engaged the Bucks County Project and Diversity Office in assisting us with this process.  Through education on this issue, I've also learned that recruitment starts at the high school and college level, so I've made an overt effort to speak to students of diverse backgrounds about the possibilities of serving the public in a criminal justice career."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["My experience, passion, and commitment to bettering our community and rebuilding the bridges that have been shattered over the last several years drives me to serve my community in the best way I can."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["Bucks Co. is far behind the integration of mental health mechanisms into the criminal justice system. I strongly believe that there are proven strategies that the DA can implement that would greatly improve the system. First, I will work aggressively to establish a mental health court in Bucks County. I have heard the announcement that we might be getting one soon. If this is true, I cannot wait to see it fully operational because we have waited far too long for something that other Counties have had for years. Second, I would provide mental health training for all staff within the DA’s office and establish comprehensive mental health protocols into every relevant case. Lastly, my office would identify ways to help integrate mental health support into police departments. Police should be supported by programs, personnel, and training that will proactively address mental health issues before they escalate out of control so that no one needs to get hurt or loses their life."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"What further police reforms are needed to address issues of racial bias and police brutality? ","response":["I believe instituting a Community Policing model is the only way to comprehensively address the growing gap between traditionally disenfranchised communities and police departments. A community policing model means officers who know the community, and citizens who know their officers. I would support programs like this that bring the community together and end the divide.  Additionally, I believe diversity within police departments would also go a long way towards combating racial bias. In the end, however, prejudice exists everywhere therefore, I would make it clear on Day One that there is no place for racial bias or brutality in the Bucks County Law Enforcement Community and if an officer or employee of the District Attorney’s Office is found to have broken their solemn oath to uphold the law with fairness and equity, than I would make sure that individual is held accountable. As DA, I will not tolerate excessive use of force or uneven application of the law in Bucks County."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["A part of the Community Policing Model is the inclusion of prosecutors in my Community Unification Project. The more involved and available prosecutors are, the more community members will understand what the DA’s Office does, how to hold us accountable, how to stay informed, and how to remain involved in the process going forward. Conversely, if prosecutors engage consistently with the community they serve, their work will invariably reflect the greater understanding they’ll gain from such interactions. They will have intimate knowledge of the people they’re fighting for and will have a bond which will drive them harder to seek justice."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"How would you address gun violence in Bucks County?  ","response":["A Gun Violence Task Force is long overdue in Bucks County. Therefore, I would establish open structured lines of communication between law enforcement, gun shop owners, and the community allowing us all to share information, be informed about potential problem signs, and know what to do about anything we might think could escalate into a violent encounter. ","","Additionally, investment in an integrated mental health system within the criminal justice system would go a long way towards helping to proactively address potentially dangerous situations before they reach a point where someone gets hurt or killed. In concert with mental health professionals and properly trained and equipped law enforcement, community members could aid in policing individuals with guns who might pose a threat to themselves or others.",""]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"Do you support efforts to decriminalize marijuana or lessen penalties? Why or why not?  ","response":["I have publicly called for an end to arrests of nonviolent marijuana offenders. Currently, the Bucks County DA’s Office continues to encourage the arrest of marijuana users, even if they have a medical marijuana card, and then proudly diverts them into expensive treatment programs, claiming that their marijuana use is a substance abuse issue. I couldn’t disagree more. Medical marijuana is legal in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania for many reasons but mainly because the science on this issue has shown that there are myriad health benefits for individuals who have been unable to find relief through other means. The waste of taxpayer dollars on arresting, charging, and processing these individuals is galling. Lastly, the emotional and financial burden this process puts on those arrested is unconscionable. Many of these individuals are using marijuana because of injuries or mental health issues so to put them through criminal proceedings and treatment is cruel and asinine."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"How would you address the opioid problem in the county? ","response":["We are losing the war on drugs. In fact, in the last year, overdose deaths have continued to increase.  I believe the main reason we are failing in this fight is the lack of mental health treatment available to those battling drug addiction aka substance use disorder.  Treating underlying mental health issues is essential in order to successfully combat substance use disorder. I will work with rehabilitation and recovery professionals to ensure proper treatment is made available to those suffering from addiction and along with it addressing the other mental health issues that may underlie it. In addition to making mental health treatment available to those battling addiction, I will expand diversionary programs to include a focus on this treatment. I will also focus on getting opioids off the streets. I will go after doctors that practice with greed and self-interest by preying on those suffering from addiction. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_district_attorney_antonetta_stancu","question":"What steps would you take to diversify the office?  ","response":["The current DA’s office is woefully lacking in representation commiserate with the demographic make-up of Bucks County. This has to change and it starts with the hiring process. Currently, the DA’s Office recruits from just two law schools which presents limitations to diversification. I would seek to expand the schools from which we recruit while also changing the tenor of the Office’s mission. By engaging with different law students and also advocating for the newest techniques in law enforcement with a focus on mental health, I believe we can greatly expand the type of talent we attract to the Bucks DA’s Office. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_mark_e._lomax","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I am honored to have had the opportunity to serve the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania as a State Trooper for 27 years. During my time on the force department, I rose to the rank of major and led the State Police Academy and all the training and education for the department’s 6,500 personnel. These experiences allowed me to work besides, lead, and train some of our Commonwealth’s finest. After my retirement, I spent time as the training manager for the International Association of Chiefs of Police. My career in law enforcement has prepared me to do for Bucks County families what I have done for Pennsylvania families my entire adult life, keep them safe. As your next Sheriff I will ensure that our office continues to work day in and day out to keep Bucks a safe place to live, work and raise a family. The Deputy Sheriffs within the department are incredibly fine individuals, who will have my full support, and I will use my experience to implement and refine the foremost best practices."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_mark_e._lomax","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing law enforcement across our country is a fraying trust between certain communities and our officers. As your next Sheriff, I will support our Deputy Sheriff's while also using my experience to reach out to every community in Bucks County, to listen, and ensure they know that we are here to keep them safe."," ","The more trust between our officers and those they protect, the safer we all are, and the more effectively law enforcement can do our job. I will make personal outreach to community leaders a priority and conduct a listening tour within the first month on the job."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_mark_e._lomax","question":"What further reforms are needed to address issues of racial bias and police brutality? ","response":["As a use of force/training expert, I will work to address these issues and similar ones every day. The best way to ensure that our officers do their jobs effectively and in a way that every Bucks resident feels safe and treated equally is by implementing proper training and policies. Also, by equipping our officers with best practices/policies and to update training on an ongoing basis. As Sheriff, I will ensure that my team is current on the use of force and bias training."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_mark_e._lomax","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["I believe being accessible is the best way to ensure transparency in policing. As Sheriff, my door will be open to every community in Bucks County, and during my first few months I will go to every corner of Bucks to speak with community leaders, teachers, principals, parents and students about what our department does well and what it could do better. I am committed to being the most accessible Sheriff in our County's history. Moreover, one of my priorities is to get the Bucks County Sheriff’s Office state and nationally accredited, ensuring that our policies, practices, and procedures are up to date and in conformance with best practices."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_mark_e._lomax","question":"How would you address gun violence in Bucks County?  ","response":["As Sheriff I will fully enforce the existing laws in place around who can purchase a firearm. I will also focus efforts on getting illegal guns off our streets and advocate for any additional resources or legislation I believe is needed to keep Bucks County families safe. Gun violence is an issue that has taken far too many lives and as Sheriff, curbing gun violence will be one of my top priorities."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_mark_e._lomax","question":"What steps would you take to diversify the department?  ","response":["During my time in the State Police, I had the honor to serve as the first African American Trooper to lead the state police academy in its 116-year history. My own law enforcement career is a testament to the opportunities created when we enable and encourage individuals of all backgrounds to participate in law enforcement."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_fred_harran","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["For the past 34 years, I have had the privilege of serving as a Bensalem Township Police Officer, and most recently as the Director of Public Safety for the past 15 years. Protecting and serving my community was the greatest honor of my life. Throughout my tenure with the department, I have focused on reducing crime with innovative technology such as creating the first Countywide DNA database, I have worked to develop new reforms that have increased accountability within our department, and I have created partnerships with civic organizations to benefit my community. Having insight on policing in the 21st century has given me the ability to work with all aspects of the Criminal Justice system, Social Service agencies and the Community. This is accomplished by a progressive approach in combining community policing, technological advancement, innovative law enforcement  and intelligence lead policing through teamwork."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_fred_harran","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["My highest priorities as your Sheriff includes, obtaining State and National Accreditation. In 2021, one of the most important aspects of Law Enforcement is to have a policies, procedures, rules, regulations and training that are accepted in the Law Enforcement community.  I will also continue and expand on many of the initiatives I have been doing that bring a premier service to our community. This is only done by working with the other Police Chiefs and organizations in the county. We must continue to create new and lasting relationships, institute new initiatives that tackle drug addiction epidemic and ensure that those selling drugs are held accountable. I will find new ways in dealing with the Mental Health crisis that has such an impact on families and our community. ","I will work to provide new services and make sure that the services already required by Sheriff's office are done within BUDGET. ","Openness, Transparency and Accessibility will be a key component.",""]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_fred_harran","question":"What further reforms are needed to address issues of racial bias and police brutality? ","response":["In 1829 Sir Robert Peel the \"father of modern policing\" introduced the \"9 principles of policing\" included in that was a statement \"the police are the public and the public are the police\". We must reinforce those principles today, now more then ever. We must continue to work with the community in ensure trust, transparency and confidence. Government must make sure that police departments have the funding necessary to provide the proper training and supervision for our departments. We must have in depth backgrounds for new officers and a robust hiring process. Departments must have the right policies and procedures in place to ensure proper action and responses are taking place.       "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_fred_harran","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["Building relationships and maintaining trust with our is such a key element in policing in 2021.  I have over 22 years of executive leadership in municipal policing, I have demonstrated the unique ability to bring policing, municipal government and community together. As the opioid epidemic escalated across Bucks County, our department supported many initiatives and launched BPAIR, “Bensalem Police Assisting In Recovery,” which was the springboard for a similar Bucks County program.  As Past President for the Bucks County Police Chief’s Association, I also chaired the committee that developed the 15 Police \"Use of Force' policies that are be adopted by all 41 Law Enforcement agencies in our county. I continue to work with the NAACP to ensure the trust that is place upon us, we have the only PD that I know of that has representatives from the NAACP and community on the police hiring board.   We must continue transparency, openness and relationship partnerships with the community.   "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_fred_harran","question":"How would you address gun violence in Bucks County?  ","response":["I would ensure that the Bucks County Sheriff's Office increases it's support to our 39 Police departments in the county. We would work with our courts to make sure court orders are enforced, specifically regarding firearm issues. I also have idea's for new initiatives in the county that will help with overall crime issues and firearm safety.    "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_sheriff_fred_harran","question":"What steps would you take to diversify the department?  ","response":["I have worked hard in Bensalem to diversify the Police Department and would bring those steps to the Sheriff's office. This would be done by implementing the following:  making hiring more accessible by having a on line application process; working with many groups like the NAACP and houses of worship of recruitment drives; having community members as part of the interview process; using the current sheriffs and community members as recruiters. I would be open immediately to hearing idea's from the residents of Bucks county on this issue just like what has been done in Bensalem.   "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_recorder_of_deeds_robin_robinson","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["After being sworn into office in 2018, I now have a record to run on, and am confident in the work that I’ve done. In my first term, I started a historic deed book restoration project - restoring the county records back to 1684 that I found deteriorating in a county warehouse. After discovering that deed fraud was a major threat in our area, I worked directly in the effort to spearhead The Bucks County Fraud Alert System- a free system for all residents of Bucks County to protect them against identity theft. This system is now used as a model for other counties across the Commonwealth. The work that I’ve done with the Realtors in the area has been recognized by The Southeast Realtors Association, who unanimously endorsed me for re-election. As Recorder of Deeds, I have made our service to the community a major priority of mine, and I plan on continuing this achievement of good government through a second term."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_recorder_of_deeds_robin_robinson","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["My main job as Recorder of Deeds is to maintain and protect the record of the county. And with that, I acknowledge that the greatest issue facing The Recorder of Deeds Office is the ever-changing technology and most up-to-date processes. To face this issue, I have begun the process of modernizing the office by transitioning documents to PDF/A and a cloud based storage system. Not only is this going to be more cost efficient, but it will ensure records are more easily accessible to constituents. I am currently working with members of the state legislature to make law changes that would ensure certain procedures done in the Recorder of Deeds Offices are done in a more efficient and smoother manner. I need a second term in order to see the continuation of these projects and to address these top concerns. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_recorder_of_deeds_robin_robinson","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["Transparency is an issue that I continually work to improve. One step I made towards transparency when first taking office in 2018 was sending out a bi-monthly newsletter, updating constituents on all changes happening in the Recorder of Deeds Office, and in the County. There are currently more than 9,000 residents that are signed up to receive this bi-monthly update. There is no change in the Recorder of Deeds Office that is made without notice. When changes occur, I personally make sure that we send a letter to every Title Company in Bucks County and surrounding areas.  In January 2020, I opened the records dating back to 1684 in order to ensure that Title Companies and Realtors could continue working from home during the pandemic. We are now currently re-scanning old deeds so that they can be more accessible and easier to read for all constituents. I plan on continuing this level of transparency, and striving to achieve even higher levels of transparency into a second term."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_recorder_of_deeds_dan_mcphillips","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I believe I am the best candidate for Bucks County Recorder of Deeds because I possess significant experience in management, county administration and budgeting. I have successfully managed teams that provided efficient and quality service to the public. In my public sector work, I have gained vital experience in how all the offices in the county work and I will be ready to go from day 1. I have designed and implemented budgets that ensure that the public is provided top level service while respecting the needs of the employees. I know the role, I know to how to budget and I know how to lead and that is why I am the best candidate for the Bucks County Recorded of Deeds. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_recorder_of_deeds_dan_mcphillips","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The Recorder of Deeds office would benefit from increasing accessibility to our residents. Currently, the office hours are not designed to meet the needs the of our working class residents. The office currently closes at 4:15 every day. I would implement evening hours to allow residents to avoid having to take time off of their jobs to visit the office. This is just one example of how we can make improvements to the office to increase the value offered to residents. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_recorder_of_deeds_dan_mcphillips","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["I would make it a point to increase engagement and awareness with the public. This can be accomplished a number of ways. In addition to being in the office as much as possible during office hours, we can also bring the office to other locations to ensure we are accessible to underserved communities. We can also use digital media to educate the public. We must ensure that the office is being used to its greatest potential. By doing so, we will provide value to the taxpayers, services to the residents, and rewarding opportunities to our employees. The people pay for this office and we will make sure that our doors always stay open to them. "]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_prothonotary_judi_reiss","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["I have been honored to be your prothonotary over the past four years. It has meant so much to have your trust and I am incredibly grateful to have the opportunity to lead this office since 2018. During my time as your prothonotary we have faced the tremendous challenge of COVID-19 as a community, and I am proud that because of the dedication of my staff and innovative thinking, my office was able to continue to serve Bucks residents even at the height of the pandemic. Innovative, cost saving measures like the expansion of paperless divorce applications allows those interacting with my office to quickly receive the documentation they need and I have worked hard to streamline processes that are under my supervision. It is my belief that doing my job well, means finding ways for individuals to have as seamless an experience as possible when dealing with my office and if reelected I will continue to do just that."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_prothonotary_judi_reiss","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["The top issue facing my office is innovation. Before I was elected, the Prothonotary office predominantly conducted paper based services, completely out of sync with how many Bucks residents pay their bills, purchase items, engage with one another; online. My first priority and an effort I accelerated during COVID-19 was to move as many services as possible online, making access to my office easier for every resident of Bucks County. While we have made incredible progress there is still more left to transition to an online platform and if reelected that would be my foremost objective."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_prothonotary_judi_reiss","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["Moving services online inherently makes things more transparent. Now most documentation is electronic and thus something that can be preserved forever, opposed to paper files that are difficult to maintain and locate. We have begun the process of transferring all of our decaying microfilm and microfiche to digital that is easily accessed on the County Viewer."]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_prothonotary_coleen_christian","question":"What makes you the best candidate for this office?  ","response":["The Office of Prothonotary is an administrative position in the Civil Division of the Court of Common Pleas. The Prothonotary handles all the filings in the Civil & Family Division of the Court. My 20 years’ experience in project management, communication skills & commonsense abilities make me ideally suited to serve as Prothonotary. Project management requires strong leadership & clear communication. I have a proven track record of successfully managing & delivering high profile design projects, including The White House, the PA Governor’s Mansion & the Bucks Co. Visitor’s Center. My experience as an Upper Makefield Twp. Supervisor, as well as the education I received at Villanova, NYU & Harvard, contributes to my in-depth knowledge of building community & municipal management. As a proud mother of three, including a son serving in US Army Military Intelligence, I seek to protect the ideals of fiscal responsibility, office efficiency & respect for each & every taxpayer. "," "," ",""]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_prothonotary_coleen_christian","question":"What is the top issue facing this office, and what are your plans to address it? ","response":["At present, there is a Class Action Suit, which names my opponent as “overcharging taxpayers,” and collecting “court fees in excess of statutory limits.” I will thoroughly investigate this issue and take the appropriate action. As Prothonotary, my primary objective will be Customer Service and efficient modernized service. As a past member of the Economic Re-development Commission for the Philadelphia Navy Yard and a former television journalist, I have critical understanding of best practices, and will use this additional experience to benefit the daily operations of the Prothonotary Office. My goal is consistent and effectual execution of all administrative duties, and an office that operates with good common sense. Protection from Abuse Petitions will be handled with expediency.","",""]},{"candidateCode":"bucks_county_prothonotary_coleen_christian","question":"What steps would you take to increase transparency in your office?  ","response":["As Prothonotary, I would be easily accessible and readily available to all tax payers and the County Commissioners. I will work closely with community stakeholders, such as Bucks County judges, the Bucks County Bar Association, Bucks County Children and Youth Social Services, and those organizations who work to help all people with Protection From Abuse Petitions (PFA’s). Lastly, timely notification and clear communication of fee adjustments will be a priority.  ","",""]}]